<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Equality on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/equality/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/equality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Give and Tell Challenge</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke challenged me to the “Give and Tell Challenge”&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy to comply. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ceoblues.com/archive/2014/august/giveandtell&#34;&gt;Dan James,&lt;/a&gt; inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_Bucket_Challenge&#34;&gt;ALS Ice Bucket Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, came up with the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You donate to a cause, or causes, that have meaning to you and you say why. You then challenge 3 other people to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-out&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/a&gt;. All Out campaigns for a world where no person will have to sacrifice their family or freedom, safety or dignity, because of who they are or who they love. Living in a country that has a fairly open-minded approach to equality, it’s hard to believe that in 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s illegal to be LGBT in 77 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being LGBT is legal grounds for life imprisonment or execution in 10 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one transgender person is murdered every 36 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only 17 countries recognise marriage equality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is completely unfair to suffer because of the way you were born and who you love. All Out has run a lot of campaigns focusing on the laws and treatment of people in particular countries, but also on the suffering of individuals who desperately need urgent support. They’re a small organisation who often rely on the expertise of its members, so I recommend you &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en/about&#34;&gt;join their mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nominations&#34;&gt;My nominations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.wwf.org.uk/adopt-a-gorilla/&#34;&gt;WWF&lt;/a&gt;, and nominated Sean Johnson, so you should go and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;read Shaun’s post&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewaterproject.org/&#34;&gt;The Water Project&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to nominate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joanna_p&#34;&gt;Jo Porter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nd_kane&#34;&gt;Natalie Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hellofisher&#34;&gt;Steve Fisher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear about an issue that they care about. But I want to change the terms slightly…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-and-or-tell&#34;&gt;Give AND/OR Tell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@boagworld/the-ice-bucket-challenge-e0663fbf6544&#34;&gt;“Give and Tell Challenge” post, Paul Boag&lt;/a&gt; explains the reasons behind giving regularly and how to calculate a reasonable donation size. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;Sean Johnson&lt;/a&gt; both do regular work for charities for free. But not everyone can afford to do so. The element of the Ice Bucket Challenge that I admire the most is that it encourages people to raise awareness of motor neurone disease (ALS). If we can’t afford to donate to charity right now, even though we want to do so, raising awareness is a charitable act in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Jo, Natalie and Steve: I challenge you to give and/or tell. And no time limit this time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 13:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-in/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ve-changed-my-mind-about-this-subject&#34;&gt;I’ve changed my mind about this subject!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To read about why and how I don’t believe this anymore, &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/&#34; title=&#34;Women and conferences&#34;&gt;please read Women and conferences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-tech-conferences&#34;&gt;Business…Tech…Conferences…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every time&lt;/strong&gt; I hear these dreaded phrases, “*Women in business*”, “*Women in tech*”, “*Women at conferences*” I just groan. It’s really boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples. “*There’s only x% of women at this conference*” or “&lt;em&gt;There’s no female speakers at this conference&lt;/em&gt;.” Not just as observations (there’s nothing wrong in stating the obvious,) but saying it’s a negative point. I couldn’t care less how many other girls there are at a conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asides from it being a complete bonus when there’s no queue for the Ladies, I’d rather a conference was full of eager people who bought their tickets because they were interested and wanted to engage with other attendees. Would you rather there were 100% enthusiastic, participatory attendees or a conference where there was &lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; male/female attendees where 30% were just there to make up the numbers and weren’t bothered about being there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for speakers, maybe there are more male leaders (not exclusively, there are some brilliant female speakers) in the industry. The quality of a conference shouldn’t be compromised just in order to get some female speakers. Get the best speakers you can, and just don’t discriminate against having great women when they do emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, I do understand people who are working for female equality. I appreciate it. I’m not really a feminist, as nowadays feminism seems to mean that men can’t say or do anything and women can act like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misandry&#34; title=&#34;Misandry on Wikipedia&#34;&gt;female-equivalent of chauvinists&lt;/a&gt; as they like (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loose_Women&#34; title=&#34;Loose Women on Wikipedia&#34;&gt;Loose Women&lt;/a&gt; and other embarrassing examples.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find being singled out as female isn’t the same as being equal. Reverse discrimination isn’t as positive as it often seems. Gender is completely irrelevant in the tech industry, certainly at conferences and definitely in business. We’re not talking about manual labour or track running here, where women and men are clearly different. Why should women be remarkable just for existing in these industries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, I don’t think my design work reflects my gender. Certainly cultural and environmental factors must impact on my work, but design work is about context. Design work reflects the context of the project and the context of the client. I don’t like pink because I’m female but I might use pink on a site if I think it’s appropriate. I don’t think you could tell I’m a girl just by looking at my work (though correct me if I’m wrong, because if you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; then I’m doing something wrong!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s issues with most industries being male or female-dominated. That’s not going to change overnight. But in the same way, I really can’t say that anything in business, tech or conferences have ever put me off being a part of it. There are so many factors affecting genders in work, be it education, culture, or actual discrimination. Let’s just get rid of the discrimination part, and when it’s not a problem, let’s not make it an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, let me be completely honest. If anybody talks about me as being a “woman in business”, a “woman in tech” or a “woman at a conference”, not only is it weird being referred to as a &lt;strong&gt;woman&lt;/strong&gt; (I’m not that old!) but I also find it pretty fucking patronising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-comments&#34;&gt;5 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-184&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;pilky&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-184&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-03-02T14:26:26+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:26pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag Heh. Well the best way to increase the number of women in a field is to improve education and reduce discrimination
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-185&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d2ba25cc379899a37b46acae43f6ddc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d2ba25cc379899a37b46acae43f6ddc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.stinkyink.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Andy W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-185&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-03-02T14:44:13+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:44pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I suppose now would probably be a *really* inappropriate time to tell you “not to worry your pretty little head about it” ? ;-)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-186&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d05b9773b7459c843453d783832de22?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d05b9773b7459c843453d783832de22?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://peterbailey.eu&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Peter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-186&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-03-02T19:47:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:47pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I agree. It makes it seem like it’s especially hard for women to succeed in business, but really it’s down to the person, not their sex.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-187&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;alaric&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-187&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-03-03T00:27:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:27am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag I always thought “this tech conferences has women” was a bit like clubs that let women in free, so that horny men will pay.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
