<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grids on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/grids/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/grids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web workshop at Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 I’m running my ‘Design theory for the web’ workshop at Interlink conference in Canada on the 18th of June.
 
It’s a one day workshop and I’ve written a mega description below for anyone wanting to know more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grid Frameworks and why I’m not keen on them…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 19:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a post for 12 Devs of Xmas on Grid Frameworks.
After spending months whining about grid frameworks, 960.gs and Bootstrap, I’ve finally backed up my tweet-sized complaints with some context and examples.
I knew it would be contentious and that some people would feel antagonised by my saying that developers who don’t consider accessibility shouldn’t be on the web. And possibly also that I suggest some developers lazily fail to customise frameworks to appropriately suit their needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grids, flexibility and responsiveness</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/grids-flexibility-and-responsiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 21:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/grids-flexibility-and-responsiveness/</guid>
      <description>First steps: choosing a typeface The first step in my grid design was to choose an appropriate typeface. I knew this would be everything on such a text-heavy site, and I really struggled because, as with all the elements on my personal site, I wanted it to reflect “me”. I wanted a typeface that felt friendly and not too formal whilst still appearing clean, readable and professional. I sunk money on a few lesser-known typefaces (everybody wants to be different and original, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips For Developers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>This little post is based around the talk I gave at Bathcamp. Rich Quick came up with the great idea that, whilst Bathcamp attendees are mostly developers, a talk on design for developers was probably appropriate.
And you might have seen on my post from last week, I was looking for a case study to use in my talk. As happens with everything, I just didn’t have time to include the case study in the talk, so I thought I would blog it here as a follow-up from Bathcamp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
