<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Personal on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 12:44:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bereaved</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bereaved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bereaved/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last night I had a dream, or maybe a nightmare. I was in a ballet class in a church hall, learning all kinds of complicated and not-really-ballet dance sequences. The class was busy, we were all in clumsy rows. We were a diverse group of dancers in our everyday clothes. It was the same church hall I did most of my ballet classes in when I was younger, with lots of wood panelling, and stacked plastic chairs in place of a barre. The left side of the hall was a folding wall painted pale green. One of the folds was open into the side room, to allow latecomers and visitors in and out of the room. Lots of people were coming and going through the door.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During a particularly tricky piece of choreography, I absent-mindedly looked over to the side door and saw my mum standing in the doorway, watching and smiling. I hurried through the pack of dancers to get to her, but she turned and walked away, exiting the side room door into the carpark. I chased her, and called out to her, “Mummy!” She turned around smiling at me, standing there in the car park. I went to give her a hug, there was nothing more that I wanted in the world than to just give her a hug. But before I could get to her, she put her hands up and gestured for me to stay away. “You’re all sweaty. It’s not good for me. Not right now.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up shocked with a lump in my throat. It’s been fourteen months since my mum died. Eighteen months since my grandmother, my mother’s mother, died. I’d never lost anyone so close to me before, let alone our family’s two local matriarchs in the space of four months. Two women who loved, supported, and encouraged us, non-stop from our births to their deaths. Sometimes in their own peculiar ways, but always fiercely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grief of bereavement surprised me. It wasn’t like it was in books or on TV. I’m a tearful kind of person, but I didn’t cry all the time, or even very often. I mostly felt strange and a bit empty. Sometimes the painfulness hits me in a sudden wave, the overwhelming feeling of how much I miss them, and I sob until my pillow is wet. I bawled in a café on my birthday because what was the point of a birthday when I couldn’t share it with the person who gave birth to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, distraction is the strongest effect grief has had on me. It has gotten better over time, but I had long periods of struggling to focus on anything at all. Firstly months, then the odd week, now the odd day. Previous traumatic events have seen me plow everything into my work, but now I just couldn’t. My mind wouldn’t settle, it felt soft and cloudy. My short-term memory stopped functioning so well. My mind wasn’t always hurting, but it wasn’t doing much else either. But I was fidgety. I didn’t want to sit around feeling weird so I started knitting a lot. My mum taught me how to knit a few months earlier, and we’d bought a bear pattern together. In just over a week, Stanley was created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/10/23829268239_8fb377ae37_k.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4848&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/10/23829268239_8fb377ae37_k-1024x975.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Knitted teddybear with a slightly wonky face wearing a multicoloured knitted jumper&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Stanley, as named by my brother Sam who has a knack for naming cuddly toys
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, the tearful moments have become less, but I’m often shaken. Throughout 2015 and 2016, I’ve had days of sudden drops in mood, going back to feeling distracted and odd. I didn’t realise until fairly recently that those drops weren’t always random turns. Sadly, 2016 has been noticeably full of high-profile deaths. Somebody I can’t remember wrote a kind tweet advising all to take care of their friends during those times; the massive coverage and shared emotional distress can affect those who have experienced loss themselves. I’ve always tried to be empathetic to &lt;a href=&#34;http://everydayfeminism.com/2015/06/guide-to-triggering/&#34;&gt;triggering&lt;/a&gt;, but I’d never experienced anything like it myself. I was being triggered by the news; other people’s sad experiences were making me feel those feelings all over again. It can seem a bit selfish to have to take care of myself when others are suffering more recent pain, but it’s hard to tell my biology to behave selflessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weepy incidents lessen, remembering my mum and granny becomes less about suddenly remembering they’re not there, and more remembering the fun and silly stuff. With two strong personalities like them, the missing holes are very big, but the memories are all the more enjoyable. The family knows exactly what both of them would say about any given situation and can parrot it to each other convincingly. We’ll always miss them, just hopefully less painfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m never really sure what to say when people ask about my bereavements, how I’m feeling, or even how I’ve been recently. Knowing is hard and dwelling on the matter isn’t much fun either. Everybody will inevitably experience the loss of someone very close to them in the course of their lifetime. It’s probably a more horrible realisation than realising we ourselves are going to die. But like many other mental health-related issues, it’s normal. Because of that I’m sorry I don’t have any useful advice or uplifting wisdom as part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekmentalhelp.com/&#34;&gt;#geekmentalhelp week&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not a professional. And sometimes all the rest of us can do is share what hurts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-comments&#34;&gt;4 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151131&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba455da484aa46174a8b6504e10bd91e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba455da484aa46174a8b6504e10bd91e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://iamashley.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ashley Baxter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151131&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-05T11:57:07+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:57am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        This is beautifully written, Laura. Thanks for sharing.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151134&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c08248149e67f2c4f02b8fe32cb9952b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c08248149e67f2c4f02b8fe32cb9952b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ruth John&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151134&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-05T12:44:45+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:44pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Agreed, this is so such a heart felt read. Sharing is more than enough x
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151196&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/889fa1d4fb8cd3772f6d2d6ed208cfac?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/889fa1d4fb8cd3772f6d2d6ed208cfac?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://tonianni.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Antonia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151196&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-06T21:24:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:24pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Awesome, and just spot on. My dad and Grandmum (his mother) passed on in a space of 3 weeks this June and I just didn’t know what to do with myself. Your words are almost exact of how I could describe things. Sharing is so important and I’m glad I stumbled across your post. I hope it would comfort you in knowing that someone out there is comforted by your post.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151359&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Kathy&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151359&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-09T21:12:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:12pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Wow, lady! This is deep stuff. Thank you so much for sharing. I have not lost my mom, but I lost my granny a few years back. Thank you for phrasing this so beautifully, and for sharing your pain. It reminded me that it’s okay to feel, and that is a powerful and much-needed reminder. Kudos.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 21st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethical-design-manifesto-refresh&#34;&gt;Ethical Design Manifesto refresh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we launched a refresh of the Ethical Design Manifesto, along with a video. As it was a short-ish video, I felt like I had no excuse but to do the captioning for it too. I couldn’t get Subtitle Horse (my usual favourite web software) working with the video, so I ended up using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jubler.org/&#34;&gt;Jubler&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while to get my head around how to use the interface, but I found using the audio track from the video very useful, as I could sync the subtitles to the wave forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.05.01.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4828&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4828&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.05.01-1024x601.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Jubler with highlighted wave forms for subtitle editing&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Jubler in action
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creative-mornings-malmö&#34;&gt;Creative Mornings Malmö&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday I also gave my first ever talk in Malmö/Sweden. It was at Creative Mornings Malmö which had a lovely venue at Djäkne. The topic was “Change” and I spoke about Ethical Design, and why we need it. Aral took lots of bad photos of me, and one of them is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.12.00.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4829&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4829&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.12.00-1024x768.png&#34; alt=&#34;Me talking with a slide of the Ethical Design Manifesto (The 3 Rs of Ethical Design) in a fluffy black cardigan&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Me doing my impression of a crow
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re settling into a good routine here in Malmö. We’re working from the office all week, 8:30-5ish, and doing a better job of taking time off during the evenings and weekends. It’s still tiring though! I underestimated the sheer cognitive load of dealing with an unfamiliar language and culture. Of course, everybody speaks English and is very kind and friendly. But just going to the supermarket, finding our way around, and learning how things work, takes a little more time and a little more effort. It’s a great adventure! But makes us well worn out at the end of every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.17.54.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4830&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4830&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.17.54-1024x767.png&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar paddling in the sea in front of the Turning Torso in Malmö&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Enjoying the beach life!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-monday-21st-march-2016/1122&#34;&gt;posted on the Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-monday-21st-march-&lt;sup&gt;2016&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1122&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 1st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 10:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well… we’re here! In Malmö, sitting in our new office at Media Evolution City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy and exhausting week. Oskar and I made our 800 mile trip in one day, thanks to the wonderful “courier” and took another day to recover. Then it was straight into the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last week has been meeting new friends, relocation admin, and arranging a few events for the year. All the while Aral has been coding. (And he intends to write a moving-related update on our blog ASAP!) Things will move much faster now we’re in a city with a supportive community and a proper place to work…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/2016-03-26.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4823&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4823&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/2016-03-26.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar the dog on the sandy beach in Malmö&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Loving the beach!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-1st-march-2016/1099/1&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-1st-march-2016/1099/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 16th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s nearly time! We’re moving to Sweden next Tuesday, and it’s currently at equal parts exciting and stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The storage locker in Brighton is almost empty, and we’ve stashed all our sentimental stuff—the things you want to keep, but probably aren’t worth putting in a suitcase to a foreign land—at my family’s house. We’re only taking a couple of suitcases of clothes, our work equipment, and of course Oskar. If we can squeeze Aral’s fancy Anglepoise lamp and a few nice bits of artwork into the pet transportation van, then we’ll have those along too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of pet transportation, Oskar and I will be making our way to Sweden by road with pet couriers. It’s not cheap, but it means that I don’t have to drive across five countries on the weird side of the road, and me and my pup get to travel together. It’s going to be a long trip, with at least one overnight in Germany, so I might keep myself occupied by blogging the experience as we go…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the admin and accounting side, Aral and I are taking this “fresh start” opportunity to wind down our own limited companies that we used for consultancy/freelancing, and simplifying our accounting. Neither of us are doing anything that isn’t in some way related to Ind.ie, so there’s no point us spending money on maintaining all the accounts. That’s also particularly good news for me, as it should lessen my admin tasks and leave me more time to work on design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One week to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-16.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4819&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter wp-image-4819 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar the dog lying curled up on a leather sofa&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		If I look cute, I won’t be told off for being on the sofa…
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-16th-february-2016/1087&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-16th-february-&lt;sup&gt;2016&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1087&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 5th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note: I’ve been writing diary entries on the Ind.ie forum for a while now. I’ve decided to start sharing these on my site now too, as I’ve not been posting much else! (They have bonus dog photos.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write a diary entry for ages, and 8am on a Friday morning is the first opportunity I’ve had to get to it (and I’ve already been working for an hour…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is going well. You might’ve heard that we’ve decided to move to Sweden. Our visit at the end of January saw us finding a beautiful apartment in Davidshalltorg in Malmö, and the wonderful people at Media Evolution City going out of their way to organise us an office space where Oskar can join us. It’s been an arduous six months, and we’re really excited to move to such a friendly and welcoming space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy few weeks, with us both working hard on the hush-hush project (not long to go!) Aral speaking in Amsterdam, our two-night house-hunting trip to Malmö, and my speaking on two panels this week. Now we have just over two weeks to move everything we need to Sweden, and sort everything else. Including transporting Oskar across 5 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/&#34;&gt;we’re selling some of the stuff from our storage room&lt;/a&gt; on the 13th February. If you’re interested in any of it, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laura@ind.ie&#34;&gt;give me a shout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-05.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4816&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter wp-image-4816 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar on a muddy path in 10m visibility fog&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Making the most of the British countryside!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-friday-5th-february-2016&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-friday-5th-february-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Furniture (and other nice things) for sale</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So we’re finally moving to Sweden at the end of the month. You might remember that we &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/&#34;&gt;sold a lot of our stuff&lt;/a&gt; last summer when we left Brighton. We kept a lot of good stuff, thinking we’d relocate it with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now we’re moving to a small apartment in Malmö, and a beautiful furnished office in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediaevolutioncity.se&#34;&gt;Media Evolution City&lt;/a&gt;, so we are only taking the essentials. (Yes, that includes &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gigapup&#34;&gt;Oskar&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s left is the things that we really would’ve kept, but can’t. Fancy any of it? Please let &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/aral&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; or me know, via &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/laurakalbag&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@ind.ie&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;desks&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;2x Biurko adjustable desks&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;del-500-each-del&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;£500 each&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Only used for ~4 months, these &lt;a href=&#34;http://biurkobiurko.com&#34;&gt;Biurko adjustable desks&lt;/a&gt; are nearly-new, with spotless oak tops. They go for £650 new (excluding VAT and shipping from Poland) we’re selling them for £500 each.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;120 cm width&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;80 cm depth&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;73 – 120 cm height range (sit-stand)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;attachment_4812 wp-caption aligncenter wp-image-4812 size-large&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/Screen-Shot-2016-02-02-at-15.49.09-1024x834.png&#34; alt=&#34;Biurko desk at full height.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Biurko desk. It’s bigger than it looks. This is at full height. Legs come out wider when desk is lowered.
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;They’re already packaged with special wrapping to protect the tops from damage in transit. They weigh a lot, and are very big, so you will need a large van and more than one person!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;apple-displays&#34;&gt;1x &lt;del&gt;2x&lt;/del&gt; Apple 27&amp;rdquo; Thunderbolt Display&lt;del&gt;s&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;del-500-for-newer-display-del-400-for-older&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;£500 for newer display, &lt;/del&gt;£400 for older&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Apple Thunderbolt displays in mint condition and their original packaging. Requires a Thunderbolt port to connect to a Mac.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;attachment_4810 wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4810&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/my-desk-1200-1024x674.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A messy desk with Apple Display, iPad, MacBook Pro, and dog&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Apple Display as seen on a messy desk. Ridiculous dog not included.
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The older display has a defect since purchase that it cannot act as a power supply for the Mac (the power lead doesn’t work) but it’s otherwise in perfect working order. This defect won’t affect you if you already have a charging power supply for your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on how old your Mac is, you may need one of the tiny magnetic adapters to fit the power supply to your Mac. I think we might have a couple that we’ll throw in if you need one. Again, the display can be used without powering the Mac, it’s just a nice bonus feature to reduce the number of things you plug into the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aeron-chair&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;1x Herman Miller Aeron chair&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;del-350-del&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;£350&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;The iconic office chair. Dark grey, size B (medium sized) with lumbar support. Bought refurbished 18 months ago. Costs ~£900 new.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;attachment_4808 wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4808&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/front-772x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Aeron chair&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Aeron chair
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whiteboard&#34;&gt;1x Nobo Double-sided 1200 x 900mm mobile whiteboard&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;200&#34;&gt;£200&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bought less than a year ago. Great whiteboard for wheeling around the office, and double the planning space as you can flip the board over. It has brakes. RRP £500, on Amazon for £330. We’ll throw in a load of whiteboard pens and an eraser to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4809&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/31GOSYy3JLL.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Nobo whiteboard&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It’s large and heavy (great for writing on, harder to lift.) It’s currently in two pieces: board and stand. It can be dismantled into smaller parts, but the board itself is 1200x900mm, and the wheelbase is probably no shorter than 1250mm in one piece, so you’ll need a vehicle that fits it all in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;guitar&#34;&gt;Vintage Shadow 861 Semi Acoustic Guitar (VEC1500N)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;£150&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great condition, stays in tune. With soft case and guitar stand included. Goes for ~£300 online.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;attachment_4811 wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4811&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/15516043930_93144778c6_k-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;living room showing guitar and prominent dog&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		The guitar is on the left side. Only photo I could find with it in! Dog not included.
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;long-board&#34;&gt;Long board (Loaded Tan Tien complete)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;£100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;£250 new. Longer than a skateboard, and looks cool too. I have no idea about long boards. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/aral&#34;&gt;ask Aral&lt;/a&gt; if you want to know how it rides…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-also&#34;&gt;And also…&lt;/h2&gt;
Some smaller items. Let me know if you want any more information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dyson Animal vacuum cleaner&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;£100 &lt;abbr title=&#34;Or nearest offer&#34;&gt;ONO&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (~£300 new) Used condition, but still works really well. The best vacuum cleaner for dog hair as &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gigapup&#34;&gt;Oskar&lt;/a&gt; can testify.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;USB 2200 AA Microphone £50 ONO &lt;/del&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;(~£175 new) Nearly new.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;Fitbit Aria Scales £50 ONO &lt;/del&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;(£99 new) Nearly new. Requires AA batteries to work, and WiFi to send the data to “the cloud.” Doesn’t need to be used with a Fitbit.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Skateboard £50 ONO **(~£100 new) Good condition. But I don’t know what type it is…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;Blue Yeti USB Microphone £50 ONO &lt;/del&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;del&gt;(£99 new) Nearly new, podcasting favourite. Has different directional modes which is useful if you want to record two people talking to each other.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wooden tree bark bookcase £50 ONO &lt;/strong&gt;(~£100+ new) Great condition. 3 sturdy shelves, fits big books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philips Wake-Up Light Alarm Clock £50 ONO &lt;/strong&gt;(£100 new) Great condition. Perfect for people who struggle with dark mornings. Coloured sunrise simulation, five sounds and radio function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-and-how&#34;&gt;When? And how?&lt;/h2&gt;
Everything will need to be collected from Big Yellow Storage Brighton (from our storage locker) on &lt;strong&gt;Saturday 13th February&lt;/strong&gt; between &lt;strong&gt;12 noon –; 5pm&lt;/strong&gt;. If you definitely want the desks, or a combination of the larger items, we might be able to arrange pick up a few days before or after (But we really don’t have much time, we’re moving in under 3 weeks!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t post anything, it’s really expensive. But if you want to arrange a courier to collect on the 13th, we can handle that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Bundles for Sale</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3rd July: NEW BOOKS ADDED!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aralbalkan.com/notes/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish/&#34;&gt;We’re moving&lt;/a&gt;. And because we’re moving abroad, we’re &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gumtree.com/sellerads/1119077228&#34;&gt;getting rid of all of our stuff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#books&#34;&gt;Just take me to the books already&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aralbalkan.com/notes/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish/&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; and I have a lot of books between us. We’re sad to lose them. Many have been gifts from friends, written by people we know, and helped us do what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling books one by one is a time-consuming (and not cost-effective) exercise. Inspired by my friend Al Power coming over and asking “which books do you have on Typography?” I thought they’d be worth selling as bundles. All these books are worth way more than we’re selling them for, but we’re in a rush and want them to go to good homes. I’ve not done any particularly complicated pricing. Small books are £8 per bundle. Four small books: £10. Two small books: £5. Big books are £12 per bundle. Big book bundles with two books are £10. They’re all in good condition, most nearly-new. A few come with bonus margin notes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s more (lots of bigger books) coming! If people show interest in this, we’ve got more on typography, art, programming languages and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;postage-options&#34;&gt;Postage options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with books is that they cost a fortune to post. So I’ve bundled them all under 2kg so we can keep the post cheap. (Oddly, 2kg costs more to post than 2 x 1kg.) They fall into two categories: below 1kg, and above 1kg. (Listed alongside the bundles)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want them 2nd class to save the pennies, that’s cool too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;below-1kg-postage&#34;&gt;Below 1kg postage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect from us in Brighton (Kemptown): &lt;strong&gt;Free!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st Class: &lt;strong&gt;£3.30&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st Class Signed for:** £4.40**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;above-1kg&#34;&gt;Above 1kg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect from us in Brighton (Kemptown): &lt;strong&gt;Free!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st Class: &lt;strong&gt;£5.45&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st Class Signed for: &lt;strong&gt;£6.55&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All books are now gone. Thank you for your interest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;want-to-buy-them&#34;&gt;Want to buy them?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give me a shout on Twitter, or drop me an email. We can arrange payment by bank transfer, and I’ll post them right away. First come, first served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;already-reserved&#34;&gt;Already reserved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, these are already gone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-8-faces-bundle-i&#34;&gt;The 8 Faces Bundle I&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/8-Faces-Part-I.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4766&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/8-Faces-Part-I.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;8 Faces Issues #1, #2, #3, #4&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED** 8 Faces Issues #1, #2, #3, #4 (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-8-faces-bundle-ii&#34;&gt;The 8 Faces Bundle II&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/8-Faces-Part-II.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4745&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/8-Faces-Part-II.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;8 Faces Issues #5, #6, #7, #8&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED** 8 Faces Issues #5, #6, #7, #8 (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-accessibility-bundle&#34;&gt;The Accessibility Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Accessibility.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4746&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Accessibility.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Design Meets Disability by Graham Pullin, Universal Design for Web Applications by Wendy Chisholm and Matt May, Just Ask: Integrating Accessibility Throughout Design by Shawn Lawton Henry&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Design Meets Disability* by Graham Pullin, *Universal Design for Web Applications *by Wendy Chisholm and Matt May, *Just Ask: Integrating Accessibility Throughout Design *by Shawn Lawton Henry (Above 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-colour-theory-bundle&#34;&gt;The Colour Theory Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Colour-Theory.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4748&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Colour-Theory.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Color Harmony Workbook by Lesa Sawahata, Colour: A workshop for artists and designers by David Hornung&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Color Harmony Workbook *by Lesa Sawahata, *Colour: A workshop for artists and designers *by David Hornung (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-communicating-design-bundle&#34;&gt;The Communicating Design Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Communication-Design.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4749&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Communication-Design.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Visual Literacy: A Conceptual Approach to Graphic Problem Solving by Judith Wilde and Richard Wilde, Communicating Design by Dan M Brown&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED** *Visual Literacy: A Conceptual Approach to Graphic Problem Solving* by Judith Wilde and Richard Wilde, *Communicating Design *by Dan M Brown (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-css-bundle&#34;&gt;The CSS Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/CSS.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4750&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/CSS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sass For Web Designs by Dan Cederholm, CSS3 For Web Designers by Dan Cederholm, SMACSS by Jonathan Snook&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Sass For Web Designs *by Dan Cederholm, *CSS3 For Web Designers *by Dan Cederholm, *SMACSS *by Jonathan Snook (Below 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-design-approaches-bundle&#34;&gt;The Design Approaches Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Design-Philosophies.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4751&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Design-Philosophies.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Design as Art by Bruno Munari, The Language Of Things by Deyan Sudjic, The Hacker Ethic and the Spirit of the Information Age by Pekka Himanen, The Shape of Design by Frank Chimero&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Design as Art *by Bruno Munari, *The Language Of Things *by Deyan Sudjic, *The Hacker Ethic and the Spirit of the Information Age *by Pekka Himanen, *The Shape of Design *by Frank Chimero (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-design-theory-bundle&#34;&gt;The Design Theory Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Design-Theory.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4752&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Design-Theory.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Principles of Form and Design by Wucius Wong, Universal Principles of Design by William Lidwell, Kritina Holden, and Jill Butler&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Principles of Form and Design *by Wucius Wong, *Universal Principles of Design *by William Lidwell, Kritina Holden, and Jill Butler (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-grids-and-visualisation-bundle&#34;&gt;The Grids and Visualisation Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Grids-and-Visualisation.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4753&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Grids-and-Visualisation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Practical Guide to Designing with Data by Brian Suda, Ordering Disorder: Grid Principles for Web Design by Khoi Vinh, Making and Breaking the Grid by Timothy Samara, This Is A Print Handbook&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** A Practical Guide to Designing with Data** ***by Brian Suda, *Ordering Disorder: Grid Principles for Web Design *by Khoi Vinh, *Making and Breaking the Grid *by Timothy Samara, *This Is A Print Handbook *(slim, no spine!) (Above 1kg) **£12**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holistic-design-bundle&#34;&gt;The Holistic Design Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Holistic-Design.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4754&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Holistic-Design.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Designing For Emotion by Aarron Walter, A Practical Guide to Designing the Invisible by Robert Mills&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Designing For Emotion *by Aarron Walter, *A Practical Guide to Designing the Invisible *by Robert Mills (Below 1kg) **£5**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-javascript-and-jquery-bundle&#34;&gt;The JavaScript and jQuery Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/JavaScript.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4757&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/JavaScript.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jQuery in Action by Bear Bibeault and Yehuda Katz, JavaScript: The Good Parts by Douglas Crockford, Simply JavaScript By Kevin Yank and Cameron Adams&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** jQuery in Action* by Bear Bibeault and Yehuda Katz, *JavaScript: The Good Parts *by Douglas Crockford, *Simply JavaScript *By Kevin Yank and Cameron Adams (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mobile-web-bundle&#34;&gt;The Mobile Web Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Mobile-Web.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4759&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Mobile-Web.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mobile First by Luke Wroblewski, Content Strategy For Mobile by Karen McGrane, Mobile Web Design by Cameron Moll, The Mobile Book by Smashing Magazine &#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Mobile First *by Luke Wroblewski, *Content Strategy For Mobile *by Karen McGrane, *Mobile Web Design *by Cameron Moll, *The Mobile Book *by Smashing Magazine (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-user-experience-bundle&#34;&gt;The User Experience Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/User-Experience.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4762&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/User-Experience.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Undercover User Experience Design by Cennydd Bowles and James Box, Neuro Web Design by Susan M Weinschenk, Don’t Make Me Think! By Steve Krug, The Elements Of User Experience by Jesse James Garrett&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Undercover User Experience Design *by Cennydd Bowles and James Box, *Neuro Web Design *by Susan M Weinschenk, *Don’t Make Me Think! *By Steve Krug, *The Elements Of User Experience *by Jesse James Garrett (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-web-design-bundle&#34;&gt;The Web Design Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Web-Design.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4763&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Web-Design.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Practical Guide to Designing for the Web By Mark Boulton, Just Enough Research by Erika Hall&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED** *A Practical Guide to Designing for the Web *By Mark Boulton, *Just Enough Research *by Erika Hall (Above £1kg) **£5**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-writing-more-good-bundle&#34;&gt;The Writing More Good Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Writing-More-Good.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4765&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Writing-More-Good.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Complete Plain Words by Penguin, Chambers Writing for The Web&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** The Complete Plain Words *by Penguin, *Chambers Writing for The Web * (Below 1kg) **£5**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tech-and-design-business-bundle&#34;&gt;The Tech and Design Business Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1335.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4776&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1335.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It’s Not How Good You Are, It’s How Good You Want To Be by Paul Arden, Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson, Insites: The Book by Keir Whitaker and Eliot Jay Stocks, Crush It! by Gary Vaynerchuk&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** It’s Not How Good You Are, It’s How Good You Want To Be* by Paul Arden, *Rework *by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson, *Insites: The Book *by Keir Whitaker and Eliot Jay Stocks, *Crush It! *by Gary Vaynerchuk. (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-t-shaped-designer-bundle&#34;&gt;The T-Shaped Designer Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1334.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4775&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1334.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Interviewing For Research by Andrew Travers, Design Is A Job by Mike Monteiro,  Mobile First by Luke Wroblewski, Undercover User Experience Design by Cennydd Bowles and James Box&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED ***Interviewing For Research* by Andrew Travers, *Design Is A Job *by Mike Monteiro, * Mobile First *by Luke Wroblewski,* Undercover User Experience Design* by Cennydd Bowles and James Box. (Below 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-talk-the-talk-design-bundle&#34;&gt;The Talk The Talk Design Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1333.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4774&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1333.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Designer’s Lexicon by Alastair Campbell, The Universal Methods Of Design by Bella Martin and Bruce Hanington&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** The Designer’s Lexicon *by Alastair Campbell, *The Universal Methods Of Design *by Bella Martin and Bruce Hanington. (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-timeless-usability-bundle&#34;&gt;The Timeless Usability Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1331.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4773&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1331.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Defensive Design for the Web by 37signals, Usability Engineering by Xristine Faulkner&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Defensive Design for the Web *by 37signals, *Usability Engineering *by Xristine Faulkner. (Below 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-graphic-design-bundle&#34;&gt;The Graphic Design Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1330.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4772&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1330.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Designer Says compiled by Sara Bader, Logo Design Love by Jon Hicks, The Icon Handbook by Jon Hicks&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** The Designer Says *compiled by Sara Bader, *Logo Design Love *by Jon Hicks, *The Icon Handbook *by Jon Hicks. (Above 1kg) **£12**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ellen-lupton-typography-bundle&#34;&gt;The Ellen Lupton Typography Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1326.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4771&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1326.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Type on Screen by Ellen Lupton, Thinking With Type by Ellen Lupton&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		**RESERVED*** Type on Screen *by Ellen Lupton, *Thinking With Type *by Ellen Lupton. (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-actionscript-3-0-bundle&#34;&gt;The ActionScript 3.0 Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1322.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4768&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1322.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ActionScript 3.0 Cookbook by Joey Lott, Darron Schall &amp;amp;amp; Keith Peters, Learning ActionScript 3.0 by Rich Shupe with Zevan Rosser&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		***ActionScript 3.0 Cookbook*** by Joey Lott, Darron Schall &amp;amp;amp; Keith Peters, *Learning ActionScript 3.0* by Rich Shupe with Zevan Rosser. (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-typography-bundle&#34;&gt;The Typography Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1325.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4770&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1325.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;8Faces #5, Detail In Typography by Jost Hochuli, A Typography Workbook by Kate Clair&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*8Faces #5*, *Detail In Typography *by Jost Hochuli, *A Typography Workbook *by Kate Clair. (Above 1kg) **£10**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-extreme-programming-bundle&#34;&gt;The Extreme Programming Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1324.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4769&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/IMG_1324.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Mythical Man-Month by Frederick P. Brooks Jr, Testing Extreme Programming by Lisa Crispin and Tip House, Extreme Programming by Martin Lippert, Stefan Roock and Henning Wolf&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*The Mythical Man-Month *by Frederick P. Brooks Jr, *Testing Extreme Programming *by Lisa Crispin and Tip House, *Extreme Programming *by Martin Lippert, Stefan Roock and Henning Wolf. (Above 1kg) **£12**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-being-an-artist-bundle&#34;&gt;The Being An Artist Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Being-An-Artist.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4747&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Being-An-Artist.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Art &amp;amp;amp; Fear by David Bayles and Ted Orland, This Is Not A Book by Keri Smith, Letters To A Young Artist by Julia Cameron&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*Art &amp;amp;amp; Fear** ***by David Bayles and Ted Orland, *This Is Not A Book *by Keri Smith, *Letters To A Young Artist *by Julia Cameron. (Below 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-html5-bundle&#34;&gt;The HTML5 Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/HTML5.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4755&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/HTML5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HTML5 For Web Designers by Jeremy Keith, HTML5 Cookbook by Christopher Schmitt &amp;amp;amp; Kyle Simpson, Introducing HTML5 by Bruce Lawson and Remy Sharp&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*HTML5 For Web Designers *by Jeremy Keith, *HTML5 Cookbook* by Christopher Schmitt &amp;amp;amp; Kyle Simpson, *Introducing HTML5 *by Bruce Lawson and Remy Sharp (Above 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-introductory-philosophy-bundle&#34;&gt;The Introductory Philosophy Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Introductory-Philosophy.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4756&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/Introductory-Philosophy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penguin Dictionary of Philosophy, The Story Of Philosophy by Bryan Magee&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*Penguin Dictionary of Philosophy*, *The Story Of Philosophy *by Bryan Magee (Above 1kg) **£5**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-beginnings-bundle&#34;&gt;The Beginnings Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/The-Beginnings.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4760&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/The-Beginnings.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Autobiography of Charles Darwin, Origin Of Species by Charles Darwin, Big Bang by Simon Singh&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*The Autobiography of Charles Darwin*, *Origin Of Species *by Charles Darwin, *Big Bang *by Simon Singh. (Above 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ologies-bundle&#34;&gt;The Ologies Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/The-Ologies.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4761&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/06/The-Ologies.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mythologies by Roland Barthes, The Decisive Moment by Jonah Lehrer, Here Comes Everybody by Clay Shirky&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		*Mythologies* by Roland Barthes, *The Decisive Moment *by Jonah Lehrer, *Here Comes Everybody *by Clay Shirky (Below 1kg) **£8**
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Sale: Mid 2013 MacBook Air</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/for-sale-mid-2013-macbook-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 16:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/for-sale-mid-2013-macbook-air/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October, I found myself doing a lot more in Terminal than I’d done before, and I needed a computer with a faster processor, so I upgraded to a MacBook Pro. This means that my pimped-out Mid 2013 MacBook Air that I bought in December 2013 is now for sale. It’s in nearly-new condition, as it’s been kept in a shell case for almost all its (short) life. I used it for around 8 months. These are the specs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;13.3&amp;rdquo; Mid 2013 MacBook Air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processor 1.7GHz Intel Dual-Core Core i7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory 8GB 1600MHz LPDDR3 SDRAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Drive 512GB Flash Storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fresh install of OS X Mavericks (easily upgraded to Yosemite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/SP678?viewlocale=en_US&amp;amp;amp;locale=en_US&#34;&gt;exactly the same specs&lt;/a&gt; as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/mac/compare/notebooks.html&#34;&gt;fully-specced new MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;, so you’ll be getting yourself a bargain. I paid £1,579 for it, and you can get it from Apple for £1,499. I’m looking for £1,100, and I’ll include free UPS delivery inside the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, send me an email to me@laurakalbag.com, or tweet me @laurakalbag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/02/air-open.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4598&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/02/air-open.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mid 2013 MacBook Air from front&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/02/air-closed.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4597&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/02/air-closed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mid 2013 MacBook Air with closed lid&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 97: Made in Scotland from girders</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-97-made-in-scotland-from-girders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 14:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-97-made-in-scotland-from-girders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/97&#34;&gt;This week’s episode of Unfinished Business&lt;/a&gt; was great fun to record. Both Ashley Baxter and I were Andy’s guests, and we talked about unhealthy food, being a podcast guest, Christmas decorations, and everything that’s in store for the three of us over the next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;[
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-4098 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/11/unfinishedbusiness.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andrew Clarke &amp;amp;amp; guests have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
](http://unfinished.bz/97)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 89: Burger in donut</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-89-burger-in-a-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 11:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-89-burger-in-a-donut/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/89&#34;&gt;Last week’s episode of Unfinished Business&lt;/a&gt; was a very different discussion from the usual. Andy and I talked about his fantastic idea for Geek Mental Help week (October 27th onwards) and how so many people in our industry are affected by mental health issues. I’ll definitely be writing a post for Geek Mental Help Week, and I hope you will too! I’m sure you’ll be able to find out the latest about Geek Mental Help Week from the Twitter account &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/geekmentalhelp&#34;&gt;@geekmentalhelp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;[
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-4098 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/11/unfinishedbusiness.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andrew Clarke &amp;amp;amp; guests have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
](http://unfinished.bz/83)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-comments&#34;&gt;3 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151412&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Kathy&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151412&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-11T09:57:13+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:57am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I think Geek Mental Help week sounds like a brilliant innovation! As a sufferer of several job-related mental health issues myself (I think being a lone lady in a STEM department attracts them), I would be delighted to share and learn! I’d love to know how to contribute.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laurakalbag bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151413&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1fdeaf38709c0e27b603515b052903f6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1fdeaf38709c0e27b603515b052903f6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://laurakalbag.wpengine.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;laurakalbag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151413&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-11T10:36:30+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:36am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &amp;lt;3 I’m sure others would love to hear from you (I certainly would!) Andy Clarke recently wrote an article on exactly [How can you contribute to Geek Mental Health Week](https://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/how-can-you-contribute-to-geek-mental-help-week&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow).
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-151817&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2cb96c29c8bb3cd04a799c71a78c3635?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Kathy&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-151817&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-10-19T21:27:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:27pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Aw! Thank you, Laura! Thanks for sharing the link, too, and for all the great work you are doing. Kudos.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons why you should get an office dog</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote my Pastry Box thought on 5 reasons why you should get an office dog. It’s not just silly photos of Oskar, but actually five reasons why having Oskar for company has helped keep me sane. Through living and working by myself, to living and working with other people, he’s still incredibly valuable as a companion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you do happen to like dog photos, you might want to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gigapup&#34;&gt;@gigapup on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://alpha.app.net/gigapup&#34;&gt;app.net&lt;/a&gt;. They’re just auto-posted photos of Oskar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-september-11&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4549&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/office-dog.png&#34; alt=&#34;Thursday 11th September 2014 - 5 reasons why you should get an office dog&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give and Tell Challenge</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke challenged me to the “Give and Tell Challenge”&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy to comply. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ceoblues.com/archive/2014/august/giveandtell&#34;&gt;Dan James,&lt;/a&gt; inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_Bucket_Challenge&#34;&gt;ALS Ice Bucket Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, came up with the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You donate to a cause, or causes, that have meaning to you and you say why. You then challenge 3 other people to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-out&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/a&gt;. All Out campaigns for a world where no person will have to sacrifice their family or freedom, safety or dignity, because of who they are or who they love. Living in a country that has a fairly open-minded approach to equality, it’s hard to believe that in 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s illegal to be LGBT in 77 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being LGBT is legal grounds for life imprisonment or execution in 10 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one transgender person is murdered every 36 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only 17 countries recognise marriage equality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is completely unfair to suffer because of the way you were born and who you love. All Out has run a lot of campaigns focusing on the laws and treatment of people in particular countries, but also on the suffering of individuals who desperately need urgent support. They’re a small organisation who often rely on the expertise of its members, so I recommend you &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en/about&#34;&gt;join their mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nominations&#34;&gt;My nominations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.wwf.org.uk/adopt-a-gorilla/&#34;&gt;WWF&lt;/a&gt;, and nominated Sean Johnson, so you should go and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;read Shaun’s post&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewaterproject.org/&#34;&gt;The Water Project&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to nominate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joanna_p&#34;&gt;Jo Porter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nd_kane&#34;&gt;Natalie Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hellofisher&#34;&gt;Steve Fisher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear about an issue that they care about. But I want to change the terms slightly…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-and-or-tell&#34;&gt;Give AND/OR Tell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@boagworld/the-ice-bucket-challenge-e0663fbf6544&#34;&gt;“Give and Tell Challenge” post, Paul Boag&lt;/a&gt; explains the reasons behind giving regularly and how to calculate a reasonable donation size. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;Sean Johnson&lt;/a&gt; both do regular work for charities for free. But not everyone can afford to do so. The element of the Ice Bucket Challenge that I admire the most is that it encourages people to raise awareness of motor neurone disease (ALS). If we can’t afford to donate to charity right now, even though we want to do so, raising awareness is a charitable act in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Jo, Natalie and Steve: I challenge you to give and/or tell. And no time limit this time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplaces of Web Professionals</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 07:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning Martin Wolf published an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinwolf.org/2014/08/14/workplaces-of-web-professionals-part-1/&#34;&gt;blog post with photos of the “workplaces of web professionals”&lt;/a&gt;. I always wonder if people really are &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; tidy, or if they spent a while clearing up before they took the photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The featured photo of my workplace (in our ind.ie home office) shows the fairly typical mess on my desk, and the very typical dog getting in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://martinwolf.org/2014/08/14/workplaces-of-web-professionals-part-1/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4522&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/08/workplaces-of-web-professionals.png&#34; alt=&#34;a photo of my desk, complete with a lot of junk and a dog in shot&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert.fm Playlist</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/desert-fm-playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 09:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/desert-fm-playlist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was asked to create a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.desert.fm/laura-kalbag.html&#34;&gt;playlist of ten songs for Desert.fm&lt;/a&gt;. Nate, Bobby and Jamie sent me an email with the premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our idea is to to add value to digital playlists through personal stories and inspirational music. We’re totally genre agnostic and we don’t judge (honest!), we can find inspiration in the most unlikely of places sometimes, so we encourage our curators not to hold back. If theres a story to it we want to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music is, like it is to many people, a big part of my life. Listening to music together has always been a family activity, and with such a big family, we all developed very critical opinions of each others’ tastes. My dad taught us that it doesn’t matter if your taste in music isn’t “cool”, so I went very non-mainstream in my teens and haven’t looked back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My desert.fm playlist is semi-chronological and describes the context of the music in my life, as I went from enjoying what my dad shared with us, to developing my own &lt;em&gt;very particular&lt;/em&gt; taste. I’ve explained why I love the music, the band or just that song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.spotify.com/user/laurakalbag/playlist/0cPri8LcgM6XgoNcILuDO2&#34;&gt;Spotify playlist of these tracks&lt;/a&gt; if you want to just get down to listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.desert.fm/laura-kalbag.html&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4517&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/08/desert.fm_.png&#34; alt=&#34;Desert.fm presents Laura Kalbag&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/&#34; title=&#34;Becoming part of Indie Phone&#34;&gt;my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-June-5&#34;&gt;my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak&lt;/a&gt;. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-June-5&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4490&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/06/pastry-box-june.png&#34; alt=&#34;Laura Kalbag on The Pastry Box, Thursday 5th June 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiephone.eu&#34;&gt;Indie Phone&lt;/a&gt; for 50% of my working time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What is Indie Phone?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has opened our data up to a lot of potential abuse, including the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.democracynow.org/2013/10/14/edward_snowden_speaks_out_against_nsa&#34;&gt;government dragnet surveillance employed by the NSA and GCHQ (and other governments)&lt;/a&gt;. For users aware of these problems, we can either choose to share our data, or be excluded from the majority of services (and social interactions) on the web. Worse still, the majority of general consumers on the web are unaware of these problems. There are loose, and often misleading, privacy settings on these services. Few people realise that they’re still sharing their data with the companies that own their services, and many other third parties. Even fewer people realise that their email and private messages are being stored, and potentially read and shared, with these services and third parties. To find out more about these issues, I really recommend watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thersa.org/events/audio-and-past-events/2014/Free-is-a-Lie&#34;&gt;Aral’s talk, ‘Free Is a Lie’&lt;/a&gt;, and watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://tacma.net/&#34;&gt;‘Terms and Conditions May Apply’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone aims to create a smart phone that isn’t just for the tech folk that want to take control over their data. We want to create experiences that combine hardware, software, and the cloud, as well as appealing to the everyday consumer. The fact that it’ll be open, and allows you to take control of your data, and choose what you want to be shared, is an essential bonus. It’s incredibly important that these tools are available to everybody. We don’t want to discriminate against those with less tech experience or knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like Indie Phone. There are a few fantastic companies and products working towards other &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;indie technologies&lt;/a&gt;. Together we can try to make technology, and the web, more open and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-indie-tech&#34;&gt;What’s indie tech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data-hungry services have become the norm. Indie Technologies have sustainable business models and offer alternatives to these services. These alternative products need to be design-led and consumer-friendly so they can realistically compete in the consumer market. At Indie Phone, we’re spearheading indie tech, we want to be a great example to other indie technologies. We also have plans to help support and promote other indie tech projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-work-with-indie-phone-when-i-love-client-work-so-much&#34;&gt;Why work with Indie Phone when I love client work so much?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been very trendy lately to switch from client work to a side project or product. A lot of designers and developers don’t enjoy client services. But I do. I really really love working with clients, and helping them achieve their goals. It’s similar to why I love Indie Phone. I like providing services to people who otherwise may not be able to create their own site or understand what would work for them on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been Chief Sounding Board for the last 10 months, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; has researched, planned, brainstormed and agonised over Codename Prometheus and Indie Phone. It’s been his life for nearly a year, so in turn has been a huge part of my life. I have absolute faith in his ability to see it through. It’s been hard sitting on the sidelines, desperately wanting to help, but not being able to dedicate the time and money that a project of this size really needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sale of Aral’s family’s home in Ankara, we finally have funds to afford other people to work on the Indie Phone up to crowd funding. Money is still tight, we can’t afford me to work on Indie Phone 100% of the time, and this works for me. The money is far better spent on other valuable skills required to get us up-and-running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-do-for-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What I do for Indie Phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design and web development. Web is my specialism, so the most expertise I can offer Indie Phone is in producing the websites, mini sites and other web-based materials. I also work on the branding and other general graphic design tasks. Sometimes I do some writing, and I do a lot of editing. All of my work is collaborative. Aral, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jo-porter.com/&#34;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt; and I all review and critique each others’ work, and this is an exciting new experience for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-other-50-of-my-time&#34;&gt;What about the other 50% of my time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still carry on the relationships I have with my existing clients, and take on a few new clients, with a decent amount of time to dedicate to client work. I love the variety of client work, and I really enjoy working with different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-want-to-work-with-other-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;I want to work with other indie tech projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been picky with new projects, I only work with clients that I care about and projects that interest me. That’s how I do my best work. And lately, as I’ve been absolutely influenced by Indie Phone, I really care about the success of indie tech projects. Is your project design-led, free and open, and independent in line with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;Indie Technology Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;? Then I’ve got a deal for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;20-off-for-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;20% off for indie tech projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to put my money where my mouth is. I want to work on indie tech projects so much, that I will work for 20% less (on my hourly rate) for an indie tech project. This will be expensive for me, but I want to do more to help indie technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-can-i-offer-an-indie-tech-project&#34;&gt;What can I offer an indie tech project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I’m an all-round designer. With design-led projects, the majority of indie tech projects probably have a designer in place already, but I’m here for support and strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/graphic-design/&#34; title=&#34;Graphic Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. From logos to typography to icons for your avatars, I can create your brand and show you how to use it effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I love the web. If it’s working out the experience for your app, I can help you with design and front-end development. With marketing sites, I can promote your product with an end-to-end solution (copy to content management system, I can do all of that.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in my 20% discount, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@laurakalbag.com?subject=Indie%20Tech Project&#34;&gt;send me an email at me@laurakalbag.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-huge-but-also-not-so-huge&#34;&gt;It’s huge, but also not so huge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this hasn’t changed much. I’m still working from home, as the Indie Phone office is currently occupying the largest room in our house. I’m still working on projects I love with people that I love. I’m very lucky :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-29759&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://designack.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ngaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-29759&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-04T08:45:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:45am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        What a great idea Laura! I really hope it goes well for you. Having a side project that you’re passionate about can make your client work even better too I think. It’s having that freedom to do something where you can see your creativity bloom while making a difference that is great about side projects.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-32622&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ran&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-32622&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-16T01:00:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;01:00am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Keep us posted on Indie Phone, sounds good.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April’s Pastry Box thought on writing</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 09:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was slow to post about&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-april-19&#34;&gt; my April Pastry Box post&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/a-little-realign/&#34; title=&#34;A little realign&#34;&gt;my realign&lt;/a&gt; got in the way. It was really a little insecure thought about how my writing and thinking is improving, but I’m finding it hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;[
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4466&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/05/pastry-box-april.png&#34; alt=&#34;Laura Kalbag on The Pastry Box, Saturday 19th April 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
](https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-april-19)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today is the day &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box&lt;/a&gt;. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/bakers/year/2014&#34;&gt;the lineup for this year&lt;/a&gt;, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon. It’s very exciting to join in, and I really love the &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/philosophy&#34;&gt;philosophy of consuming content in a way that works for you, and ensures the content’s longevity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethics&#34;&gt;Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great conversation about ethics in client work with Andy Clarke on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/50&#34;&gt;Unfinished Business podcast&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. In a world where society is clearly struggling with so many issues (wealth/poverty divide, human rights, privacy, and so on) I wonder how I can make a difference, or prevent myself from being complicit in further problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run-up to my publishing date on The Pastry Box (it’ll likely be the 11th of each month) I was so worried about what I would write, and trying to come up with something interesting. Then I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mostlysignssomeportents.tumblr.com/post/72759474218/we-are-huxleying-ourselves-into-the-full-orwell&#34;&gt;this post by Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, and had some worrying conversations about other people’s attitude to privacy with &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt;. Suddenly I found myself writing an incoherent stream of anger into my notebook. A long thoughtful walk with the dog later, and I finally had something that might be worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know what you think, this means a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4195&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/the-pastry-box.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of my post on The Pastry Box&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.learningpeople.co.uk/blog/blog-posts/finding-your-inspiration-an-interview-with-web-designer-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me&lt;/a&gt; about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.learningpeople.co.uk/blog/blog-posts/finding-your-inspiration-an-interview-with-web-designer-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4093&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/10/thelearningpeople-734x1024.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of The Learning People: Finding your inspiration, an interview with web designer Laura Kalbag&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I also pledge to be better</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 07:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/10/698-i-pledge-be-better-and-i-hope-you-do-too&#34;&gt;Faruk’s great post “I Pledge To Be Better (And I Hope You Do Too)”&lt;/a&gt; where he speaks about the continuing problems with discrimination and lack of diversity in tech, and how more people should speak up about these issues. Faruk rightly says we all have the power and responsibility to make things better. I believe that when we don’t speak out about discrimination, we’re almost causing as much damage as condoning discrimination. Because it won’t just go away if we pretend it’s not there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/&#34; title=&#34;Women and conferences&#34;&gt;spoken about it before&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m all too aware of how I used to be one of those &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/about-work/e82b7ca7de03&#34; title=&#34;Fantastic post by @Shanley about women in tech for the patriarchy&#34;&gt;“Fuck You, I Got Mine”&lt;/a&gt; women. I want to make up for that. I also believe it’s important that women aren’t scared to be vocal about discrimination and diversity. In fact, it’s of the utmost importance that &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; is scared to be vocal about these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As women, we need to be better allies to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogjustine.wordpress.com/2013/10/12/because-it-needs-to-be-said/&#34;&gt;those who have suffered&lt;/a&gt;. For me, this starts with acknowledging that, whilst my own experiences have been mostly very positive, this doesn’t mean that I’m reflective of the whole industry. It’s too easy to sit in your own self-absorbed bubble. I have so much respect for the people who are standing up and speaking out for diversity, I want to show my support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-not-all-bad-but-it-s-more-than-bad-enough&#34;&gt;It’s not all bad, but it’s more than bad enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get defensive when you’re reading posts like this, it’s easy to get annoyed at people “focusing on the bad”. I want to be clear that I love 99.99% of the people that I’ve met in the industry, and that a huge majority of people are good and mean well. But we’re not going to make anything better by refusing to see the dark side. We need to confront our problems so we know how to find the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pledge&#34;&gt;The pledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/10/698-i-pledge-be-better-and-i-hope-you-do-too#pledge&#34;&gt;Faruk’s pledge&lt;/a&gt; (which you also can &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/KuraFire/7002725&#34;&gt;find and fork on Github&lt;/a&gt;) is a clear set of intentions to help make the industry a better place. I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/laurakalbag/7013814&#34;&gt;forked my own version&lt;/a&gt;, and tweaked it so that it represents my own intentions. This has mostly been removing the part about declining speaking opportunities if it’s an exclusively white/male lineup. As I’m a woman, this puts me in a slightly different position. Still, I want commit to voicing my concerns to organisers if I feel a lineup I’m included in lacks further diversity (within reason). This is a bit wooly, and is all about intentions and contexts, so isn’t so easy to put into a pledge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-pledge-to-be-better&#34;&gt;I Pledge To Be Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want our industry to be a safe, welcoming and inclusive place for everyone, regardless of their gender, abilities, skin colour, sexuality, age, class, neuro-diversity or any other attribute. I acknowledge that this is not currently the case, and will do my best, to the extent that I can afford to dedicate to this, to help make ours a better community and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value the diversity of perspectives that people with different backgrounds bring to the table. I will call out exclusionary practices, behaviours or cultures and see how, together, we can perhaps reshape them to be inclusive and supportive instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will take some time to read up on, and educate myself about issues such as sexism in our industry. I acknowledge the onus is on me to be decently informed before speaking out, calling out, or participating in these discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will examine my own privileges, uncomfortable though it may be, and do my best to recognise them going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will call out people for behaviours that I deem offensive or unacceptable, but I will do so respectfully and with civility. I will strive to educate, not antagonise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge that I will make mistakes, and that I may offend someone unintentionally with my words or actions. Rather than get defensive when called out on it, I will try my hardest to listen respectfully, and learn more instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not attend events that do not have clear &lt;a href=&#34;[http://adainitiative.org/what-we-do/conference-policies/](http://adainitiative.org/what-we-do/conference-policies/&#34; title=&#34;The Ada Initiative Conference anti-harassment policy&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct policies&lt;/a&gt;, like an anti-harassment or diversity statement. I will also decline to attend events that feature, or permit to attend, any known offender of sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pledge to be better, and set a positive example for others in our community, industry, and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-appeal&#34;&gt;The appeal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please blog about diversity. It doesn’t matter if you want to pledge for yourself or not, we just need to make it clear that we don’t accept discrimination in our industry. If you don’t have a blog, why not post a quick tweet? If you’re feeling unsure, &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/09/696-primer-sexism-tech&#34;&gt;read these two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-false-dichotomies-and-diversity/&#34;&gt;primers first&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more Red Bull</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/no-more-red-bull/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/no-more-red-bull/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Using a Fitbit over the last year and a half has taught me that making your habits more visible in public makes you more likely to work harder. When you’re giving up a bad habit, often there’s not much stopping us from slipping back into the bad habits. So I am writing here, on Tuesday 27th August 2013 that &lt;i&gt;I am giving up Red Bull&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It sounds ridiculous, but I have a problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I’ve not got to the point where my teeth have dropped out or I have heart palpitations, but Red Bull has been my “one last thing” for the last couple of years. I used to have a terrible diet, and barely exercised, which I wrote about a little in &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/six-months-of-the-fitbit-and-the-new-fitbit-aria/&#34;&gt;my Fitbit review post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m past that now, I do a lot of exercise and eat healthily but not to the point of obsession. But I’ve still been drinking a lot of Red Bull. Last week I fooled myself thinking that if I swapped Red Bull for organic energy drinks, then it’d be ok. Yesterday I realised that I was just attempting to justify the bad habit. Most people just laugh when I tell them I drink a lot of Red Bull, but you know it’s bad when I tell you that I have Red Bull after breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Addictive personality&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people just seem to get addicted to things that much easier than others. I’m one of them. Luckily I’m addicted to exercise now, so it’s not always a bad thing. But through drinking so much Red Bull, I’m also addicted to caffeine and sugar. I’ve tried giving up Red Bull before, but I just ended up eating more pick’n’mix sweets. When I go on holiday or away, it’s often harder to find energy drinks, so I find myself drinking coffee (which I hate) or tea, loaded with sugar. I’m determined to not replace it with other bad sugary things. I’m writing this here so I really do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Highs and lows&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine and sugar are great, but the rush is so impermanent. I always say I do my best design work when I’m hopped up on caffeine and sugar. I think that’s probably me making excuses for drinking so much Red Bull! I hope that getting caffeine out of my system will result in a more consistent working pace, where I don’t feel like I have to adhere to all these conditions I’ve invented for myself in order to be productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stand by for the whining&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I’m going to be annoying, and sleepy. Sympathy should probably be directed towards&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/aral&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt;, who has to put up with me. I don’t deserve any sympathy, I’m just doing what I should have done so long ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-899&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1abd4058d8f2f3b40af9d61190a6f10a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1abd4058d8f2f3b40af9d61190a6f10a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://thierrydewolf.wordpress.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Thierry D.W.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-899&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-09-09T09:37:46+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:37am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hiya Laura,

first of all, great desicionmaking here! Avid “water-drinking-and-avoiding-all-sorts-of-coffee” person that I am, I can wholeheartily recommend a healthy lifestyle that doesn’t involve any coffe, redbull or cheap alternative.  The only thing that comes close to it for me, is cola, since that stuff keeps me up (and makes me hyper) with even less then half a liter. But since it’s been more than a few years already since I’ve had my last drop, I’d say that that is proof that there can be a life after addiction. You’re not the only one who’s highly vulnerable to addictions there.

The trick that kept me alive through and after the process of the addicition is to have a healthy dose of outgoing alternatives (walking, jogging and running are my favorites), replace the sweet factor by (a lot of) something of the healtier kind (Evian-water is my favorite so far, I’m guilty) and always keep some form of gum at the ready. That last one is to keep your mind of the temptation. Other then that, willpower and short naps are your only friend.

Best of luck (and maybe keep us posted?),

Thierry

PS Sorry I just came around now to posting here, so late after your publication
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;Dare conference in September&lt;/a&gt;. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business. I was only just becoming aware of what I was doing, and writing a talk was a good way for me to dig a little bit deeper. So I wrote a proposal and my proposal was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk has a slightly cheesy name, “My secret is honesty” but I promise you, the content is real. I’ve already tested it on a lovely group of people in Porto, Portugal, and hope to have a shortened version ready in September. It’s a very different topic for me, I usually talk about web design and development, but I think it’s the right place for an open talk about openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3849&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/07/dare-conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dare conference 2013&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies In Tech</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A while ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://adactio.com&#34;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to &lt;a href=&#34;http://ladiesintech.com/&#34;&gt;ladiesintech.com&lt;/a&gt;, suggesting that it might be something that’d interest me. After having a chat with the lovely &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jennlukas&#34;&gt;Jenn Lukas&lt;/a&gt; over email, I had a story that I wanted to share about my adventures in speaking, and Jenn has now helped me &lt;a href=&#34;http://ladiesintech.com/asking-for-help/&#34;&gt;share it on the site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I’ve ever had anybody edit my writing. I’ve had other people proof-read and check my writing for mistakes, but never changing that much (despite often needing it!) Jenn teamed me up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stephaniehay.com/&#34;&gt;Steph Hay&lt;/a&gt;, who was so kind in helping me un-jumble the story into a more coherent order and make sure I made my points clearly. They both gave me a lot of support and encouragement along the way too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ladiesintech.com/asking-for-help/&#34;&gt;My post on ladiesintech.com&lt;/a&gt; is about asking for help, and how I stopped making excuses and found the confidence to get into speaking with the help of other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ladiesintech.com/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2629&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/03/ladiesintech.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ladies in Tech - Celebrating and supporting female speakers in technology&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-524&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4c0f74cdf869bc2256b5fb32a2351f43?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4c0f74cdf869bc2256b5fb32a2351f43?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://jennlukas.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jenn Lukas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-524&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-26T20:50:01+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:50pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I never knew how hard it was to edit until being involved in this site! It’s taught me so much, both being edited myself for my article as well as watching the process with others. It’s an interesting break from development, but also one that reminds me how much I love development. ;)

So happy Jeremy got us in touch!! And double happy that you shared your story with us!! I truly believe the more we share, the more we understand that feelings of nervousness are okay but the reward is totally awesome!! Thanks for helping us spread that story!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 20:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Burnout. Spending hours just staring into space when you’re supposed to be doing work, when you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be doing work. Feeling foggy-headed and grey the whole time when you usually feel eager and excitable. Menial tasks are just about manageable, but anything requiring careful consideration or creative thinking feels impossible. I sleep but I still feel tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m burned out. The last couple of months have really taken their toll. I tend to always be on top of my work schedule, ensuring I don’t work late into the evenings or weekends on client work, as I know I need time away from the screen to spend on my social life and my health. However, due to some client work getting out of hand, over-optimism with scheduling, and a talk at Responsive Day Out (speaking is always exhausting), I got through the mad rush and just couldn’t do &lt;em&gt;any more&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onishiweb.co.uk/2012/09/burnout/&#34;&gt;Adam Onishi has spoken extensively about burnout&lt;/a&gt;, and I know I’ve got it lucky. Burnout can be a bad side effect of really caring about your work, and I’ve always been aware that I’m inclined to over-work and so need to keep myself in check. I rarely lack motivation (though sometimes lack confidence), I love what I do. Burnout is not laziness, it’s illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dragging-myself-out-of-it&#34;&gt;Dragging myself out of it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week of feeling incredibly unhappy, I spent a weekend trying to escape work. But spending the weekend worrying about the amount I had to do once the weekend was over made it worse. The first step to dragging myself out of the burnout was acknowledging that it had become a problem, and realising that I would improve far quicker if I stopped trying to fight it and let myself rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-little-bit-at-a-time&#34;&gt;A little bit at a time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that working a little bit at a time is helping. I’m always very productive in the mornings, so I’ve been getting up early and getting on with work. When I feel the burnout dragging me down, I stop. I do something completely different, completely unrelated to work (walking the dog, playing computer games). These stints away from work seem to re-invigorate me, and after a couple of hours I can get back into working again. I can’t speak for how anyone else feels when they’re burnt out, but this seems to be making me more productive, and really helps my mood and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also trying to harness the moments when I’m feeling sharp and focused. Right now I’m writing a blog post because it’s too late to do client work (I know it’d have an effect on a productive early morning tomorrow) but I’m still running off the adrenaline of a successful few hours work earlier in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-minds-are-funny-things&#34;&gt;Our minds are funny things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We forget how important our state of mind is to our overall health until it becomes a real problem. Recent events with those close to me, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.truthfully.ca/&#34;&gt;Shannon Fisher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://lizelcoate.tumblr.com/post/42841858501/18-months-of-freelance-and-the-black-dog&#34;&gt;Liz Elcoate&lt;/a&gt; writing bravely about depression have inspired me to write this post. Let’s talk about these funny minds of us more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;28-comments&#34;&gt;28 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-497&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3d5cb04f1bd3bd744b5a7050ebc14874?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3d5cb04f1bd3bd744b5a7050ebc14874?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.jonathanstrong.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jonathan Strong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-497&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T20:50:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:50pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great blog post, i feel i can relate to ‘Burnout’.

I’m currently working full-time, starting my own business and studying a distance learning degree! I’ve found that if things get too much and i feel myself getting stressed, i take 15mins to meditate. It’s something new for me but i’ve found that it helps.
        &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-498&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/76f881f8cd63e66837aeb26023e9dd69?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/76f881f8cd63e66837aeb26023e9dd69?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/Niaccurshi&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Lee Griffin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-498&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T20:51:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:51pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        The frustrating thing about it is that you can both understand how it was avoidable&amp;#8230;but also how it couldn’t be avoided! I imagine it’s degrees worse as a full time freelancer, but the whole job is about relationships, and it almost seems inevitable that points are reached where we find ourselves painted in to a corner and unwilling (rather than unable) to do what we really should do which is be frank with those we’re working with and for. 

But there’s the fear that the relationship may sour, and probably some experience in the past about how turning back work, or pushing it back, has resulted in the business side of that relationship being as fruitful.

Jenny (@Grinblo) posted this link today and I think it’s really useful on this subject: [http://t.co/V8ZrEIAgIy](http://t.co/V8ZrEIAgIy&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
        &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-499&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6a3ee49625841a3100dd0dc00309cf35?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6a3ee49625841a3100dd0dc00309cf35?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://timothybsmith.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Tim Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-499&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T20:53:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:53pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks for writing about this. I had recently been in the same boat.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-500&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9dd6817ae3cd4093d6db7cd649836112?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9dd6817ae3cd4093d6db7cd649836112?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Karolina Szczur&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-500&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T20:57:45+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:57pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        There’s an interesting take on positive side of burnout too: [http://zenhabits.net/burn/](http://zenhabits.net/burn/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)

And plus one to being there.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-501&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8bff715a965594c68c993ca957036af?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8bff715a965594c68c993ca957036af?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://welcomebrand.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;James Young (@welcomebrand)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-501&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T21:00:47+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:00pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’ve suffered from mild depression (actual, diagnosed depression rather than feeling depressed) in the past as well as having the occasional stretches of just feeling burnt out and unable to focus and it’s all gone away since I’ve started distance running. 

I love being outside in all weathers covering the miles on local trails and I’d recommend it to anyone who struggles. 

There’s a notion that designers love their jobs so much they’re always “on the clock” thinking about design, buying typography books or practicing photography skills etc and I think it’s vital getting away from it all whether it’s running or some other hobby/activity. 

Hope your mind clears a little after a break!

J.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-502&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/11e31aeb26f58f57edf881cfddd974b3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/11e31aeb26f58f57edf881cfddd974b3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.tanusoft.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Christophe Franco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-502&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T21:41:01+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:41pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It’s so difficult to comment on this one&amp;#8230; Kudos for having the strength to admit if though, I know what it feels to go through all this, and the hardest part is probably to admit it publicly.

One deep cause that I’ve been able to identify was lacking a reason to keep on with the daily work routine that was progressively burning me out. After a year or so since I’ve finally realized this, I’ve still to figure out what could possibly change my mind so deeply (hint : at least I know it includes life changing decisions both in my work and in my personal life&amp;#8230;)

&lt;p&gt;Reading Peter Bregman’s 18 Minutes has helped me a lot figuring out all this&amp;#8230; If you haven’t read it yet, it’s worth giving it a try.

[http://peterbregman.com/18-minutes/](http://peterbregman.com/18-minutes/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-523&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae762973fff8da00c83a428a82f5541f?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae762973fff8da00c83a428a82f5541f?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.burnouttoolbox.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Roger Carr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-523&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-28T05:20:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;05:20am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I second the recommendation for the book “18 Minutes.”  I read it at the suggestion of a friend and it helped me as well.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-503&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6558e7f01eb5667da77bdd3f9fbd38e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6558e7f01eb5667da77bdd3f9fbd38e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kodsmuts.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-503&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T22:15:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:15pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Thank you for sharing!

I kind of recognize this. People talk a lot about separating work and your personal life. As for me, since I started working as a web developer, I don’t have a barrier between those two anymore. This is both awesome and real bad. I’ve definitely had my moments when I’ve been totally stressed out. &lt;/p&gt;
I really hope you feel better soon. Stay strong!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-504&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6ace81a8eaf2f4997e054f8d19b0e0a2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6ace81a8eaf2f4997e054f8d19b0e0a2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://totl.net/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Christopher Gutteridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-504&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T22:18:11+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:18pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I am an always-on-the-clock kinda person, but I know (now, after many mistakes and f- ups) that I need to keep some slack in the schedule. Even if I’m in full flow and *could* take on one more thing, I’ve learned to keep enough slack so when I go into a mild burnout I don’t let anybody down. 

That’s when, not if. You can’t run 100% all the time, so don’t budget your time that way. You’ll make yourself ill trying to look after everybody but yourself. 

I generally take the view that any respectable professional looks after their tools and should be respected for doing so. Your number one tool is yourself; mind and body &amp;#8212; not looking after your health isn’t going the extra mile, it’s unprofessional. You’ve got to say some small “no”s all the time, so you don’t end up having to say “no” for 6 months.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-505&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a1a96ac1ce9d8ae633ad9a45990495ba?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a1a96ac1ce9d8ae633ad9a45990495ba?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.sushkelly.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Sush Kelly (@maxray)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-505&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T22:51:04+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:51pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Ah yes burn out. Kind of sneaks up on you! Had a real bout of it over the last year since we had a little boy. Adding him and the associated sleep depravation and lack of free time suddenly shifted the balance and I realised I had been burning the candle at both ends in order to maintain things. 

As James mentioned about running I found that a run or bike ride really helped as well as accepting that I can no longer just work through the night to get something done! 

It is definitely something that affects web designers more than other fields. I think this is because of the constant shifting in skills and the like.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-506&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e2feaeedc595ffdc675f31f1e6920526?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e2feaeedc595ffdc675f31f1e6920526?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/paulmasek&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Paul Masek&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-506&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-12T23:44:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:44pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I find keeping up with the constant changes in the web dev world and the resources that go along with that the most exhausting thing (It does keep things interesting though!).  

I’d be interested to know how people manage to fit ‘education’ into their busy schedules, as I often find my twitter favourites / instapaper / google reader lists spiral out of control&amp;#8230;.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-507&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c35f88ae9dcb3582323160d0dd137bc8?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c35f88ae9dcb3582323160d0dd137bc8?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://joeyaugustin.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Joey Augustin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-507&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-13T02:20:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;02:20am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The combination of staring at screens all day, sitting, trying to keep up with the industry, looking for work, doing work&amp;#8230; it all adds up to this mental juggling act and before we know it our brain and body fail.

I’m working through similar issues. Being a one-person show as a freelancer is very difficult. Thanks for being honest. I wish you the best.&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-508&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/fe0839f2e5944283ae5e63aa43f125e3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/fe0839f2e5944283ae5e63aa43f125e3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://helloimnik.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Nik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-508&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-13T13:31:47+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:31pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I can completely relate to this –; a bi-product of being a perfectionist, working hard towards my design career and having an almost full time admin job to hold down too. I find myself getting depressed and cabin fevery when I spend too long doing work in front of the computer so it definitely is worth considering our mental health, taking time away from the computer and doing things that refresh you. Wise words Laura!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-509&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6d7a74af65923df9030944188a90ef5?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6d7a74af65923df9030944188a90ef5?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Chris Comben&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-509&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-13T14:09:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:09pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Ah you all just need to man up! ;)

I’ve found cutting up the day and not worrying about constant work helps me too. Watch some TV while working, take a 10 minute nap, call someone, go see a film. Yes it does mean sometimes I have to work at night, but if I feel like I can then it helps me. It amazes me if you actually stop and look at an office how often people are actually not working. You just feel that if you work on your own or at home that you have to do more hours than anyone else.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-510&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/81b6f9b56b91806d00192a12f2d78269?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/81b6f9b56b91806d00192a12f2d78269?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Paul Cross&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-510&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-13T16:27:25+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:27pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Possibly the “best” articulation I’ve read.  7 years into running a small business and I’ve been feeling like you describe for the last 2.  There are a few other symptoms you’ve not listed, but I’m not man enough to admit to them.  All the best.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-511&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0d67d2d5776421751c75899fe7c8b0aa?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0d67d2d5776421751c75899fe7c8b0aa?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.republicofquality.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Steve Fisher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-511&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-13T17:31:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:31pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Laura, this is such a great post. One I’ve been close to writing over the last few months as I’ve had too much on my plate and knew I was more than burnt out and had reached depression. Recently I took a few days off which lead to three weeks off work just so I could regain some balance. I’m still working on it as it isn’t easy, but I’m lucky to have a courageous life partner at my side. 

I want you to know that Shannon and I are in your corner ready to contribute to a healthy future! You should take some time off this summer and come to Vancouver. ; )
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-513&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/50a2b24590a36e2ca9404a4c03bbe233?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/50a2b24590a36e2ca9404a4c03bbe233?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://truthfully.ca&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;shannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-513&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-15T02:44:34+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;02:44am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        HELLS YEAH. xo
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-512&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/af595e4c74f8c5b5347cd24b132ec50a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/af595e4c74f8c5b5347cd24b132ec50a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Brian Hermelijn&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-512&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-14T11:28:03+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:28am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I have to say, that I am completely related to this as well. Its like you work on for hours on end, without caring for your own health.

So finding that [peak hours that makes you more creative, would not only give you the advantage to finish work easier, it will also makes you come up with better results. 

Aside from that, I wholeheartedly agree that playing games or just watch some shows that makes you laugh, can make your mind rest and enjoy the moment, until you  can start working again. For some this may be difficult, since they become to focused on the other mentioned tasks.

But it’s definitely something to try out. Thanks for posting this article!

Brian
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-515&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2c22ec5e9ac5e4af3a5853fe2fd67e77?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2c22ec5e9ac5e4af3a5853fe2fd67e77?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Chatman R.&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-515&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-15T20:52:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:52pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’ve dealt with burnout a few times. It really is a consequence of loving your work so much that it doesn’t feel like work. I used to pull a ton of all-nighters to get things done, because I was so eager to get it all launched. Your sleeping habits get messed up, and the exhaustion just shatters productivity.

That said, I’m nowhere near strict enough to have 9-5 kind of consistent hours. Instead I work when I feel most productive, and after a set time (usually 7 hours, give or take an hour), I just *stop*. I’ve found it helps to work according to your natural rhythm, and sometimes that just means stepping back from the keys when time’s up. 

Of course, as you said, sometimes things just spill over in ways we don’t expect. Burnout used to completely piss me off, but now I just try to accept it as a sign that my mind is running on empty and needs a break. And I completely agree that as people we try very hard to look bulletproof to the outside world. Sharing our vulnerabilities can be liberating in a sense, because we all have them. It’s just part of being human.

As always, I appreciate your honesty. Lets us know we’re not alone with our frustrations.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-516&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/77b178c0c5bec748485307a18e73c6b9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/77b178c0c5bec748485307a18e73c6b9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://simoncox.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Simon Cox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-516&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-18T10:00:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:00am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I have talked with Adam about this having been through it myself several times.  This is going to happen to a lot of people if they don’t balance life and work. You right to find other things to do but video games is a bit too close to working on the web –; still using a computer. Taking the dog for a walk is good but you will still be thinking about work while getting pulled along.

Find yourself a hobby –; something you can loose yourself in that completly removes yourself from design and the web. I make model railways –; it’s challenging and very creative (the way I do it –; read ‘bodge’) and completly removes my mind from work and the web. Choose something that doesn’t put any time pressures on you, something that you need to concentrate on and requires some craft to acomplish. The craft aspect will instill ideas in you head for later by opening new nural pathways and provide inspiration.

Last year  I took a week off work and built a shed –; quite a big shed. I was absolutly exhausted, had loads of cuts and bruises including nettle stings when I ignominiously fell off the staging into a nettle bed –; and despite all that the following week I was unstopable at work, really motivated and full of inspiration. 

Go get ’em girl.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-517&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/65796052d4c7fc7ff84eb65ba2a17861?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/65796052d4c7fc7ff84eb65ba2a17861?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/twittem&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Edward McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-517&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-26T22:27:15+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:27pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        One line you said really sticks with me, “Burnout can be a bad side effect of really caring about your work” The interesting thing for me lately is defining the which part of caring is bring me so much grief. 

Personally, I truly get invested in the success of my employers/clients. Sometime this leads to burnout from being overworked, other times it leads to burnout over the actions/inaction of said employer/client. This had led to a lot of thought over when to terminate work for a freelance client or look for a position at another company. 

I find the things the burn me out the most are feeling like you’re working for a company that doesn’t recognize your contributions, or for a client that doesn’t put foot to pavement and use the tools created to be successful.

&lt;p&gt;I often find myself analyzing what I could have done better to contribute to their success. What tools could I have equipped them with? Did I build the best product for them? Did I really hit their target market?

Then apathy kicks in, and its defiantly a squatter in my house of creativity.&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-521&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7966b70a1382fbd8ee144239e1c386d9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7966b70a1382fbd8ee144239e1c386d9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/benpford&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ben Ford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-521&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-19T17:18:06+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:18pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nice article Laura.

The way you explain to overcome ‘burnout’ is generally a very good way of working anyway; find the time you work at your best, and try to get a higher percentage of your work done during that time. Take short, regular breaks completely away from your work and your work station.

I read a lot of blogs about this way of working and completely ignored it, questioning how I can do more work when I work less hours.

I decided to try this technique in the last year of my degree, and it completely changed the way I was writing, revising and studying and haven’t stopped working this way since.&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-522&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae762973fff8da00c83a428a82f5541f?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae762973fff8da00c83a428a82f5541f?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.burnouttoolbox.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Roger Carr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-522&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-28T05:16:54+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;05:16am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It is great that you are writing about the topic of burnout.  I have been there and consider myself a recovering burnout.

It is great that you are already aware of burnout and are addressing it before it becomes more serious.  I denied its existence while it crept up on me, so it has required more time and change to deal with it.

Getting away from work can provide a temporary relief, but doesn’t change the work situation.  If you continue to find yourself in chronic stress, consider reevaluating your purpose, goals and processes on the work side of your life.  Changes may be required.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and conferences</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 21:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I used to not understand the fuss around women at conferences, I thought that we should all just carry on with what we were doing well already and not get caught up in needless controversy. I even &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/women-in/&#34; title=&#34;Women in…&#34;&gt;wrote a blog post saying exactly that a couple of years ago&lt;/a&gt;. I’d never experienced (to my knowledge) any difficulties because I was a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bit-uncomfortable&#34;&gt;A bit uncomfortable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I started hearing more about/was exposed to women who did have bad experiences. And I attended a few events where I just didn’t feel comfortable. It took me a while to pinpoint why I didn’t feel right. I didn’t realise right away that it was the lack of diversity that made me feel singled out. I realised that it was also the reason I felt uncomfortable when I was invited to women-only events. It wasn’t because I want to be surrounded by women, it’s because I want to be surrounded by diversity. It’s unique perspectives that bring more interesting solutions to problems and promote innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-s-hard-to-know-if-you-re-not-being-welcoming&#34;&gt;It’s hard to know if you’re not being welcoming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At these events where I felt uncomfortable, I didn’t have any &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; experiences, it was more that I felt people didn’t expect me to be there; I wasn’t the target audience. So rarely in these situations is there gender-based discrimination, it’s usually just ignorant comments based on stereotypes like “I didn’t think you’d be a developer, I thought girls were usually designers.” It was always the case that the men making the comments or featuring scantily-clad women in their presentations didn’t realise the effect these things might have on the audience, or that they might be alienating people. This is half of the problem, when you’re someone who’s rarely on the receiving end of these things, it’s hard to understand the effect they could have on others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feeling-special&#34;&gt;Feeling special&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I think I was trying to protect in my defensive blog post was that sometimes I could see the upsides of being singled out. It made me feel special in my uniqueness, like I had something that no one else had, and I got more attention because of it. I’m a bit ashamed, but I’m not too angry at my former self because I think that’s a fairly normal thing to feel, everybody wants to feel like one in a million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also a bit nervous, I didn’t want to have the spotlight put on me for the wrong reasons. I’d done a couple of talks at bar camps, and I quite liked the idea of doing more in the future. I didn’t want to be cast as “the token girl” speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-it-s-worth-effecting-change&#34;&gt;Why it’s worth effecting change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big deal now is about the amount of women speakers at conferences, and it’s kind of an extension of the “women attending conferences”, “women in the industry”, “women studying computing” problems. The thing is, this is a point where &lt;strong&gt;we can actually make a difference&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’d be very difficult for most of us to effect change in education, but it’s much easier for us to get more women representing the industry at conferences. This could hopefully then encourage more women to attend conferences, which would lead to more women in the industry, women studying computing subjects etc, and the same goes for other minority groups. I don’t think many people would argue that this is a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quotas-at-conferences-they-re-not-the-only-possible-solution&#34;&gt;Quotas at conferences, they’re not the only possible solution…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big controversy is about how we can manage this. Without resorting to quotas or all women speakers reluctant to accept speaking invitations without wondering “am I only here because I’m a girl?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s currently a big problem with conference organisers who just aren’t that bothered about diversity in the industry. I can understand their hiding away from the issue, because actively trying to improve it is very very hard. There have been a &lt;a href=&#34;http://2012.jsconf.eu/2012/09/17/beating-the-odds-how-we-got-25-percent-women-speakers.html&#34;&gt;few posts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekfeminism.org/2012/05/21/how-i-got-50-women-speakers-at-my-tech-conference/&#34;&gt;written about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2012/11/solving-pipeline-problem.html&#34;&gt;how conferences have done this&lt;/a&gt;, but the main point is that organisers have been forced to look inside themselves and consider whether they pick their speakers objectively, without bias against minorities. Many organisers ask their friends to speak. It must be an awkward thing if you suddenly realise that, totally unintentionally, all your friends are white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;examining-ourselves&#34;&gt;Examining ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a problem because most people couldn’t possibly identify this in themselves, and then those that do wouldn’t want to admit it anyway. It’s difficult to understand that we (society) tend to favour white men in authority roles (such as speaking at conferences) because that’s what our culture has taught us to want. You don’t have to be a white man to feel this way towards white men in authority either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fighting-our-biases&#34;&gt;Fighting our biases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to combat these biases (whether they’re known or unknown, and whether we acknowledge them or not) is to ask conference organisers to review their speaker selection process. Especially if it seems to result in featuring one type of person. Nothing more than that. Quotas don’t help, because that just results in “token” speakers, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2013/01/a-simple-suggestion-to-help-phase-out-all-male-panels-at-tech-conferences/266837/&#34;&gt;men pledging to not speak unless there’s a satisfactory representation of women&lt;/a&gt; is helpful, because it’s telling the organisers that diversity is important to them, and that you believe the current lineup isn’t representative of a fair speaker selection process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledging-what-s-going-on&#34;&gt;Acknowledging what’s going on&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not always a problem if organisers used a fair process and it still resulted in an all white male lineup. The important part is that they acknowledge there’s a problem and try to explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;. We all know that there’s not as many women in the industry as men, what we want to know is that people are trying to improve upon the situation, rather than promoting an environment where minorities don’t feel comfortable. Without even acknowledging that a problem exists, the imbalance in the industry will inevitably continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;standing-up&#34;&gt;Standing up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campaigning for diversity is the final controversy. It’s not a fun topic to discuss, and people are very easily hurt if they feel as though they’re being attacked or accused of gender discrimination. Unfortunately this results in all sorts of people reacting in ways that aim to shut up those who are trying to address the imbalance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Both men and women have said that men’s opinions on the matter aren’t as valid as women’s opinions. This is sad. While men may not have been able to experience the bias against women first-hand, that shouldn’t mean that they’re not allowed to fight for the equality that they believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great analogy from Martin Pilkington “…But you’re not allowed to speak out on women’s rights as you’re not a woman! Nor animal rights as you’re not a pigeon!” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pilky/status/294468887246938115&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/pilky/status/294468887246938115&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. I’ve seen a few women on Twitter imply that it’s not a problem because they haven’t had bad experiences themselves. This is the camp I used to fall into. Because it wasn’t affecting me, I didn’t want to draw negative attention to myself. It’s ok if you haven’t experienced something and so you feel uncomfortable standing up for it, but to deny that something exists because it hasn’t affected you seems very self-centred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the one that I had feared for so long, and it finally happened to me a couple of weeks ago:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well she certainly wasn’t a ‘token girl’ at our second event, but she appears to want to be branded as one” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/leydon/status/294457218114408448&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/leydon/status/294457218114408448&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best way to shut women up about equal rights is to suggest that they’re only doing it for selfish reasons.*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nobody-wants-to-be-the-token-speaker&#34;&gt;Nobody wants to be the token speaker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy speaking occasionally, but I’m really more of a fan of attending conferences. I don’t want token women speakers to exist, let alone have people suggest that I am one, and that I was only asked to speak to fulfil a quota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keeping-on-standing-up&#34;&gt;Keeping on standing up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still going to fight this one out, though. I want to make the industry a more diverse, interesting and inviting place, and I want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/a-loveletter/&#34; title=&#34;A loveletter&#34;&gt;set a good example for those that come after us&lt;/a&gt;. I know that I’m quite a confident person, and I feel like I’m in a better position to stand up for us than many others, and I don’t want to waste my opportunity to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are people who write about this subject in a far more analytical, less emotional, way. If you want to know more, I particularly recommend Aral Balkan’s, Faruk Ateş’s and Sara Wachter-Boettcher’s posts. I’ve included some that I’ve found very useful below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/article/universal-design-irl&#34;&gt;Universal Design IRL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2012/11/673-problem-slate-white-male-speakers&#34;&gt;The Problem with a Slate of White, Male Speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-false-dichotomies-and-diversity/&#34;&gt;On false dichotomies and diversity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/stop-staring-at-my-willy-please/&#34;&gt;Stop staring at my willy, please&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/diversity-equality-toxicity-etc/&#34;&gt;Diversity, equality, toxicity, etc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;15-comments&#34;&gt;15 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-468&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6e42ad665fb2b5579feb77328563afb5?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6e42ad665fb2b5579feb77328563afb5?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/helloanselm&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Anselm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-468&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T09:18:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:18am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I really like this article much. You mention the most valid points and problems we currently have (won’t limit that to our industry as this appears in many more industries the same way).

&lt;p&gt;Just to add one thing to your personal experience: I am sorry about this, this tweet is unnecessary. But as a male (it just doesn’t matter I want to say with that) speaker who is not known very much and new to speaking you get such comments regardless of your gender. I also got some very disappointing comments on some talks of me. I do think this is very unpleasant to people who speak because they want to share something. People are taking ones self-confidence with such statements.

Spoken for most speakers (I am assuming here) I don’t think they want to be speakers because they wanna be rock-stars but because they want to share something. Criticize them by just tweeting / writing such crappy statements just shows how poor-minded the person is who writes or says this.&lt;/p&gt;
btw: Can you set line-height in textarea back to normal? hard to write here ;-)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-469&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-469&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T09:30:34+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:30am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Traditionally, I’ve always leaned towards the school of thought that says “The population is evenly split along gender lines, women are just as talented as men, therefore the number of women in the industry/on boards of directors/speaking at conferences should automatically balance themselves, without any need to do anything about it.” That works well enough in theory, but if, as seems to be the case, it isn’t balancing well, then I’m happy to do what I can to adjust the situation. For reasons that I don’t entirely understand, having not experienced them myself, (some) women seem to need, or at least appreciate, female role models. Therefore, it seems to me that for the tech industry (conference speakers etc) to balance properly, we first need to reach a critical mass of female role models. If this is something that can only be achieved by actively considering the gender of speakers, then so be it.

Regarding your point about male views not being as valid as female ones: I think a lot of men (myself included) feel that expressing opinions on this subject is a little bit like a rich MP talking about what life is like for the poor. Many of us would quite like to take more of a stand on the issue, but I think we need to be invited to do so by women first. Otherwise we feel like we’re barging in on a conversation of which we’re not currently a part.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-473&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c36b48f5546f3977336c4e7f2f33771a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c36b48f5546f3977336c4e7f2f33771a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.sophiedennis.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Sophie Dennis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-473&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T11:50:45+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:50am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Mark, please do speak up. We need all the good men like yourself to take a stand on this –; otherwise we’re too easily dismissed in some quarters as “those shrill women”. 

I agree with Amber that it’s easy to be insulated from this even as a woman. I’ve never been threatened or publicly insulted like many women I hear from. To be honest I’m fairly thick-skinned and when I’m aware of sexist behaviour towards myself, tend just to find it hilarious.

It’s something, as you can imagine, that Andy and I are grappling with with [Digpen](http://digpen.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow). Part of me can’t imagine anyone behaving like this at one of our conferences. I’m tempted to say that the atmosphere here in the South West is quite different, and we’re wary of making a big deal of “zero tolerance” in case that makes people think we *do* have a problem. At the same time, we want to make it clear that if there is ever this kind of behaviour at a Digpen event, or we hear of anyone treating our speakers badly (whatever their gender), we won’t stand for it.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-475&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-475&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T15:55:32+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:55pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        As you can imagine, Sophie, I’ve been thinking a lot about DigPen in this context, not least because it forms the bulk of my recent conference experience. I’ve certainly never witnessed any sexism there, and I wonder if that is down to the crowd or the history of the event. Obviously DigPen has never set out to be female-orientated, but between being founded by Frankie and now steered by you, it’s always had a strong female presence on the stage. I have two ideas about why this may have made a difference. 1) An event that has a strong female presence from the outset might be less likely to attract the sort of men who don’t respect and value women in technology, and 2) (more importantly) the presence of women standing on that stage from day one has provided exactly the sort of role model for women that I was talking about above. This may have given other women confidence to both attend and speak at the events, without worrying that they won’t be received well. Of course it could simply be that everyone connected to DigPen is just so damn lovely ;-)
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-470&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1abd4058d8f2f3b40af9d61190a6f10a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1abd4058d8f2f3b40af9d61190a6f10a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://thierrydewolf.wordpress.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Thierry D.W.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-470&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T09:51:48+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:51am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hi Laura,

I must say, I’m at a loss for words, partially because (kind of like yourself) I never *really* was exposed to any bad behaviour on conferences. But more importantly, and I cannot stress this enough, because I am stunned by the braveness you have to keep fighting despite the fact you’ve never had any real setback during conferences. Don’t get this the wrong way though, I’m sure nobody wants to be called out as a token, I’m sure, but I’ve seen people write crazy stuff on the internet as well, and yours seems still bareable compared to them. Yet, despite this, you still fight back, even if it was just to defend those whom are truely being bullied. Now that.. that’s a noble thing. It’s why I’m proud to know you.

Keep fighting Laura, we’re behind you ;)&lt;/p&gt;
PS Hope I didn’t say/write anything offensive here? Sorry if I did.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-471&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/899342d1ff532340125ae00d33c250c6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/899342d1ff532340125ae00d33c250c6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://iandevlin.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-471&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T10:05:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:05am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        You say “we all tend to favour white men in authority roles (such as speaking at conferences) because that’s what our society and culture has taught us to want” –; do you really believe this sweeping, generalisation of a statement?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-478&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1d373d0d4bec09d439451824b5a7e3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1d373d0d4bec09d439451824b5a7e3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;neil manuell&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-478&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-07T18:14:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:14pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @ian there are some very elegant recent studies that confirm this. I will try and dig out a link.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-472&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1d373d0d4bec09d439451824b5a7e3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1d373d0d4bec09d439451824b5a7e3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://revisual.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;neil manuell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-472&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T10:46:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @mark As for me, I would not think of it along those lines –; some of my best friends are women, or gay, or have a disability. I live with a woman and a baby daughter. All these people are part of my life and are what shapes me. I would never deign to fight for their rights (apart from my son and daughter as they do not have a voice as yet). However I will fight for *my* right to be surrounded by diversity. I will fight for *my* right not to be surrounded by hatefulness, or labeled as hateful because my neighbour is.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-476&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-476&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T16:15:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:15pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Neil, that’s an interesting idea. I’d never thought about having a right to diversity around me. Kind of makes sense in a way though, if you accept the argument (as I do) that diversification results in an enriching experience.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-474&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1ba19b20dfd597b96b1b780a0bbb6dd8?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1ba19b20dfd597b96b1b780a0bbb6dd8?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.twitter.com/AllThingsSmitty&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Matt Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-474&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-05T15:20:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:20pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks for sharing this.  You have some good insight about this. It’s just a shame that our community is filled with this crap.  We’re supposed to support one another, have passion for what we do and share it to grow the community.  These old-world views about gender have no place.  Lea Verou made a comment to me recently that she saw (in Europe, at least) that the southern part of Europe was more sexist than the northern part.  We have to put a kabash on ignorance and make it well known that the community won’t tolerate it.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-479&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8302284db42037f9aadcb322990c0d1b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8302284db42037f9aadcb322990c0d1b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.voxylady.com.au&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Debbie Carr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-479&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-11T01:39:36+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;01:39am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Having started my first speaker bureau in 2004, I realised a number of years later that most of my speakers were male. Nothing wrong with that, except I found I was always shortlisting men. Only solution was to form a women’s speaker agency which I did. Voxy Lady Women’s Speaker Bureau. And..no I don’t discriminate I also represent men on my now re-branded original bureau. 

What amazes me the most about having a women’s speaker bureau is how many requests I get for my speakers to speak for FREE!!! And yes, even from corporations who could easily afford a speaker.  We don’t do free because our speakers are all seasoned professionals who need a fair exchange for their expertise.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-480&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/24bc8a6bed2974ac9cf37762b589e7d2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/24bc8a6bed2974ac9cf37762b589e7d2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.peterstreet.com.au&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Peter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-480&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-11T02:17:41+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;02:17am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Nice reading you’re taking a negative and making it into a positive, not just for your self, but also for people who would in a similar way feel left out.

Additionally, I am prepared to take one for the team, reviewing the appropriateness of the scantily clad women images.

&lt;p&gt;Best Regards,

 Peter&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A loveletter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-loveletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 12:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-loveletter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;p-style-opacity-0-9-font-style-italic-note-i-wrote-this-a-while-ago-when-i-was-thinking-about-the-things-that-made-me-want-to-work-on-the-web-of-course-it-s-not-exclusively-women-that-inspire-me-but-as-a-girl-who-continually-questions-the-value-she-is-bringing-to-a-project-i-often-find-the-women-of-the-web-had-the-greatest-effect-on-my-self-assurance-i-wrote-this-in-my-notebook-in-a-fit-of-fury-nbsp-after-witnessing-some-upsetting-trolling-towards-a-couple-of-women-on-twitter-p&#34;&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;opacity: 0.9; font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Note: I wrote this a while ago when I was thinking about the things that made me want to work on the web. Of course, it’s not exclusively women that inspire me, but as a girl who continually questions the value she is bringing to a project, I often find the women of the web had the greatest effect on my self assurance. I wrote this in my notebook in a fit of fury&amp;nbsp;after witnessing some upsetting trolling towards a couple of women on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the women of the web (and those who support them),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You inspire me. I don’t just mean that in a throwaway hero-worship kindof way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your bravery and determination give me the belief and desire to stand up and talk about what I care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s not &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; you’re women, or &lt;em&gt;despite&lt;/em&gt; that you’re women. You share what you believe in because you don’t want to keep things selfishly to yourselves. You want to help others learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the fact that you are women can get in the way for others. It’s their problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, however, carry on with dignity. You don’t pretend that words don’t hurt, or that you don’t feel emotional. There’s no dishonesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you set an outstanding example to the rest of us. That we can, and should, try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst you should never bear the responsibility of my admiration, please be aware that I will always be grateful that you were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laura x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-1805&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/01/29-heart@2x.png&#34; alt=&#34;heart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-comments&#34;&gt;10 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-442&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e95fc0d78290a8d2e27a419af5c85233?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e95fc0d78290a8d2e27a419af5c85233?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Sadaf Chohan&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-442&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T13:29:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:29pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Dear Laura

I appreciate your this post, as well as your postings &amp;#8230; though am a developer but i always remained inspired by you since i came across your blog &amp;#8230; your posts not only helps regarding field things but it motivates me in terms of working hard .. stay fit &amp;#8230; going on daily walks &amp;#8230; working properly in professional ways and i also appreciate being such a busy lady you replied my emails and help in possible way u can by your suggestions &amp;#8230; Thankx for being an inspiration .. stay blessed

Regards&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-443&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/72933f8d340100f493cfac7ca699cc62?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/72933f8d340100f493cfac7ca699cc62?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://robinwinslow.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Robin Winslow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-443&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T13:45:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Bravo.

I love your blog design by the way. Very bold.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-444&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f09e13b2647166e6d0c5bd4722b0ba71?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f09e13b2647166e6d0c5bd4722b0ba71?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;dtgreen&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-444&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T14:26:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:26pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I think you’ll find that you’ll have others writing web loveletters to you in the future, as you’re clearly on the road to becoming a bit of an inspiration yourself! ;)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-445&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-445&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T15:13:40+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:13pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I find it interesting that you find more kinship with women in this supposedly gender neutral age. Is that to do with women sticking together in a male dominated industry, or is it perhaps a reflection of differences between how men and women view gender? I ask because, as a man, I feel no particular kinship towards other men over women, nor do I find them more supportive or inspiring. Perhaps women are just more awesome?

For what it’s worth, I consider you a source of inspiration.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-446&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-446&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T16:02:07+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:02pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thank you, you lot :)

@Mark It’s not that I find more kinship with women, I just find them particularly inspiring in this way. That’s why I tried to emphasise at the beginning that they certainly aren’t my only inspiration. And why I mentioned that those who support these people are equally included.

There are so many people I love and respect, and I’m sure that most of them are men, because there are just so many more men in the industry. It’s this difficulty of being one type of minority that makes it so easy to feel slighted or disheartened, and those who get past that are often under-appreciated or suffer extra scrutiny for their trouble. It’s also so important to for these groups of people to have people they can look up to and take assurance from. Of course, they don’t have to be the same minority, but sometimes it just helps.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-447&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-447&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T17:45:25+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thank you for taking the trouble to reply Laura, much appreciated. As a young, white male of average height, weight and build, I realise I don’t have any idea of what it is like to be in a minority of any kind, especially not in this industry. Whilst there are some people who go out of their way to victimise or over scrutinise minorities, I think most people in the majority either do it accidentally or are completely unaware that it is happening. Whilst it’s great that you can find people to support and inspire you, I wonder if you have any thoughts on how to improve the situation for/awareness of minorities? Most of us believe strongly in equality and diversity of all kinds and see the benefits of it every day, but perhaps there is more we can do to ensure it happens, or at least get out of the way if we are stopping it?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-448&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/50a2b24590a36e2ca9404a4c03bbe233?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/50a2b24590a36e2ca9404a4c03bbe233?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://truthfully.ca&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;shannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-448&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T21:16:22+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:16pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post, Laura. You’re lovely. 

@Mark, being aware of your privilege is one way. For instance, as a white male, you have the highest privilege. In Laura’s particular industry (not to mention everywhere else), women fight to receive the same amount of respect and credibility that is handed to you. Perhaps some of her kinship with women is due that common experience, knowing that a successful woman’s journey looks very different from a man’s. 

Acknowledge that you have privilege, know what it is, stop to consider it, point it out to others, and be an ally. Those are all great places to start.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-4&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-451&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://markglover.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-451&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-17T10:35:11+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:35am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great point @Shannon (and apologies for taking so long to reply). It is a privilege to be in my position, and I try never to forget that. Being from the younger generation and having been brought up to believe that everyone is equal, it still shocks me to see that women aren’t treated with the same respect and given the same opportunities as men, when it seems completely absurd to act as though they aren’t as capable. I know that men and women often have different skill sets and outlooks, but I’ve always taken this to be a strength, not a weakness, as the differences seem to complement each other well. I work with a number of women in the tech industry, and I admire their skills and dedication just as much as the men I work with. I’m not naturally inclined to admire women more, simply for being women, as I’ve always thought the gender distinction to be completely unnecessary, but perhaps I will do in the future, given what I’m reading here about how much harder women are having to work for the respect that they deserve. Every day I meet people who are technologically literate and those that aren’t, but I’ve never seen a correlation between ability and gender. It just doesn’t exist.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-450&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/72933f8d340100f493cfac7ca699cc62?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/72933f8d340100f493cfac7ca699cc62?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://robinwinslow.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Robin Winslow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-450&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-16T11:56:03+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:56am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        There is been a lot of discussion about this recently. This is a particularly good post: [http://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-false-dichotomies-and-diversity/](http://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-false-dichotomies-and-diversity/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow). It’s not about people intentionally being discriminative (although there is way too much online bullying/harassment) it’s more about systemic bias and a lack of acknowledgement or a concerted effort to subvert it.

Regarding efforts to subvert it, this is a great resource: [http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/FLOSS#How_to_encourage_women_in_FLOSS](http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/FLOSS#How_to_encourage_women_in_FLOSS&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-449&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6558e7f01eb5667da77bdd3f9fbd38e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d6558e7f01eb5667da77bdd3f9fbd38e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kodsmuts.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ida&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-449&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-15T22:53:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:53pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        That’s a great letter. Thank you!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
