<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 12:44:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bereaved</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bereaved/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bereaved/</guid>
      <description>Last night I had a dream, or maybe a nightmare. I was in a ballet class in a church hall, learning all kinds of complicated and not-really-ballet dance sequences. The class was busy, we were all in clumsy rows. We were a diverse group of dancers in our everyday clothes. It was the same church hall I did most of my ballet classes in when I was younger, with lots of wood panelling, and stacked plastic chairs in place of a barre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 21st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a busy few weeks.
Ethical Design Manifesto refresh Last week we launched a refresh of the Ethical Design Manifesto, along with a video. As it was a short-ish video, I felt like I had no excuse but to do the captioning for it too. I couldn’t get Subtitle Horse (my usual favourite web software) working with the video, so I ended up using Jubler instead.
It took a while to get my head around how to use the interface, but I found using the audio track from the video very useful, as I could sync the subtitles to the wave forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 1st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 10:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Well… we’re here! In Malmö, sitting in our new office at Media Evolution City.
It’s been a busy and exhausting week. Oskar and I made our 800 mile trip in one day, thanks to the wonderful “courier” and took another day to recover. Then it was straight into the office.
The last week has been meeting new friends, relocation admin, and arranging a few events for the year. All the while Aral has been coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 16th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>It’s nearly time! We’re moving to Sweden next Tuesday, and it’s currently at equal parts exciting and stressful.
The storage locker in Brighton is almost empty, and we’ve stashed all our sentimental stuff—the things you want to keep, but probably aren’t worth putting in a suitcase to a foreign land—at my family’s house. We’re only taking a couple of suitcases of clothes, our work equipment, and of course Oskar. If we can squeeze Aral’s fancy Anglepoise lamp and a few nice bits of artwork into the pet transportation van, then we’ll have those along too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 5th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</guid>
      <description>Note: I’ve been writing diary entries on the Ind.ie forum for a while now. I’ve decided to start sharing these on my site now too, as I’ve not been posting much else! (They have bonus dog photos.)
I’ve been meaning to write a diary entry for ages, and 8am on a Friday morning is the first opportunity I’ve had to get to it (and I’ve already been working for an hour…)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Furniture (and other nice things) for sale</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/</guid>
      <description>So we’re finally moving to Sweden at the end of the month. You might remember that we sold a lot of our stuff last summer when we left Brighton. We kept a lot of good stuff, thinking we’d relocate it with us.
But now we’re moving to a small apartment in Malmö, and a beautiful furnished office in Media Evolution City, so we are only taking the essentials. (Yes, that includes Oskar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Bundles for Sale</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</guid>
      <description>3rd July: NEW BOOKS ADDED!
We’re moving. And because we’re moving abroad, we’re getting rid of all of our stuff.
Just take me to the books already
Aral and I have a lot of books between us. We’re sad to lose them. Many have been gifts from friends, written by people we know, and helped us do what we do.
Selling books one by one is a time-consuming (and not cost-effective) exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Sale: Mid 2013 MacBook Air</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/for-sale-mid-2013-macbook-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 16:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/for-sale-mid-2013-macbook-air/</guid>
      <description>In October, I found myself doing a lot more in Terminal than I’d done before, and I needed a computer with a faster processor, so I upgraded to a MacBook Pro. This means that my pimped-out Mid 2013 MacBook Air that I bought in December 2013 is now for sale. It’s in nearly-new condition, as it’s been kept in a shell case for almost all its (short) life. I used it for around 8 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 97: Made in Scotland from girders</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-97-made-in-scotland-from-girders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 14:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-97-made-in-scotland-from-girders/</guid>
      <description>This week’s episode of Unfinished Business was great fun to record. Both Ashley Baxter and I were Andy’s guests, and we talked about unhealthy food, being a podcast guest, Christmas decorations, and everything that’s in store for the three of us over the next year.
[  ](http://unfinished.bz/97)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 89: Burger in donut</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-89-burger-in-a-donut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 11:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-89-burger-in-a-donut/</guid>
      <description>Last week’s episode of Unfinished Business was a very different discussion from the usual. Andy and I talked about his fantastic idea for Geek Mental Help week (October 27th onwards) and how so many people in our industry are affected by mental health issues. I’ll definitely be writing a post for Geek Mental Help Week, and I hope you will too! I’m sure you’ll be able to find out the latest about Geek Mental Help Week from the Twitter account @geekmentalhelp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons why you should get an office dog</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</guid>
      <description>Last week I wrote my Pastry Box thought on 5 reasons why you should get an office dog. It’s not just silly photos of Oskar, but actually five reasons why having Oskar for company has helped keep me sane. Through living and working by myself, to living and working with other people, he’s still incredibly valuable as a companion.
And if you do happen to like dog photos, you might want to follow @gigapup on Twitter or app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give and Tell Challenge</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</guid>
      <description>When Andy Clarke challenged me to the “Give and Tell Challenge”, I was very happy to comply. Dan James, inspired by the ALS Ice Bucket Challenge, came up with the challenge:
 You donate to a cause, or causes, that have meaning to you and you say why. You then challenge 3 other people to do the same thing.
 All Out I have just donated to All Out. All Out campaigns for a world where no person will have to sacrifice their family or freedom, safety or dignity, because of who they are or who they love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplaces of Web Professionals</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 07:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</guid>
      <description>This morning Martin Wolf published an interesting blog post with photos of the “workplaces of web professionals”. I always wonder if people really are that tidy, or if they spent a while clearing up before they took the photo.
The featured photo of my workplace (in our ind.ie home office) shows the fairly typical mess on my desk, and the very typical dog getting in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desert.fm Playlist</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/desert-fm-playlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 09:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/desert-fm-playlist/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I was asked to create a playlist of ten songs for Desert.fm. Nate, Bobby and Jamie sent me an email with the premise:
 Our idea is to to add value to digital playlists through personal stories and inspirational music. We’re totally genre agnostic and we don’t judge (honest!), we can find inspiration in the most unlikely of places sometimes, so we encourage our curators not to hold back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time, my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April’s Pastry Box thought on writing</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 09:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I was slow to post aboutmy April Pastry Box post as my realign got in the way. It was really a little insecure thought about how my writing and thinking is improving, but I’m finding it hard.
[  ](https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-april-19)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I also pledge to be better</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 07:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</guid>
      <description>This post was inspired by Faruk’s great post “I Pledge To Be Better (And I Hope You Do Too)” where he speaks about the continuing problems with discrimination and lack of diversity in tech, and how more people should speak up about these issues. Faruk rightly says we all have the power and responsibility to make things better. I believe that when we don’t speak out about discrimination, we’re almost causing as much damage as condoning discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No more Red Bull</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/no-more-red-bull/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/no-more-red-bull/</guid>
      <description>Using a Fitbit over the last year and a half has taught me that making your habits more visible in public makes you more likely to work harder. When you’re giving up a bad habit, often there’s not much stopping us from slipping back into the bad habits. So I am writing here, on Tuesday 27th August 2013 that I am giving up Red Bull.
It sounds ridiculous, but I have a problem</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at Dare conference in September. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.
Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies In Tech</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, Jeremy Keith introduced me to ladiesintech.com, suggesting that it might be something that’d interest me. After having a chat with the lovely Jenn Lukas over email, I had a story that I wanted to share about my adventures in speaking, and Jenn has now helped me share it on the site.
This was the first time I’ve ever had anybody edit my writing. I’ve had other people proof-read and check my writing for mistakes, but never changing that much (despite often needing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 20:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</guid>
      <description>Burnout. Spending hours just staring into space when you’re supposed to be doing work, when you want to be doing work. Feeling foggy-headed and grey the whole time when you usually feel eager and excitable. Menial tasks are just about manageable, but anything requiring careful consideration or creative thinking feels impossible. I sleep but I still feel tired.
I’m burned out. The last couple of months have really taken their toll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and conferences</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 21:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I used to not understand the fuss around women at conferences, I thought that we should all just carry on with what we were doing well already and not get caught up in needless controversy. I even wrote a blog post saying exactly that a couple of years ago. I’d never experienced (to my knowledge) any difficulties because I was a woman.
A bit uncomfortable But then I started hearing more about/was exposed to women who did have bad experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A loveletter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-loveletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 12:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-loveletter/</guid>
      <description>Note: I wrote this a while ago when I was thinking about the things that made me want to work on the web. Of course, it’s not exclusively women that inspire me, but as a girl who continually questions the value she is bringing to a project, I often find the women of the web had the greatest effect on my self assurance. I wrote this in my notebook in a fit of fury&amp;nbsp;after witnessing some upsetting trolling towards a couple of women on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>