<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Bundles for Sale</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/book-bundles/</guid>
      <description>3rd July: NEW BOOKS ADDED!
We’re moving. And because we’re moving abroad, we’re getting rid of all of our stuff.
Just take me to the books already
Aral and I have a lot of books between us. We’re sad to lose them. Many have been gifts from friends, written by people we know, and helped us do what we do.
Selling books one by one is a time-consuming (and not cost-effective) exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 72: Big Bad Boy Breakfast Bap</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 16:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-72/</guid>
      <description>This week’s episode of Unfinished Business was great fun to record. After my recent move to working on Indie Phone, alongside my boyfriend Aral Balkan, I was curious to know how Andy and Sue have worked so well together since the beginning of Stuff and Nonsense.
I sent Sue some questions, which she answered and sent back to me, without Andy seeing the answers. During the show, I asked Andy about his thoughts and read Sue’s answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #64</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-64/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. It was a special episode as Rachel Andrew was also a guest (yeah, I designed her site!) I don’t like to go on about stuff like this too often, but if you’d told 21 year old me (7 years ago) that I’d be appearing on a podcast with Andy Clarke and Rachel Andrew, it would’ve blown my mind. They’re two very lovely people whose writing helped me learn about, and become so excited about, the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>