<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelancing on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/freelancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/freelancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’m doing now and why</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</guid>
      <description>I’d been a freelance web designer/developer full-time, working for myself, for six years. I love working with clients, and working with small businesses is a very sustainable business model. You can make a big difference to a small business. You can get paid fairly well. And you can forge long-term relationships with people whose businesses you really care about. I always said I’d never give it up, unless it was for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 83: Slightly sticky bottoms</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-83-slightly-sticky-bottoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 16:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-83-slightly-sticky-bottoms/</guid>
      <description>Andy is back this week and so we did a handover episode of Unfinished Business. This week we talked about our different approaches to the podcast and what’s relevant to “business”. Andy found an interesting article on the BBC website about smartphone stress, so we talked about how we handle disconnecting when we go on holiday, and in our downtime at home.
[  ](http://unfinished.bz/83)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 81 and 82</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 18:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</guid>
      <description>I was so busy last week that I forgot to post about Unfinished Business episode 81: Do you have a dinosaur onesie? This week, Ashley and I recorded episode 82: Love a good pep talk.
It’s been a fun few weeks. It’s been interesting how a lot of people have said that Ashley and I focused more on business-related topics than Andy’s recent episodes. That may well be the case, but it wasn’t really intentional, or because we think the podcast should be more business-focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 80: I wonder why he trusts us?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 09:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-80/</guid>
      <description>Andy Clarke is on holiday for three weeks and has handed over the Unfinished Business reins to Ashley Baxter and I. This week’s episode is all about business insurance for freelancers and small businesses. We talked about public liability, professional indemnity, business contents and copyright infringement. It was great because I got to ask Ashley loads of questions I forgot to ask when she was helping me get insured!
I’m not sure if the audio quality is as good as it usually is on Unfinished Business, as my editing skills are rather rusty… But this episode does feature a little bit of Oskar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 12 Devs of Winter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at 12 Devs of Winter on the 22nd January in Shoreditch. Because I’ve clearly lost my mind, I’m going to be doing another new talk. This time on ‘Freelancing for the reluctant businessperson.’ I’m that reluctant businessperson, and I’m hoping to share some silly stories about all the daft things I’ve done and some of the things that have worked out just fine.
For once, I’m ahead of the schedule, and tickets will be released this Wednesday 8th January at 10am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #44</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 18:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was on Unfinished Business again! Andy and I talked about hosting workshops, business names and how to make a good impression via email. My audio is pretty awful, and I’m sorry for that. I tried to be all clever with my headset, but ended up sounding very small and faraway…
I’m also going to be on Unfinished Business more regularly. I always have fun chatting to Andy, and it’s a great excuse to pick his more experienced brains about business stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including “ask me anything” in my contract</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</guid>
      <description>At Dare conference in September, I saw a great talk by Kevin Hoffman on “How To Rebuild Amidst Crisis.” I loved this talk, there was so much in it, but one thing struck me as something I could carry over into my work: Kevin said he included “ask any question and I’ll answer it” in his contract.
This might seem like stating the obvious at first, but really there’s nothing obvious to a client who is new to you, and your process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest co-host on Unfinished Business again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.
I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!
 
Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage One of the sponsors this week was Slide + Stage, a full-day intensive masterclass with Aral Balkan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project  It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)
Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was guest co-host on one of my most favourite podcasts, Unfinished Business. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.
We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 20:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</guid>
      <description>Burnout. Spending hours just staring into space when you’re supposed to be doing work, when you want to be doing work. Feeling foggy-headed and grey the whole time when you usually feel eager and excitable. Menial tasks are just about manageable, but anything requiring careful consideration or creative thinking feels impossible. I sleep but I still feel tired.
I’m burned out. The last couple of months have really taken their toll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people  In the previous posts, I mentioned that I was going to explain the details of the project later on. This was because I didn’t want to get bogged down by the details of the brief while I was focusing on finding the right team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>I know, this is a funny topic on which to base a blog post but I love the Unfinished Business podcast, and I’d like to elaborate why in something more than a few fawning tweets.
Business, but not suits Business doesn’t feel like the right word to describe what I do. It’s a hobby that makes me enough money to support myself. The word ‘business’ conjures up images of suits, handshakes and networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Wing podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 09:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was a guest on Tim Smith‘s The East Wing podcast. It was a pre-recorded conversation and it was great fun. You can listen to it on the East Wing website, and it’ll be up on iTunes soon.
We discussed how I got started in the industry (really sorry traditional Graphic Design people, I may have generalised a bit…), speaking at conferences, women in the industry and mentoring.
As I said last night on Twitter, Tim Smith is such a great guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, a potential project turned up in my inbox. An old school friend wants a website, needs it soon and doesn’t have a huge budget.
Me and freelancing I’m lucky, I get offered a lot of projects, and usually I don’t have any availability for a few months. Little projects like this generally can’t pay the bills for me. It’s a lot of time (particularly admin) for a fairly small return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Tour Brighton</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Insites is a mini tour of four cities in the UK where Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks present discussions with well-known people from the web/tech industry. I was lucky enough to go to the first evening in Brighton on Monday where Aral Balkan, Sarah Parmenter and Jeremy Keith were the guests.
The Format The format of the evening was something unfamiliar to most of us. Each guest was interviewed by either Keir or Elliot and then there were questions from the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
