<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Honesty on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/honesty/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/honesty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>The lovely people at Dare conference have released the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”
I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that there’s loads of great talks on there, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at Dare conference in September. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.
Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bardowl: The Big One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I’ve been working with a great team of people on our iPhone app, Bardowl, an app for streaming unlimited audiobooks for £9.99 a month (think Spotify but for audiobooks.)
It’s not been a quick and easy. Getting publishers to come round to the idea, and securing good audiobooks, has been a lengthy process but we’ve been lucky to have people who really know what they’re talking about behind the scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Xmas Special—Integrity and Polarity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 08:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was Insites: The Xmas Special, a brilliant event put on by the lovely Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks. After being well fed, everybody in the room gave a six minute(ish) talk about something they’ve learned in 2012.
It was a personal, open and incredibly meaningful set of talks. There were no slides, and nobody in the room was sat behind a laptop or Twitter. The conversations that ensued afterwards were greater than anything you’d get at any big conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
