<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Honesty on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/honesty/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/honesty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lovely people at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com&#34;&gt;Dare conference&lt;/a&gt; have released &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos/kalbag&#34;&gt;the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty&lt;/a&gt;. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/open-for-business&#34;&gt;my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos&#34; title=&#34;Dare conference videos&#34;&gt;there’s loads of great talks on there&lt;/a&gt;, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations. If you enjoy any of the videos, &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos#donate&#34; title=&#34;Donate to Dare conference&#34;&gt;please donate&lt;/a&gt;. Dare didn’t make any money this this, but it was a phenomenal, heartwarming and groundbreaking event. I can’t wait for next year’s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos/kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4087&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/10/dare-conf-video.png&#34; alt=&#34;My Secret Is Honesty - Video of Laura Kalbag at Dare conference&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/&#34; title=&#34;Speaking at Dare conference&#34;&gt;speaking at Dare conference&lt;/a&gt; this September, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lucidplot.com/2013/08/05/kalbag-podcast/&#34;&gt;I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn&lt;/a&gt;, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his &lt;a href=&#34;http://lucidplot.com/2013/08/05/kalbag-podcast/&#34;&gt;podcast also has a proper transcript&lt;/a&gt; if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lucidplot.com/2013/08/05/kalbag-podcast/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3989&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/08/lucid-plot-podcast.png&#34; alt=&#34;lucid plot - Jonathan Kahn&amp;#39;s blog about changing culture through digital work&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;Dare conference in September&lt;/a&gt;. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business. I was only just becoming aware of what I was doing, and writing a talk was a good way for me to dig a little bit deeper. So I wrote a proposal and my proposal was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk has a slightly cheesy name, “My secret is honesty” but I promise you, the content is real. I’ve already tested it on a lovely group of people in Porto, Portugal, and hope to have a shortened version ready in September. It’s a very different topic for me, I usually talk about web design and development, but I think it’s the right place for an open talk about openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3849&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/07/dare-conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dare conference 2013&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bardowl: The Big One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For the last few years, I’ve been working with a great team of people on &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/bardowl/id492667930?ls=1&amp;amp;amp;mt=8&#34;&gt;our iPhone app&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bardowl.com&#34;&gt;Bardowl&lt;/a&gt;, an app for streaming unlimited audiobooks for £9.99 a month (think Spotify but for audiobooks.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not been a quick and easy. Getting publishers to come round to the idea, and securing good audiobooks, has been a lengthy process but we’ve been lucky to have people who really know what they’re talking about behind the scenes. Our &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bookmeister&#34;&gt;CEO, Chris Book&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/neilp33l&#34;&gt;CTO, Neil Chapman&lt;/a&gt;, have bootstrapped the business and have worked incredibly hard, taking a big risk, because they really believe in bringing good audiobooks to the iPhone without massive subscription costs or limited listening choices. They’re the reason I was first interested in being involved, and the reason I’ve stuck at it for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-only-blog-about-it-now&#34;&gt;Why only blog about it now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to wait until there was a version of the app that you’d want to try. Previously, we launched with ‘business books.’ These are wonderful if you’re into management techniques, deals, finances and all these audiobooks that I find, quite honestly, dull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;now-the-catalogue-has-got-so-much-awesome&#34;&gt;Now the catalogue has got so much awesome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, the catalogue has some serious awesome with biographies and memoirs, childrens books, classic, contemporary and modern fiction, non-fiction, poetry and drama. Roald Dahl’s Revolting Rhymes, Cormac McCarthy’s No Country For Old Men, loads of Dickens and Sherlock Holmes. I really think you’ll like it. Oh yes, and you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/bardowl/id492667930?ls=1&amp;amp;amp;mt=8&#34;&gt;try it for free for 7 days&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-have-i-done-then&#34;&gt;What have I done then?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am the sole designer. I do all the design; branding, app design and web design/development. It’s really the first product I’ve ever worked with, and I enjoy having something I get to stick with and iterate over time. I’m still not sure if I’d want to do this full time, I really love the variety that comes with client work, but it’s very rewarding feeling like you’re constantly improving one product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;working-for-almost-free&#34;&gt;Working for almost-free&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also work almost solely for a small share (I’ve had a few payments for work when we had some investment.) Since I started time-tracking the project in March 2010, I’ve put 430 hours into the project, around half of that being on the website, which has had three or four full redesigns. This working for almost-free is definitely not something I would do again, which I will elaborate on below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a complete learning experience. It was my first app design work, I created the logo long before I started working professionally as a designer, and I’ve never worked as part of a startup before, in fact I’ve never really worked as part of another company before (as a designer.) Starting before I graduated from university, it’s been a project that has spanned the whole of my freelance/professional career. As I’ve learned new things, I’ve been able to experiment, and put my new knowledge straight into the app and the website. It was my first mobile website design (pre-“Responsive Web Design”,) my first foray into web fonts, my first “Responsive Web Design” and my first experience with CSS pre-processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;designing-and-developing&#34;&gt;Designing and developing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned a huge amount about designing for apps. Unlike designing for the web, where I usually write the markup and sometimes the code, I can’t develop iOS apps. I don’t think this is a good thing, it really emphasises why I think that you must be able to write markup in order to design for the web. Designing for iOS apps, with fairly minimal knowledge of the development process is &lt;em&gt;really hard&lt;/em&gt;. I make a complete pain out of myself, constantly asking &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/kgutteridge&#34;&gt;Kieran&lt;/a&gt; questions about how things work, what’s possible, what’s native, and what would be easiest to create from a development point-of-view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve learned loads from Kieran, I still want to know more about the development process. In the new year, I’ve resolved to attend &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/aral&#34;&gt;Aral Balkan&lt;/a&gt;‘s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moderniosdevelopment.com/&#34;&gt;Modern iOS Development Workshop&lt;/a&gt; (I’ve heard so many good things.) But I don’t really see myself developing apps for a living, I find programming very difficult and not terribly rewarding, I just think my design decisions can be more well-informed as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;designing-for-free&#34;&gt;Designing for free&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above I said I wouldn’t work for free (shares) again. As a general rule, I wouldn’t recommend it, it’s a huge risk and chances are you’ll never make a return on the hours you put into the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my specific reason I wouldn’t work for free is that I believe people can often struggle to understand and appreciate the value in design if they’re not paying for it. They’ve not got an interest in getting the best value for money, so they don’t necessarily feel as though they should listen to what you say. In a way, the developer will always have the final say, as whatever they make is what gets released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’ve worked for free, and you’ve put so much time and effort into a project, you’re less likely to leave. The more time you spend, the more reluctant you’ll be to leave that all behind. It’s like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome&#34;&gt;Stockholm Syndrome&lt;/a&gt; of working for free. I still completely believe in Bardowl as a concept, and I have a huge amount of respect and love for our CEO and CTO, and that’s why I persist in trying to make my app design live up to the idea, but I’d be lying if I said I didn’t have frustrated times where a loss of control and startup politics infuriated me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;working-with-good-people&#34;&gt;Working with good people&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the occasional hiccups, I’ve found working with Bardowl immensely rewarding. There’s so much to be said about working for people who really believe and care about what they’re doing. It’s not just about doing design and development right, or business right, but about working with people right. Our CEO Chris Book is an example of somebody who cares about the people he works with. His role as CEO has often mean placating, convincing and cajoling, but he doesn’t just do this as a means to getting his app finished, he genuinely believes in providing value for those working on the project. And doing it all with honesty and transparency. Honesty and transparency are massively underrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-417&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c51f7b5294f5c364096920ae63f267dc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c51f7b5294f5c364096920ae63f267dc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Russ&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-417&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T22:18:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:18pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great, open and honest post, I can sympathise with some of the long hours/low rewards just because you either love what you are building, or love the learning process of doing it :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-418&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6ab9b89687df7f10f51a01997304f4fe?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6ab9b89687df7f10f51a01997304f4fe?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://olar.se&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ola Ringdahl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-418&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-07T14:03:07+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:03pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hi!

I´m Ola, a swedish male voicetalent who loves audiobooks. I have looked at Bardowl and it seems great but there is one questionmark: why aren´t the books listed on the website?

There is a swedish company with exactly the same concept called Storytel.se, and the show all of their books and you can also manage your books on the site which is really handy.

Best

Ola&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Xmas Special—Integrity and Polarity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 08:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was &lt;a href=&#34;http://viewportindustries.com/events/insites-the-xmas-special/&#34;&gt;Insites: The Xmas Special&lt;/a&gt;, a brilliant event put on by the lovely &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/keirwhitaker&#34;&gt;Keir Whitaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/elliotjaystocks&#34;&gt;Elliot Jay Stocks&lt;/a&gt;. After being well fed, everybody in the room gave a six minute(ish) talk about something they’ve learned in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a personal, open and incredibly meaningful set of talks. There were no slides, and nobody in the room was sat behind a laptop or Twitter. The conversations that ensued afterwards were greater than anything you’d get at any big conference. We had all shared our experiences equally and honestly. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/rachelandrew&#34;&gt;Rachel Andrew&lt;/a&gt; put so well, it was almost group therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the rules of the day was that what happened in the School Of Life stayed in the School Of Life, so far be it for me to report the personal stories of other people. However, I’m happy to share what I spoke about, so I thought I’d share it here…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-picking-sides&#34;&gt;Not picking sides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m the eldest of five children in my family. It’s a big family and none of us are shy. However, I’m usually referred to as the “sensible one” or the “calm one”. I’m all about diplomacy and trying to keep the peace if there’s any upset or argyments. It’s not that I’m afraid of conflict, I think arguments can be healthy and constructive, but I really don’t like picking sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet for so many years I didn’t take this approach when I was working on the web. CSS layouts were good, tables were bad. Semantic web was good, Flash was bad. To me, these were facts and exceptions were begrudgingly accepted as freak edge-cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there’s so much to learn on the web, it’s much easier to follow than to lead, or even just make up your own mind. As humans we seem to be drawn to polarity; picking sides. Which football team do you support? Which political party are you aligned to? Which religion do you believe in? But it’s such an unhelpful way to live. Polarity lacks subtlety, it leads to blind acceptance of everything you’re told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think about it in terms of politics, you feel forced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toe_the_line&#34;&gt;toe the party line&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of politics is damaging in itself; if everyone in a group is made to believe exactly the same thing, unquestioningly, it’s very hard to accept any new ideas or change your mind. You can’t back-track. And because you feel as though you must “stick to your side”, you blindly defend you side’s beliefs at a risk to your own integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;integrity&#34;&gt;Integrity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrity is something that has always meant a lot to me. But I feel like sometimes I’ve been guilty of risking my own integrity in order to fit in. It’s hard to go against the group, nobody wants to feel like an outsider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But life’s too short to do things that don’t make you feel proud. Of course we all do &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; projects that are good for cashflow or good for your profile, and hopefully these don’t run completely contrary to your personal beliefs, but even if we can own a tiny little part of these projects; do something good and something that we’re proud of, we can make that project worthwhile in terms of our integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to continually question what we’re doing and why we bother. I think I’m right in saying that most of what we do isn’t just “a job.” We do this because we care and we want to make better experiences for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-407&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7c77bb634e33febe9e2e9a2745732ca3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7c77bb634e33febe9e2e9a2745732ca3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/danblundell&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dan Blundell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-407&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-04T09:25:28+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:25am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        “We need to continually question what we’re doing and why we bother. I think I’m right in saying that most of what we do isn’t just “a job.” We do this because we care and we want to make better experiences for everyone.” –; This just nailed exactly why I’m feeling the way I am at the minute, good to know that there’s others that feel the same way! 

It can be really difficult when you’re surrounded by people that consider a job simply a job but I whole heartedly agree, if you can do even one tiny thing that you’re proud of, even in the toughest of projects, you can stay happy because our work means something.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
