<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 17:38:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 11 –; Overlay</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-11-overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 17:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-11-overlay/</guid>
      <description>A weird experiment that almost works…
  **Sleeping in Spring.** Mucking about with overlaying a couple of photos. It’s a bit more editing than multiple exposures, but a similar style. I was just flicking through the layer blending modes and found something that looked a bit different. Here I’ve layered a couple of blending modes and erased some areas to bring Oskar’s face out</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 10 –; Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-10-miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 11:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-10-miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>The last few days have brought a very miscellaneous collection of photos.
  **Rama on the beach.** I was out trying to get the sea and the pier, but the weather was grim, and I found this little figure instead. I think it might be Rama, but I might be wrong…   
The next photo is part of our overlaying exercise set by Ashley. I did it in post-processing, before I discovered that my camera has a multiple exposure setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 9 –; Oskar in the grey</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-9-oskar-in-the-grey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-9-oskar-in-the-grey/</guid>
      <description>This week we’ve been looking more at natural light, and portraits with foreground detail. I took my trusty (actually incredibly unreliable) model, Oskar, out for a walk and hounded him with the camera. It was a very grey day, but with a lot of light.
  **Oskar in the cow parsley.** It’s much easier to get a shot in focus when the model is sitting still! I’m pleased with the depth from the different layers of cow parsley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 8 –; Traffic and Jess</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-8-traffic-and-jess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 08:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-8-traffic-and-jess/</guid>
      <description>Our most recent exercise was to take a long exposure shot.
  **Seafront traffic.** I wandered around for a while, trying to find a good angle from a height, but the traffic was too quiet! The main sea front road was much better, though it was pretty windy last night, so it’s slightly blurrier that I’d like on the static objects.   
Before that, Ashley gave us a great tutorial on using natural light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 7 –; Small Cat</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-7-small-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 16:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-7-small-cat/</guid>
      <description>My parents’ cat, called Milly. Who I call “Small Cat” because she’s so small.
  **Small Cat.** I edited out the wonky lamp in the background because it was distracting. I also muted the grass and plants so her scary green eyes would be more noticeable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 6 –; Walk</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-6-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-6-walk/</guid>
      <description>When I started doing this course, I knew I’d probably end up with a lot of dog walking photos. Oskar and I are out every day, and so there’s lots of photo opportunities.
After exploring the self-timer in my last photo, I thought I’d try it again. Dog photos are obviously great, but I wanted something to show how we exist as a pair. Also outdoors.
  **East Brighton rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 5 –; Levitation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-5-levitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 17:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-5-levitation/</guid>
      <description>Another photo post so soon? Yes! It’s the weekend, and Ashley gave us a really cool new exercise to try levitation, so I thought I had to try it.
  **Levitation.** This took SO MANY tries. The light changed while I was setting up, so it was a bit tricky to edit the two originals together. I tried to crop out the most distracting elements of the shot, and desaturate the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 4 –; Post-processing</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-4-post-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 07:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-4-post-processing/</guid>
      <description>On my last day in Berlin, I took a lot more photos. Last night I started post-processing them, following Ashley’s email and video tutorials. Post-processing is an area where I have more experience, I’ve done a lot of Photoshopping in the past, but now I’m trying to achieve new effects using Lightroom, which is a very different animal!
  **Me in a hotel room, original.** Travelling in Berlin, and being a bit slow to set up shots, I found my only (mostly) willing model was me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 3 –; Day One at re:publica</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-3-republica-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 14:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-3-republica-day-one/</guid>
      <description>This week, the Ind.ie team are at re:publica in Berlin, so I’m getting lots of opportunities to take photos that aren’t just of the dog!
  re:publica in Berlin   
  **Projection.** A very abstract photo.   
  **STG-1 (Stage 1) at re:publica.** A fairly dark location, lit very strongly at one end. I managed to get a blurry walking man against it all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 2 –; Splash</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-splash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 19:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-splash/</guid>
      <description>The first exercise we’ve been given is to capture a splash in a cup…
  **First splash.** My kitchen is in a basement, so it’s a little bit dark. Even with the ISO jacked all the way up, this was the lightest I could get with the fastest possible shutter speed.   
  **Second splash.** So I went outside! Unfortunately my burst caught the splash a bit late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography on manual: 1</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 12:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/photography-on-manual-1/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a DSLR for nearly a year now. And I still only ever use it on the Auto modes. I studied photography (with film cameras) during my Art Foundation course ~10 years ago, but I think any decent photos were mostly luck, and I can’t remember much of it. So when Ashley set up her Girl With A Camera Course, “For the beginner photographer who wants to pick up their camera more,” I was instantly sold!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Stuff on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week my latest column, Breaking Stuff, was published on A List Apart. I’m in a strange transitional period, moving from client work to fulltime at ind.ie, so I think I’ll be writing more about situations like these as time goes on.
I’ve also finally updated that terrible avatar to something much better. I look uncharacteristically pale, but at least I’m normal colours! (Unlike the last terrible photo I’d used.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Last week my column on Inspiration was published on A List Apart. It follows roughly the same structure as the talk I gave at Design + Banter a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry mentoring on Creative Bloq</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/industry-mentoring-on-creative-bloq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 14:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/industry-mentoring-on-creative-bloq/</guid>
      <description>Craig Grannell has written a fantastic article on Creative Bloq about mentoring, looking at loads of different ways the web industry can do mentoring well. Including interviews with Clare Sutcliffe, Greg Hoy, Jeffery Zeldman, Andy Budd, Josh Emerson, Andy Budd, Anna Debenham and me!
It’s well-worth a read if you want to mentor somebody, or would like to find a mentor yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web, a workshop</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a slightly scary thing: I’m doing my first solo workshop on the 11th October 2013 in Barnsley.
I often get asked about the best way to “learn design”, and I usually say that you learn by doing and you learn by watching how others do it. In this workshop, I want to give new designers, developers, and anybody else wanting to learn how to design for the web, a good foundation with five primers, a bit of doing and a bit of watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass for designers — the talk and the case study</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I gave a talk at the fantastic online conference CSS Summit on ‘Sass for designers’. It uses my new site Web Talk Dog Walk as a case study, and explains the basics of Sass and how to get started using CodeKit.
Usually I wouldn’t recommend checking out my slides, as they’re useless without me explaining them, but as this was an online conference and I wanted the slides to be extra clear in case of technical problems, they hopefully read in a fairly easy-to-follow way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring Q and A on .net magazine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</guid>
      <description>After finishing the mentoring project last week, I had a chat with Craig Grannell about mentoring which he published on the .net website: “Laura Kalbag: web designers should mentor newcomers.”
It’s a good summary of the mentoring project and has extracts from a couple of testimonials by Sibylle and Phil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project  It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)
Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to speak</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year ago, I was in a country I’d never visited, about to give two talks I’d never given before to two large, paying audiences in the space of three days at Future Insights Live. I had only given a couple of talks to small audiences before. It was one of the scariest things I’d ever done.
A helping hand I’d seen Aral Balkan speak a few times before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people  In the previous posts, I mentioned that I was going to explain the details of the project later on. This was because I didn’t want to get bogged down by the details of the brief while I was focusing on finding the right team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing to display podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a lovely chat with El for her Nothing To Display podcast. We talked about technology and how people get started with technology, accessibility, mentoring and dystopian futures! It was a real treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: finding the right people</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 10:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>We’ve got a project! I’ll elaborate on the details of the project in a future post, but the importance of having a project was that it’s allowed me to choose the designers/developers who could get something out of being mentees. I didn’t want to do this before securing the right project as I needed to know what I was looking for in a mentee.
Finding the right mentee for the job This has been one of the hardest decisions I’ve ever had to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the right project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</guid>
      <description>This post is an update on my mentoring project idea.
Finding the right project If you follow me on Twitter, you might have seen that I’m now looking for a different project to work on. Whilst the previous project I had in mind would have been great fun, the client had a very tight deadline. I didn’t want to push that pressure on to students and freelancers who are likely to have other work they need to do in order to pass their studies or pay the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, a potential project turned up in my inbox. An old school friend wants a website, needs it soon and doesn’t have a huge budget.
Me and freelancing I’m lucky, I get offered a lot of projects, and usually I don’t have any availability for a few months. Little projects like this generally can’t pay the bills for me. It’s a lot of time (particularly admin) for a fairly small return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New To Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 15:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</guid>
      <description>Following my learning design post, I’ve started a little project called “new to design.” At the moment it just consists of a learn-design tag on my Pinboard bookmarks and a Twitter account @newtodesign so that I can share useful design resources (especially for those new to design.)
In the future, I hope it can be useful in other ways. Any suggestions or anything you want to see? You know how to get in touch…  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We read with our own contexts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 14:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</guid>
      <description>Oh Twitter. Yesterday was another day where I accidentally incited another riot with a poorly-worded tweet. Nobody is perfect, but it’s starting to happen with alarming frequency, and I wanted to understand why I keep doing this.
The ever-present ego We read everything through our own ego filter. It’s how we apply new knowledge to our own situations. Whenever we read a tweet, blog post, article, book, watch a TV show, a film, a play, we take in what we’re reading and hearing and apply it to ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bardowl: The Big One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I’ve been working with a great team of people on our iPhone app, Bardowl, an app for streaming unlimited audiobooks for £9.99 a month (think Spotify but for audiobooks.)
It’s not been a quick and easy. Getting publishers to come round to the idea, and securing good audiobooks, has been a lengthy process but we’ve been lucky to have people who really know what they’re talking about behind the scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CreativeJS for non-coders workshop with Seb Lee-Delisle</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/creativejs-for-non-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 13:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/creativejs-for-non-coders/</guid>
      <description>Programming block I’m a bit scared of JavaScript. Since I started learning front-end development about seven years ago, I’ve pretty much stayed away from it. That aside from some pretty dodgy jQuery where I can usually bodge something together but would never rely on it. I’ve always said it’s because I wanted to be really really good at HTML first, and then CSS and then JavaScript, but I somehow always stopped short of actually learning JavaScript properly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>