<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 11:34:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Interlink conference in Toronto</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 11:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 This is very very exciting. In June, I’m going to speak at Interlink conference in Toronto, Canada. The line-up is incredible, and I can’t believe I’m a part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 17:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2013/</guid>
      <description>My 2013 has been another big year. Oskar and I moved down to Brighton to live with Aral, I spoke at 13 events in 3 countries and worked with 13 clients on 20 projects. 2013 was the year of the podcast and I was a guest on 12 podcasts, most frequently with the lovely Andy Clarke on Unfinished Business. I also started writing a lot more, and now have my own column on A List Apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 23:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2012/</guid>
      <description>2012 has been a massive year for me. It was a year of saying yes to things that scared me. It was the first time I spoke at a conference (and I went on to speak at a further seven events.) I found the first house I’ve lived in by myself. I travelled to as many countries in one year as I had done in my whole life so far.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>