<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Milestones on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/milestones/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:45:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/milestones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 12:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2015/</guid>
      <description>I’m not even sure how to write about 2015… 2015 can die in a fire, go away and never come back.
My mother died in August, three months after her mother, my grandmother, died in April. Missing them both has really done me over. Grieving is not what I expected, it just makes everything exhausting. Oddly, knitting helped.
In July, we moved from Brighton to Reigate to stay with my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A realign for 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-realign-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 17:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-realign-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>Almost a year after last year’s realign, I’ve made some more tweaks to my site. There were a few reasons behind it:
 I’m not freelance anymore, so I don’t need the focus on my portfolio As I’m now working with Ind.ie, I needed to update my about page The navigation needed some accessibility work The colours were beginning to grate on me  Less portfolio, more… My blog has been fairly quiet, but actually that’s because I’ve been writing a lot elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 14:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2014/</guid>
      <description>Well, things didn’t slow down in 2014! So much so that I didn’t manage to write this post yesterday. In 2014 I spoke at 8 events in 4 countries, and worked with 11 clients on 15 projects before starting work full time with Ind.ie in August.
I wrote a lot more, with regular slots onA List Apart and The Pastry Box, and a series on Getting Started With Sass on Web Standards Sherpa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little realign</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-little-realign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 13:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-little-realign/</guid>
      <description>Things are looking a bit different around here. It’s not a redesign so much as a realign. I’ve been tinkering for a few months, and finally got to the point where I’m happy to push it live (even though there’s more I could do.)
There were a few particular goals for this redesign:
Rewrite the CSS I lived in fear that someone might look closely at my CSS. My last redesign came about when responsive web design was still young, and I was incredibly foolish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 17:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2013/</guid>
      <description>My 2013 has been another big year. Oskar and I moved down to Brighton to live with Aral, I spoke at 13 events in 3 countries and worked with 13 clients on 20 projects. 2013 was the year of the podcast and I was a guest on 12 podcasts, most frequently with the lovely Andy Clarke on Unfinished Business. I also started writing a lot more, and now have my own column on A List Apart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 23:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2012/</guid>
      <description>2012 has been a massive year for me. It was a year of saying yes to things that scared me. It was the first time I spoke at a conference (and I went on to speak at a further seven events.) I found the first house I’ve lived in by myself. I travelled to as many countries in one year as I had done in my whole life so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Really, a redesign? This can’t be real…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/really-a-redesign-this-cant-be-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 07:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/really-a-redesign-this-cant-be-real/</guid>
      <description>It’s about time… So finally I’ve redesigned my website. It’s been about three and a half years since the last version of laurakalbag.wpengine.com (still around at http://2009.laurakalbag.wpengine.com) and that’s a site I designed before I finished university, before I even started freelancing full time. To be fair, it took a while for me to hate it (not that usual kind of as-soon-as-it’s-launched-I-hate-it problem us designers often have) but that’s far too long for a portfolio site to be hanging around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a whole year since I officially started working as a freelance designer last August. I graduated from uni, had a brief fling with some full-time remote working, had an awkward interview with a recruiter and then decided that I’d rather give it a go by myself.
Getting Started I felt pretty ready for freelancing full-time, I’d had a lot of experience on projects whilst I was at university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promises</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/promises/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 12:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/promises/</guid>
      <description>Well, I’ve got a blog.
This is not a promise, but I will attempt to post some stuff focussing on quality over quantity. I’m thinking some of the more useful resources I come across; probably lots on WordPress, maybe a bit on mobile design, I’ve got a rant about HTML brewing somewhere too.
I apologise in advance for my embarrassing command of the English language and grammar.
I’m actively not going to bother designing it as nothing will ever happen if I do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
