<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelance on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #61</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. I had a lovely time chatting to Andy about speaking at conferences, working for free and I even managed to squeeze in a rant about accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#define 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</guid>
      <description>Next Saturday I’m speaking at #define 2013, a “diversity in computing festival” for 11-13 year old students who wouldn’t usually consider careers in computing.
It’s an event aimed at improving diversity in computing and I’m really proud to be speaking. I’m going to talk about a day in the life of a web designer/developer in the hope that I can share the variety involved in this kind of work and how rewarding and fun this job can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2011</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</guid>
      <description>Conferences are my social life As I go to more conferences, I meet more lovely people and get to see friends I’d only ever talk to on Twitter otherwise. In the last two years, I’ve been to about three a year and it feels about the right amount that you rarely see the same talk twice and it’s not just the same topics going round.
Again, I met loads of great people at New Adventures, but unfortunately missed more people than I meant to catch up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me vs We</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 10:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</guid>
      <description>There’s something that’s been niggling at me for ages. The way people act as if they’re a multi-person company when they’re really just one individual. This whole ‘we’ syndrome.
 We have a great new client now working with us at Just Little Old Me Ltd.
 Sometimes it makes me giggle when I know somebody is an individual ‘me’ and they’re saying ‘we’ as if they’re some kind of medieval queen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a whole year since I officially started working as a freelance designer last August. I graduated from uni, had a brief fling with some full-time remote working, had an awkward interview with a recruiter and then decided that I’d rather give it a go by myself.
Getting Started I felt pretty ready for freelancing full-time, I’d had a lot of experience on projects whilst I was at university.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
