<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Html on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/html/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Html on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 18:59:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic HTML on 24 Ways</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/semantic-html-on-24-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 18:59:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/semantic-html-on-24-ways/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a few years since I wrote something for 24ways, but this year I’m back, making the case for semantic HTML.
 
As I mention in the article, I see a lot of redundant and unsemantic HTML while I’m working on Better. HTML is often seen as easy, and therefore not worth learning in detail. It’s frustrating because HTML is one of the few completely unavoidable technologies of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>display: none;</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 08:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</guid>
      <description>Or The things you think are common knowledge but really they aren’t. I was on the ShopTalk show a few weeks ago, and a few people have asked me what I meant when I said “display: none; naughties.” I foolishly thought that people would understand what I meant, (and I’ll come to that later) so I thought I’d better explain myself.
display: none; in responsive web design When we’re changing out layouts based on viewport sizes, using media queries, we tend to switch page elements about a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMACSS –; Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/smacss-scalable-and-modular-architecture-for-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 08:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/smacss-scalable-and-modular-architecture-for-css/</guid>
      <description>I bought Jonathan Snook’s Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS five months ago and, embarrassingly, I’ve only just read it. As a “flexible guide to developing sites small and large”, it’s fantastic.
   Last month I was lucky enough to see Jonathan speak about State-Based Design (a concept which he covers in SMACSS) at theFromTheFront conference and it reminded me to put the book at the top of my to-read pile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Web Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-web-design/</guid>
      <description>I had ordered Responsive Web Design by Ethan Marcotte as soon as it came out, but being at Ampersand conference, and hearing so many people recommend it, really spurred me to take a few hours out to get on and read it.
  My copy of Responsive Web Design, already featuring a &amp;amp;#39;much used&amp;amp;#39; cover curl...   Responsive web design is a term summarising design that has a flexibility allowing it to be optimised for different browsing experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>