<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 07:20:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workplaces of Web Professionals</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 07:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/workplaces-of-web-professionals/</guid>
      <description>This morning Martin Wolf published an interesting blog post with photos of the “workplaces of web professionals”. I always wonder if people really are that tidy, or if they spent a while clearing up before they took the photo.
The featured photo of my workplace (in our ind.ie home office) shows the fairly typical mess on my desk, and the very typical dog getting in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March’s Pastry Box thought on purpose</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</guid>
      <description>Today my thought for March was posted on The Pastry Box. It was inspired by First Things First 2014, talks by Cole Peters and Nicklas de León Persson at Design and Banter, and Fictive Kin‘s slashpurpose.org.
I’ve started formulating a draft of my “purpose” for this site, but it’s not quite ready yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</guid>
      <description>After I finished my last post about Design Tips for Developers, it really struck me how much I wrote to justify my design. I wasn’t just writing tips saying “*do this, it’s good*“, “*don’t do this, it’s bad.*” I put time and effort into explaining why I made these decisions and why I didn’t do it another way.
When I send a design to a client via e-mail, I usually spend around 45 minutes –; 1 hour writing an accompanying ‘justification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a whole year since I officially started working as a freelance designer last August. I graduated from uni, had a brief fling with some full-time remote working, had an awkward interview with a recruiter and then decided that I’d rather give it a go by myself.
Getting Started I felt pretty ready for freelancing full-time, I’d had a lot of experience on projects whilst I was at university.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>