<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Client Work on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/client-work/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/client-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Stuff on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/breaking-stuff&#34;&gt;my latest column, Breaking Stuff&lt;/a&gt;, was published on A List Apart. I’m in a strange transitional period, moving from client work to fulltime at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie&#34;&gt;ind.ie&lt;/a&gt;, so I think I’ll be writing more about situations like these as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also finally updated that terrible avatar to something much better. I look uncharacteristically pale, but at least I’m normal colours! (Unlike the last terrible photo I’d used.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/breaking-stuff&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4561&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/10/Breaking-Stuff.png&#34; alt=&#34;Breaking Stuff column on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/i-dont-like-it&#34;&gt;my most recent column, I Don’t Like It&lt;/a&gt;, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://clientsfromhell.net/&#34;&gt;Clients From Hell&lt;/a&gt; attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/good-designers-good-clients&#34; title=&#34;Column on Good Designers, Good Clients&#34;&gt;it’s more often a designer’s fault&lt;/a&gt;. It might be easier to talk about these situations in the abstract than give solid advice on how to behave better. So I gave it a try, with some example interactions in my column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/07/I-Dont-Like-It-ALA.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4511&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/07/I-Dont-Like-It-ALA.png&#34; alt=&#34;I Don&amp;#39;t Like It column on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/&#34; title=&#34;Becoming part of Indie Phone&#34;&gt;my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-June-5&#34;&gt;my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak&lt;/a&gt;. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-June-5&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4490&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/06/pastry-box-june.png&#34; alt=&#34;Laura Kalbag on The Pastry Box, Thursday 5th June 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiephone.eu&#34;&gt;Indie Phone&lt;/a&gt; for 50% of my working time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What is Indie Phone?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has opened our data up to a lot of potential abuse, including the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.democracynow.org/2013/10/14/edward_snowden_speaks_out_against_nsa&#34;&gt;government dragnet surveillance employed by the NSA and GCHQ (and other governments)&lt;/a&gt;. For users aware of these problems, we can either choose to share our data, or be excluded from the majority of services (and social interactions) on the web. Worse still, the majority of general consumers on the web are unaware of these problems. There are loose, and often misleading, privacy settings on these services. Few people realise that they’re still sharing their data with the companies that own their services, and many other third parties. Even fewer people realise that their email and private messages are being stored, and potentially read and shared, with these services and third parties. To find out more about these issues, I really recommend watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thersa.org/events/audio-and-past-events/2014/Free-is-a-Lie&#34;&gt;Aral’s talk, ‘Free Is a Lie’&lt;/a&gt;, and watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://tacma.net/&#34;&gt;‘Terms and Conditions May Apply’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone aims to create a smart phone that isn’t just for the tech folk that want to take control over their data. We want to create experiences that combine hardware, software, and the cloud, as well as appealing to the everyday consumer. The fact that it’ll be open, and allows you to take control of your data, and choose what you want to be shared, is an essential bonus. It’s incredibly important that these tools are available to everybody. We don’t want to discriminate against those with less tech experience or knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like Indie Phone. There are a few fantastic companies and products working towards other &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;indie technologies&lt;/a&gt;. Together we can try to make technology, and the web, more open and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-indie-tech&#34;&gt;What’s indie tech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data-hungry services have become the norm. Indie Technologies have sustainable business models and offer alternatives to these services. These alternative products need to be design-led and consumer-friendly so they can realistically compete in the consumer market. At Indie Phone, we’re spearheading indie tech, we want to be a great example to other indie technologies. We also have plans to help support and promote other indie tech projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-work-with-indie-phone-when-i-love-client-work-so-much&#34;&gt;Why work with Indie Phone when I love client work so much?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been very trendy lately to switch from client work to a side project or product. A lot of designers and developers don’t enjoy client services. But I do. I really really love working with clients, and helping them achieve their goals. It’s similar to why I love Indie Phone. I like providing services to people who otherwise may not be able to create their own site or understand what would work for them on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been Chief Sounding Board for the last 10 months, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; has researched, planned, brainstormed and agonised over Codename Prometheus and Indie Phone. It’s been his life for nearly a year, so in turn has been a huge part of my life. I have absolute faith in his ability to see it through. It’s been hard sitting on the sidelines, desperately wanting to help, but not being able to dedicate the time and money that a project of this size really needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sale of Aral’s family’s home in Ankara, we finally have funds to afford other people to work on the Indie Phone up to crowd funding. Money is still tight, we can’t afford me to work on Indie Phone 100% of the time, and this works for me. The money is far better spent on other valuable skills required to get us up-and-running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-do-for-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What I do for Indie Phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design and web development. Web is my specialism, so the most expertise I can offer Indie Phone is in producing the websites, mini sites and other web-based materials. I also work on the branding and other general graphic design tasks. Sometimes I do some writing, and I do a lot of editing. All of my work is collaborative. Aral, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jo-porter.com/&#34;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt; and I all review and critique each others’ work, and this is an exciting new experience for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-other-50-of-my-time&#34;&gt;What about the other 50% of my time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still carry on the relationships I have with my existing clients, and take on a few new clients, with a decent amount of time to dedicate to client work. I love the variety of client work, and I really enjoy working with different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-want-to-work-with-other-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;I want to work with other indie tech projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been picky with new projects, I only work with clients that I care about and projects that interest me. That’s how I do my best work. And lately, as I’ve been absolutely influenced by Indie Phone, I really care about the success of indie tech projects. Is your project design-led, free and open, and independent in line with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;Indie Technology Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;? Then I’ve got a deal for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;20-off-for-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;20% off for indie tech projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to put my money where my mouth is. I want to work on indie tech projects so much, that I will work for 20% less (on my hourly rate) for an indie tech project. This will be expensive for me, but I want to do more to help indie technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-can-i-offer-an-indie-tech-project&#34;&gt;What can I offer an indie tech project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I’m an all-round designer. With design-led projects, the majority of indie tech projects probably have a designer in place already, but I’m here for support and strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/graphic-design/&#34; title=&#34;Graphic Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. From logos to typography to icons for your avatars, I can create your brand and show you how to use it effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I love the web. If it’s working out the experience for your app, I can help you with design and front-end development. With marketing sites, I can promote your product with an end-to-end solution (copy to content management system, I can do all of that.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in my 20% discount, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@laurakalbag.com?subject=Indie%20Tech Project&#34;&gt;send me an email at me@laurakalbag.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-huge-but-also-not-so-huge&#34;&gt;It’s huge, but also not so huge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this hasn’t changed much. I’m still working from home, as the Indie Phone office is currently occupying the largest room in our house. I’m still working on projects I love with people that I love. I’m very lucky :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-29759&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://designack.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ngaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-29759&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-04T08:45:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:45am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        What a great idea Laura! I really hope it goes well for you. Having a side project that you’re passionate about can make your client work even better too I think. It’s having that freedom to do something where you can see your creativity bloom while making a difference that is great about side projects.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-32622&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ran&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-32622&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-16T01:00:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;01:00am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Keep us posted on Indie Phone, sounds good.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and My Big Fat Ego on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/me-and-my-big-fat-ego&#34;&gt;my column on Me and My Big Fat Ego&lt;/a&gt; was published on A List Apart. It’s not that I’d say I have a huge ego, but it’s definitely something that’s easily bruised when I feel like things aren’t going my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/me-and-my-big-fat-ego&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4303&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/04/me-and-my-big-fat-ego.png&#34; alt=&#34;Me and My Big Fat Ego column on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #61</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I was a guest on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/61&#34;&gt;Unfinished Business podcast&lt;/a&gt; again. I had a lovely time chatting to Andy about speaking at conferences, working for free and I even managed to squeeze in a rant about accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/61&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4098&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/11/unfinishedbusiness.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andrew Clarke &amp;amp;amp; guests have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/delivery-logistics&#34;&gt;my latest column on A List Apart&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/delivery-logistics&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4258&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/02/Delivery-Logistics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Delivery Logistics on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #54</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/54&#34;&gt;latest Unfinished Business podcast&lt;/a&gt; has just been published, and I’m on it again! I had a lovely time talking to Andy about scheduling projects, invoicing, rates and people who don’t understand copyright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very big thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/Jo_annaP&#34;&gt;my friend Jo&lt;/a&gt; who let me take over her internet and bedroom for the recording, as our internet is still terrible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/54&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4221&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/unfinished-business-54.png&#34; alt=&#34;Unfinished Business episode #54&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today is the day &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box&lt;/a&gt;. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/bakers/year/2014&#34;&gt;the lineup for this year&lt;/a&gt;, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon. It’s very exciting to join in, and I really love the &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/philosophy&#34;&gt;philosophy of consuming content in a way that works for you, and ensures the content’s longevity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethics&#34;&gt;Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great conversation about ethics in client work with Andy Clarke on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/50&#34;&gt;Unfinished Business podcast&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. In a world where society is clearly struggling with so many issues (wealth/poverty divide, human rights, privacy, and so on) I wonder how I can make a difference, or prevent myself from being complicit in further problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run-up to my publishing date on The Pastry Box (it’ll likely be the 11th of each month) I was so worried about what I would write, and trying to come up with something interesting. Then I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mostlysignssomeportents.tumblr.com/post/72759474218/we-are-huxleying-ourselves-into-the-full-orwell&#34;&gt;this post by Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, and had some worrying conversations about other people’s attitude to privacy with &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt;. Suddenly I found myself writing an incoherent stream of anger into my notebook. A long thoughtful walk with the dog later, and I finally had something that might be worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know what you think, this means a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4195&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/the-pastry-box.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of my post on The Pastry Box&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #44</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 18:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/44&#34;&gt;Last week I was on Unfinished Business again&lt;/a&gt;! Andy and I talked about hosting workshops, business names and how to make a good impression via email. My audio is pretty awful, and I’m sorry for that. I tried to be all clever with my headset, but ended up sounding very small and faraway…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also going to be on Unfinished Business more regularly. I always have fun chatting to Andy, and it’s a great excuse to pick his more experienced brains about business stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/44&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4098&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/11/unfinishedbusiness.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andrew Clarke &amp;amp;amp; guests have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lovely people at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com&#34;&gt;Dare conference&lt;/a&gt; have released &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos/kalbag&#34;&gt;the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty&lt;/a&gt;. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/open-for-business&#34;&gt;my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos&#34; title=&#34;Dare conference videos&#34;&gt;there’s loads of great talks on there&lt;/a&gt;, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations. If you enjoy any of the videos, &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos#donate&#34; title=&#34;Donate to Dare conference&#34;&gt;please donate&lt;/a&gt;. Dare didn’t make any money this this, but it was a phenomenal, heartwarming and groundbreaking event. I can’t wait for next year’s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos/kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4087&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/10/dare-conf-video.png&#34; alt=&#34;My Secret Is Honesty - Video of Laura Kalbag at Dare conference&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open for Business on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/open-for-business&#34;&gt;My second column for A List Apart, “Open for Business,” is now up&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote Open for Business as a follow-up to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com&#34;&gt;Dare conference&lt;/a&gt; talk about honesty. It’s not the same as the full talk (and has been edited into a far better shape by Rose Weisburd) but is the essence of why I feel that being open works for my business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/open-for-business&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4082&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/10/open-for-business.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open for Business post on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-2457&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0257c59d68f24a7ec605207536aff175?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0257c59d68f24a7ec605207536aff175?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.danieldogeanu.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Daniel Dogeanu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-2457&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-10-17T18:16:06+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:16pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I read your article on A List Apart and I wanted to follow you on Twitter because the article was so awesome. Then I realized I was already following you. Awesome feeling!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
