<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Client Work on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/client-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Client Work on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/client-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Stuff on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week my latest column, Breaking Stuff, was published on A List Apart. I’m in a strange transitional period, moving from client work to fulltime at ind.ie, so I think I’ll be writing more about situations like these as time goes on.
I’ve also finally updated that terrible avatar to something much better. I look uncharacteristically pale, but at least I’m normal colours! (Unlike the last terrible photo I’d used.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time, my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and My Big Fat Ego on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Today my column on Me and My Big Fat Ego was published on A List Apart. It’s not that I’d say I have a huge ego, but it’s definitely something that’s easily bruised when I feel like things aren’t going my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #61</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. I had a lovely time chatting to Andy about speaking at conferences, working for free and I even managed to squeeze in a rant about accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In my latest column on A List Apart, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #54</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</guid>
      <description>The latest Unfinished Business podcast has just been published, and I’m on it again! I had a lovely time talking to Andy about scheduling projects, invoicing, rates and people who don’t understand copyright.
A very big thank you to my friend Jo who let me take over her internet and bedroom for the recording, as our internet is still terrible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #44</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 18:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-44/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was on Unfinished Business again! Andy and I talked about hosting workshops, business names and how to make a good impression via email. My audio is pretty awful, and I’m sorry for that. I tried to be all clever with my headset, but ended up sounding very small and faraway…
I’m also going to be on Unfinished Business more regularly. I always have fun chatting to Andy, and it’s a great excuse to pick his more experienced brains about business stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>The lovely people at Dare conference have released the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”
I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that there’s loads of great talks on there, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open for Business on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>My second column for A List Apart, “Open for Business,” is now up. I wrote Open for Business as a follow-up to my Dare conference talk about honesty. It’s not the same as the full talk (and has been edited into a far better shape by Rose Weisburd) but is the essence of why I feel that being open works for my business.
 
One comment ### Daniel Dogeanu  at 18:16pm</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>