<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 10:19:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there potential for “ethical analytics”?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 10:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</guid>
      <description>We have Piwik analytics on the Ind.ie site, and I use Gauges and GoSquared on my own site (I was indecisive at the time…) But I use Ghostery so I actually block analytics like this for my own use.
As someone who is a big web fan, and used to work in client services, I understand the value of particular types of analytics for simple sites like ours:
 Amount of hits (required to understand popular/unpopular content and make financial decisions for hosting etc) Browser/browser size/operating system (required to know how to optimise for visitors) Language spoken (required to work out how to best optimise for different languages) Referring links (to track who is saying what about your site)  BUT, I think there are unnecessary metrics that can be on the invasive side for simple sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion Of Free on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Last week, my column on The Illusion Of Free was published on A List Apart. I took a lot of time writing it, as I think it’s an incredibly important issue, and it reflects my thinking around Ind.ie. As ever, a massive thank you to the wonderful editor Rose Weisburd who helped me round things out, made me sound smarter and encouraged me in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March’s Pastry Box thought on purpose</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</guid>
      <description>Today my thought for March was posted on The Pastry Box. It was inspired by First Things First 2014, talks by Cole Peters and Nicklas de León Persson at Design and Banter, and Fictive Kin‘s slashpurpose.org.
I’ve started formulating a draft of my “purpose” for this site, but it’s not quite ready yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
