<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:26:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 418:conf web meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the very first 418:conf web meetup on 16th June 2015 in Nutfield (near Redhill) in Surrey. It’s exciting for me because it’s near where I used to live, and it’s a cool new meetup with a lot of potential.
If you’re local, you should get your ticket now. They’re free!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Design &#43; Banter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at Design + Banter on Monday in London. It’s already sold out, but there’s a waiting list available for the free tickets.
Nicklas Persson and Cole Peters are also speaking so I’m really chuffed to be part of a great lineup!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 12 Devs of Winter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at 12 Devs of Winter on the 22nd January in Shoreditch. Because I’ve clearly lost my mind, I’m going to be doing another new talk. This time on ‘Freelancing for the reluctant businessperson.’ I’m that reluctant businessperson, and I’m hoping to share some silly stories about all the daft things I’ve done and some of the things that have worked out just fine.
For once, I’m ahead of the schedule, and tickets will be released this Wednesday 8th January at 10am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MKGN this Thursday</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</guid>
      <description>This Thursday I’m speaking at Milton Keynes Geek Night. Tickets sold out terrifyingly quickly, but I put that down to MKGN always being a great event.
I’m going to talk about self-discipline, it’s a new talk and so that makes me even more nervous than usual &#34; /</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web talk dog walk II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 09:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-2/</guid>
      <description>The last web talk dog walk was a success, with three of us (plus three dogs) taking in the slightly damp wilds of Sheepcote Valley. Now for the next one!
I was originally planning on making them fortnightly but have already failed as I wasn’t organised enough to sort one out this week. This means the next Web talk dog walk will be:
9am on Wednesday 3rd July 2013 Meeting at the same spot on the corner of Wilson Avenue and Roedean Road planning to walk for an hour or so (maybe slightly longer if I continue navigating badly) in East Brighton Park/Sheepcote valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Untangle the Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Nothing quite like a last-minute post… Tonight I’m speaking at Untangle the Web at Google Campus in London. I’m doing a talk on Design Theory for the Web where I do a whistle-stop tour through designing with typography, grids and colour on the web.
I also have a stinking cold so I’m going to be taking industrial quantities of Red Bull and a quarantine zone with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web talk dog walk</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 16:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk/</guid>
      <description>I walk my dog Oskar every day, no matter what the weather. And usually it’s just him and me. So I’ve got this idea. A “web talk dog walk” where a group of us from the Brighton area can meet on a regular basis (probably fortnightly, maybe monthly) to walk dogs and chat about the web. Do you want to join us?
The first walk is 9am this Wednesday 12th June 2013 The best place to walk in the area (and conveniently near to where we live is East Brighton Park/Sheepcote valley.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
