<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Fonts on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/web-fonts/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 16:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/web-fonts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 16:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>Another fab and in-depth article from Craig Grannell on Digital Arts, this time on Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015. Craig asked a load of smart designers (and me) about web fonts, web font services, and how to choose web fonts.
 
My full answers to Craig’s original questions are below:
What do you consider the current best options for working with web fonts? I’m forever changing my mind, but I tend to prefer to host fonts on the site itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts.com mockup fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I do like the way that fonts.com do web fonts. (I also like all of the web font services for different reasons and different projects.)
Mockup fonts Fonts.com have this new system that really works. It involves an app called SkyFonts. This allows you to try out different fonts in your desktop mockups as rentals. Great for static mockups of web designs. You choose the fonts you want on the fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography and the web at Ampersand Conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a big old writeup for ubelly from my notes at Ampersand conference earlier in the month.
This was an event I decided not to live-tweet, as the content is usually more involved and in-depth, making for a better big writeup and less tweetable quotes.
Typography and the web at Ampersand conference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>I’ve tried to condense my notes from Ampersand conference into a more useful digest. More than anything this, like my live-tweeting at past conferences, is really a selfish activity to help me absorb the ideas from Ampersand better by reflecting on the themes of the day.
And of course in the spirit of the web and all things good, I may as well share this digest so anyone who wasn’t there might get a taste of the event (albeit through my probably-twisted interpretation and slightly dodgy writing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!
Day One Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.
Tweet
Tweet Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
