<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 08:54:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Destiny Machine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-destiny-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 08:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-destiny-machine/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday’s roundup was back to business as usual, after a couple of weeks of re:publica-related work. We’ve got the latest in the world of Spyware 2.0, and some fun ways that people are challenging the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New To Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 15:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</guid>
      <description>Following my learning design post, I’ve started a little project called “new to design.” At the moment it just consists of a learn-design tag on my Pinboard bookmarks and a Twitter account @newtodesign so that I can share useful design resources (especially for those new to design.)
In the future, I hope it can be useful in other ways. Any suggestions or anything you want to see? You know how to get in touch…  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We read with our own contexts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 14:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</guid>
      <description>Oh Twitter. Yesterday was another day where I accidentally incited another riot with a poorly-worded tweet. Nobody is perfect, but it’s starting to happen with alarming frequency, and I wanted to understand why I keep doing this.
The ever-present ego We read everything through our own ego filter. It’s how we apply new knowledge to our own situations. Whenever we read a tweet, blog post, article, book, watch a TV show, a film, a play, we take in what we’re reading and hearing and apply it to ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft and Care: Future Of Web Design 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 09:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written up my digest of Future Of Web Design 2012 over at the ubelly blog.
For those who want more of a blow-by-blow account of the day, I’ve compiled all of my live tweets (and retweets) from the day in a Storify feed.
http://storify.com/laurakalbag/laura-kalbag-s-fowd-tweets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day Two</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Ethan Marcotte –; Responsive Web Design Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Femi T Adesina –; Enhancing your Creativity I mis-hastagged the first tweet!
Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
My thoughts at this point: Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch continued&amp;#8230; Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!
Day One Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.
Tweet
Tweet Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yeah, so what if I live-tweet at conferences?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/yeah-so-what-if-i-live-tweet-at-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/yeah-so-what-if-i-live-tweet-at-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been at Future Of Web Design The last two days were long, but fantastic, experiences at Future Of Web Design. The talks were high quality, loads of cool people were there and I learnt a lot.
Problem is, (from some people’s point of view) I tweeted a lot. I’m not going to stop, but I thought I should explain why live tweeting isn’t just “trying to make yourself look clever by tweeting everything you hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who wants a ticket for The Big M?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/win-a-ticket-for-the-big-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 15:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/win-a-ticket-for-the-big-m/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know if you know, but I made the website for the upcoming super exciting mobile conference, The Big M.
   
As a result, I have 3 conference tickets worth £233.83 to give away to lovely people who want to learn more about mobile (covering topics such as innovation, usability, development, apps and mobile web.)
My 3 tickets are for the first day, the conference part of The Big M, which is on 21st March 2011 at Komedia in Bath (UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2011</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</guid>
      <description>Conferences are my social life As I go to more conferences, I meet more lovely people and get to see friends I’d only ever talk to on Twitter otherwise. In the last two years, I’ve been to about three a year and it feels about the right amount that you rarely see the same talk twice and it’s not just the same topics going round.
Again, I met loads of great people at New Adventures, but unfortunately missed more people than I meant to catch up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the iPad is saving my sanity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 18:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</guid>
      <description>Fan girl I’ve had an iPad since the day it was released in the UK. I bought it because I’m a fan girl. I admit it. I could pretend that I wanted it to take to conferences or use for testing or when I didn’t need a laptop when I went to visit clients. In truth, I only go to one or two conferences per year, I’ve not yet made a site that needed an iPad-specific site and when I go to visit clients I always need my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>