<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contract on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/contract/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contract on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/contract/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Including “ask me anything” in my contract</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</guid>
      <description>At Dare conference in September, I saw a great talk by Kevin Hoffman on “How To Rebuild Amidst Crisis.” I loved this talk, there was so much in it, but one thing struck me as something I could carry over into my work: Kevin said he included “ask any question and I’ll answer it” in his contract.
This might seem like stating the obvious at first, but really there’s nothing obvious to a client who is new to you, and your process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project  It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)
Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Tour Brighton</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Insites is a mini tour of four cities in the UK where Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks present discussions with well-known people from the web/tech industry. I was lucky enough to go to the first evening in Brighton on Monday where Aral Balkan, Sarah Parmenter and Jeremy Keith were the guests.
The Format The format of the evening was something unfamiliar to most of us. Each guest was interviewed by either Keir or Elliot and then there were questions from the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>