<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devices on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/devices/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/devices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mobile-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 09:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mobile-first/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on with my chapter-a-day, last week I finished reading the brilliant Mobile First by Luke Wroblewski.
   Mobile design and development has gained momentum over the last few years; with responsive design and designers regularly going giddy over iPhone app UIs, it’s surprising how little the industry discusses the *design* issues. We seem to prefer to get caught up in the more technical and development-based conversations (or the infuriatingly dull native vs web, but I’ll get back to that!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
