<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 10:37:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Last week my column on Inspiration was published on A List Apart. It follows roughly the same structure as the talk I gave at Design + Banter a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on Workspiration</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-on-workspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 11:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-on-workspiration/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I answered some questions for Workspiration on my hardware and software setup, inspiration and dreams.
Workspiration seems to have collected interviews from a huge variety of people working in and around tech, and with everybody answering the same questions, it makes for a really interesting read. Bonus is that they also (eventually) translate the interviews into Russian. It’s nice to see a site that’s open to non-English speakers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Beyond Ink podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the first episode of the Beyond Ink podcast went live. This was a podcast that Rachel had in the works for a while, and we first recorded together a few months ago. Last week we re-recorded that episode, so everything was up-to-date, and I had a fancy new microphone so I didn’t sound as terrible as I did on the last Unfinished Business.
Rachel and I chatted about process, the type of work we like to do and inspiration, amongst other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, a potential project turned up in my inbox. An old school friend wants a website, needs it soon and doesn’t have a huge budget.
Me and freelancing I’m lucky, I get offered a lot of projects, and usually I don’t have any availability for a few months. Little projects like this generally can’t pay the bills for me. It’s a lot of time (particularly admin) for a fairly small return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sharers on The Branch</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a post over on The Branch.
 James Dinsdale emailed me about a new project he was starting out, called The Branch, a site collecting posts about what inspires people. I love these kinds of posts, so I was really keen to be involved.
As a designer, inspiration is a much-discussed topic. Unfortunately, this ‘inspiration’ is often described as particular styles of design and the work of individual designers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zootool — The best and most beautiful tool for storing inspiration</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/zootool-the-best-tool-for-storing-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 21:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/zootool-the-best-tool-for-storing-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>Since I started using Zootool in March I’ve been totally addicted.
I’d been looking for a scrapbook-style app, to stash all the inspiration I find, for a while. On cool sites like Dribbble, Drawar, FFFFound and all over the web, I’m always finding pretty things I’d like to keep and use when I’m designing later on.
I was trying to do this with Little Snapper but found, whilst it’s great for posh and annotated screenshots, it wasn’t quick enough to capture and file the images and sites that I’d found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>