<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Design Issues on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What advice do you give to aspiring designers or typographers?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was just asked, amongst a couple of other questions, what advice I would give to aspiring designers or typographers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my mind focused on the aspiration part, I started writing an answer based on finding your own way of working through studying others, not copying… And then I realised it was a bit &lt;em&gt;superficial&lt;/em&gt;. What’s the biggest problem with young designers today? They’re coin-operated&lt;a href=&#34;#coin-operated&#34;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;. So I wrote what I hope is slightly better advice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be ethical. Design is a great power where you can choose to instruct and manipulate others into thinking, feeling, and acting. Use those powers for good, don’t promote or help those whose business and goals harm people. Work hard to build a society you want to inhabit in the long term. Don’t underestimate your own impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href=&#34;https://ar.al&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; came up with that term. I just love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-146596&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/06dd590ce0771be9e44af9efacb0cb76?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/06dd590ce0771be9e44af9efacb0cb76?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.greavesdesign.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-146596&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-04-27T10:32:45+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:32am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I would say focus on the one thing you are good at and master that skill and style, don’t get distracted thinking you need to know everything about anything. Such as if youre thing is vector graphics become the best at it, or if you use illustrator get to know it inside out. Hope that’s helpful advice for someone.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there potential for “ethical analytics”?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 10:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/piwik-alternative-for-analytics/627&#34;&gt;Piwik analytics&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/&#34;&gt;Ind.ie site&lt;/a&gt;, and I use Gauges and GoSquared on my own site (I was indecisive at the time…) But I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ghostery.com/en/&#34;&gt;Ghostery&lt;/a&gt; so I actually block analytics like this for my own use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who is a big web fan, and used to work in client services, I understand the value of particular types of analytics for simple sites like ours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amount of hits (required to understand popular/unpopular content and make financial decisions for hosting etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser/browser size/operating system (required to know how to optimise for visitors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language spoken (required to work out how to best optimise for different languages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referring links (to track who is saying what about your site)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BUT, I think there are unnecessary metrics that can be on the invasive side for simple sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet Service Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking of individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some metrics I find misleading, as they’re based on pattern-matching and guessing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engagement time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender/Income Level/Age/Interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these are grey areas when it comes to tracking web apps, but I’d be interested to know where you all see boundaries? Are all analytics bad analytics? Is there room for “ethical analytics” that only tracks anonymous data with limited uses? Would there be a business in that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/628/2&#34;&gt;Discussion on the Ind.ie forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion Of Free on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/the-illusion-of-free&#34;&gt;my column on The Illusion Of Free&lt;/a&gt; was published on A List Apart. I took a lot of time writing it, as I think it’s an incredibly important issue, and it reflects my thinking around &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie&#34;&gt;Ind.ie&lt;/a&gt;. As ever, a massive thank you to the wonderful editor Rose Weisburd who helped me round things out, made me sound smarter and encouraged me in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/the-illusion-of-free&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4639&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/04/Illusion-of-Free.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of column on The Illusion of Free&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at border:none</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next month I’m speaking and running a “creator unit” at border:none in Nuremberg. This is incredibly exciting as it’s an event focused around the decentralisation of the web, a topic that I care about a great deal. I’ll be talking about using considerate design and great user experiences to create genuine alternatives to the products that make money from exploiting their users’ data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also an all-new topic for me to share with other people, so I can’t wait! &lt;a href=&#34;https://border-none.net/2014/tickets&#34;&gt;Tickets for the whole 2-day event&lt;/a&gt; are just 199 euros, and they have a really clever way of matching participants up with the topics they’re interested in, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://border-none.net/2014/tickets#c67&#34;&gt;an “aurora” of interests&lt;/a&gt;. You really should come along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://border-none.net/2014&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4545&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/border-none.png&#34; alt=&#34;border:none. Creator Conference for The Rising Web 2014. October 17th - 18th Nuremberg, Germany&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt; was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-with-the-network&#34;&gt;Living with the network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-freedom&#34;&gt;Technology and freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living with the network is more about social interaction than it is about technology. When new technology is introduced, it brings more issues around social change and social acceptance than it does around the features, gadgets and gimmicks of the technology itself. As an industry, we’ve set up systems that serve the majority, but only provide benefits to the few. Georgina Voss’s talk about distribution systems covered how the postal networks allowed governments to censor media through distribution channels. These examples had alarming parallels with the internet as a distribution channel allowing for censorship through a centralised system. It was a strong warning about the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.battleforthenet.com/sept10th/&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cory Doctorow put it, “it’s not a fight about information, it’s a fight about people. And people want to be free.” And for people (and information) to be free, the information networks need to be free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-and-surveillance&#34;&gt;Privacy and surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to privacy and surveillance, we are currently frogs sitting in a pot of warm water. The water is slowly being boiled around us, our privacy and freedom being slowly taken from us by governments and corporations. We won’t notice we’re being boiled until it’s too late, we won’t notice that our privacy and freedom has been irreversibly damaged until it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already in trouble and this is why we need to talk more, and act more, on the issues of privacy and surveillance. We need to bring these issues to the fore so we don’t become the frogs in the boiling water. As Tom Scott said in his vision of 2030, “privacy was already dead, it’s that not everyone agreed with it yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-diversity&#34;&gt;Technology and diversity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy Brown emphasised how the effect of technology on society around us isn’t just about the individual, and our own selfish gains. At least it shouldn’t be. With the lack of diversity in the web and tech industries, we’re creating technology for the privileged. When we’re creating products to scratch our own itch, and solve our own problems, we’re largely creating products for young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctorow pointed out that business models don’t exist in a vacuum, they reflect political, economic and social needs. And following the lines of Mandy Brown’s talk, the political, economic and social needs that we’re currently serving are largely those of young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-was-a-brief-summary&#34;&gt;This was a brief summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My post is a little summary of some of the themes that jumped out at me over the course of Friday. Lucky for you, &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/dConstruct/tags/dconstruct2014&#34;&gt;all the talks are available in audio format on huffduffer&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re well worth a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4537&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/dconstruct-2014.png&#34; alt=&#34;dConstruct 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Designing for the unknown</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, Craig Grannell asked me some questions about designing for the unknown. The result was a really fantastic article called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalartsonline.co.uk/features/graphic-design/designing-for-unknown-how-design-templates-frameworks/&#34;&gt;Designing for the unknown: how to design templates and frameworks&lt;/a&gt;, and has contributions from some really smart people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title image is from my writeup of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/project/default-perch-theme/&#34; title=&#34;Default Perch Theme&#34;&gt;Default Perch Theme project&lt;/a&gt; I did with Perch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalartsonline.co.uk/features/graphic-design/designing-for-unknown-how-design-templates-frameworks/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4520&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/08/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown.png&#34; alt=&#34;Digital Arts: Designing for the unknown&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: The future of web design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 13:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days I’m catching up on things I failed to share in recent months. It’s been a very busy few months, but I still like to have a record of what I did and where I’ve been!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, I spoke to Neil Bennett about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalartsonline.co.uk/features/interactive-design/whats-future-of-web-design/&#34;&gt;the future of web design&lt;/a&gt;, and the challenges we face. There were some good questions, and it’s interesting to see the answers of difference people from different areas side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitalartsonline.co.uk/features/interactive-design/whats-future-of-web-design/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4514&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/08/Digital-Arts-future-of-web-design.png&#34; alt=&#34;Digital Arts - The future of web design: leading creatives discuss what&amp;#39;s coming next&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Heart Internet</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Heart Internet posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heartinternet.co.uk/blog/article/interview-with-web-accessibility-champion-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;an interview with me&lt;/a&gt; on their site. They start off saying some very kind things about me, and then it covers accessibility, design, speaking at conferences and a bit of client work. As a bonus, it’s interspersed with photos of me pulling weird faces at conferences (and being business on the phone!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heartinternet.co.uk/blog/article/interview-with-web-accessibility-champion-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4203&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/heart-interview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Interview with Laura Kalbag on Heart Internet&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today is the day &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box&lt;/a&gt;. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/bakers/year/2014&#34;&gt;the lineup for this year&lt;/a&gt;, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon. It’s very exciting to join in, and I really love the &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/philosophy&#34;&gt;philosophy of consuming content in a way that works for you, and ensures the content’s longevity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethics&#34;&gt;Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great conversation about ethics in client work with Andy Clarke on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/50&#34;&gt;Unfinished Business podcast&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. In a world where society is clearly struggling with so many issues (wealth/poverty divide, human rights, privacy, and so on) I wonder how I can make a difference, or prevent myself from being complicit in further problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run-up to my publishing date on The Pastry Box (it’ll likely be the 11th of each month) I was so worried about what I would write, and trying to come up with something interesting. Then I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mostlysignssomeportents.tumblr.com/post/72759474218/we-are-huxleying-ourselves-into-the-full-orwell&#34;&gt;this post by Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, and had some worrying conversations about other people’s attitude to privacy with &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt;. Suddenly I found myself writing an incoherent stream of anger into my notebook. A long thoughtful walk with the dog later, and I finally had something that might be worth sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know what you think, this means a lot to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-january-11&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4195&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/the-pastry-box.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of my post on The Pastry Box&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devices&#34;&gt;“Devices”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry. There’s no way of telling which device is being used without testing for user agents, and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2011/02/499-lest-we-forget-or-how-i-learned-whats-so-bad-about-browser-sniffing&#34;&gt;it’s likely that the user agent string is lying to us anyway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-sizes&#34;&gt;“Screen sizes”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, many of us started talking about device-agnostic “screen sizes”. Being device-agnostic meant we’d hopefully stop trying to make assumptions about user behaviour based on the particular type of device they were using. Mobile phone users could be “mobile” but it wouldn’t make a difference to use because we were basing our designs on screen sizes and using the knowledge that some people could possibly be “mobile” to improve usability and performance for all our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then we still keep hanging on to those devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that smart phones tend to start at around 320px, tablets possibly around 760px and then we often count anything upward of 900px as if it’s a desktop computer. If we talk about screen sizes like this, they still correspond to the screens on particular types of devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;browser-windows&#34;&gt;“Browser windows”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I talk about “browser windows”. Yeah, these are often non-resizable fullscreen apps on the screens of various portable devices, but on desktop operating systems, a browser window could be &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I check out my own site’s analytics, there are visitors from 24 different browser window widths upward of 800px. And my responsive media queries are responding to those browser window sizes. Not the device, not the size of the screen, but the width of the browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s only counting browser sizes at 800px and above. Who’s to say that a user doesn’t resize their browser window so that it’s narrower than 800px? They might be using two windows side-by-side. This would mean that they’re viewing a narrow version of a site, responding to media queries we may have designed with mobile phones in mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trying-to-be-clear&#34;&gt;Trying to be clear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’re explaining what we’re doing as designers working on responsive sites, speaking in terms of “browser windows” helps clients (bosses, stakeholders, coworkers, whatever…) understand what we’re really doing. It helps them understand what we can and can’t detect, what we do and do not have control over and help us collectively truly embrace a responsive device-agnostic approach. We need to take care with the language we use, and choose accuracy, even if it means we sometimes have to educate others, over the dumbing-down which inevitably results in expectations we can’t, and don’t want to, meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-567&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/980339c2fa3195876f7389fa0db3ed3e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/980339c2fa3195876f7389fa0db3ed3e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kruegerdesigns.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Adam Krueger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-567&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-08-08T19:23:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:23pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

Great post, referring to the browser when talking about RWD makes a lot of sense. I’ve heard “mobile-first” miss used a lot at my office. This post should help clear up some confusion.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts.com mockup fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I do like the way that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fonts.com/&#34;&gt;fonts.com&lt;/a&gt; do web fonts. (&lt;em&gt;I also like all of the web font services for different reasons and different projects.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mockup-fonts&#34;&gt;Mockup fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fonts.com have this new system that really works. It involves &lt;a href=&#34;https://skyfonts.com/&#34;&gt;an app called SkyFonts&lt;/a&gt;. This allows you to try out different fonts in your desktop mockups as rentals. Great for static mockups of web designs. You choose the fonts you want on the fonts.com website, and it syncs them to your desktop. I didn’t expect it to work as well as it does, but it just works. (&lt;em&gt;I love using Typecast and working in the browser, but a lot of time I want to play with layout on a canvas.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;however-the-plans-don-t-allow-for-much&#34;&gt;However, the plans don’t allow for much&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plans on fonts.com are frustrating. I have a Pro plan. It’s a very reasonable price for what I get, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://typecast.com/&#34;&gt;a Typecast subscription&lt;/a&gt; and 1 million pageviews a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fonts.com/web-fonts/plans-and-pricing&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3805&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/07/plans.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fonts.com plans from http://www.fonts.com/web-fonts/plans-and-pricing&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;20-mockup-fonts-a-month&#34;&gt;20 mockup fonts a month&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a very reasonable amount. Am I likely to use more than 20 different fonts over all my mockups in a month? Maybe only just… Say five family weights (bear in mind, I’m mocking up, not embedding these all on the web!) on four different projects. That’s doable. But if you hover over the details of the plan, you see this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mockup fonts are desktop versions of your Web fonts provided exclusively for creating website mockups. Delivered through SkyFonts, mockup fonts remain active for 1 day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mockup fonts remain active for 1 day. &lt;/strong&gt;This means that if I want to use the same font two days running, I use two of my allowed fonts. This means working on a mockup for three days with four fonts, I’ve nearly burned through my allowance already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fonts.com/web-fonts/plans-and-pricing&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3809&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/07/plans-hover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fonts.com plans with details from http://www.fonts.com/web-fonts/plans-and-pricing&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-next-plan-up-allows-unlimited-mockup-fonts-but-costs-nearly-three-times-as-much&#34;&gt;The next plan up allows unlimited mockup fonts but costs nearly three times as much&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I’d like to upgrade just for the unlimited mockup fonts, I can’t justify that cost when I won’t use any of the other features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-fonts-com-may-we-have-more-mockup-fonts&#34;&gt;Please fonts.com, may we have more mockup fonts?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of use who are small (me, just a one person!) web-based studios, it would be great to have more mockup fonts. We’re the people who try out your fonts, and then get our clients to subscribe and buy your fonts. We’re like an extension of your sales team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-ll-happily-pay-slightly-extra-just-not-three-times-the-amount&#34;&gt;I’ll happily pay slightly extra, just not three times the amount&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t doubt the value of the fonts, and I’m willing to spend money to get quality. Seeing as SkyFonts is doing a good job of allowing rentals, without any concern for piracy, couldn’t we have more fonts? (Maybe 150 × 24 hour uses a month?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this is an odd blog post, and probably a niche request. I was going to tweet about it, but realised I just have too much to say in a short post. If anyone else has this problem, please leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-comments&#34;&gt;3 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-563&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ca28449379d1e89b041811b4af23e627?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ca28449379d1e89b041811b4af23e627?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.fonts.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Matt Brinkerhoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-563&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-02T15:34:57+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:34pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

Thanks for taking the time to write such detailed feedback. We see Mockup and Desktop Fonts as one of the most important features of our Fonts.com subscriptions and we’re currently exploring ways to make it better. If you have more feedback, I’d love to hear it at [twitter@fonts.com](mailto:twitter@fonts.com).

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!

Matt

Fonts.com&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-564&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c083c7ffc86fab9e831990ad82033f99?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c083c7ffc86fab9e831990ad82033f99?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.jasonbradberry.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jason Bradberry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-564&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-12T16:28:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:28pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Here here! Yes and yes. And Amen.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-143312&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/51fc79b898b7953493027cc0d001ed18?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/51fc79b898b7953493027cc0d001ed18?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ken Clinkenbeard&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-143312&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2015-11-04T19:09:07+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:09pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Has anything changed with Mockup and Desktop fonts since your post. It does not appear so. For Mockup fonts, 20 font/days per 30-day period is paltry on most any design single project. And only 5 Desktop fonts per month is no better. This is especially true at this time, also, when the top plan switches to Unlimited for both categories. I realized they want people to upgrade, but this just plays us as dumb by offering an unusable plan in practice.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fl&amp;#42;t design trend</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’m about to apply a mute filter to the word “flat” on Twitter. That or start unfollowing &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-flat&#34;&gt;What’s flat?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s an aesthetic “trend” that’s been around for a while. It involves fewer gradients and textures and has thus been described as “flat” design. It’s often described as the opposite of “&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skeuomorph&#34;&gt;skeuomorphism&lt;/a&gt;,” (which is an equally irritating word when used in this way.) It was popularised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metro_(design_language)&#34;&gt;Windows Metro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and, being an aesthetic associated with fewer images, and thus better performance and more flexibility in the development of interfaces, has been a feature of many designs in both apps and on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-described-as-an-aesthetic-summary&#34;&gt;Design described as an aesthetic summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetics are just one facet of&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Something may be pretty, but a horrible user experience. Something may be pretty, but completely inappropriate for the audience or the business. Every decision made in the process of creating a product is by design. There is so much complexity to design, and to judge an interactive design purely on an aesthetic basis is simply superficial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trends&#34;&gt;Trends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trends are fine, and inevitable. Designers are inspired by each other, particularly the more effective solutions to common problems, and consequently some work ends up &lt;em&gt;looking&lt;/em&gt; much like other work. However, to dismiss work that is aesthetically similar as part of a trend is often insulting to the role of a designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, many (charlatan) designers will simply reapply an aesthetic to the content they’ve been given and call it “design” without questioning whether it’s appropriate for the content or easy to use in its behaviour. But true designers do not just assign aesthetic styles to content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a decision and a reason behind choosing that aesthetic. It will be used as a design language to communicate to the user how to interact with the product. It will be affected by, and have implications for, the use of the product and the build process. A million tiny decisions will have been made to come to that aesthetic conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m sure that decisions made by 99.99% of designers will not have been “I’ll use the flat design trend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 style=&#34;opacity: .8;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;opacity: .8;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was inspired by the many people on Twitter criticising Apple for “following the flat design trend” (and the many variants on that comment) with their iOS7 interface design. I’m trying not to be snotty when I say this, but I’m reserving judgement until I’ve had a device running iOS7 in my hands for a few days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;opacity: .8;&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aral wrote a very good post on “&lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/design-is-not-veneer/&#34;&gt;Design is not veneer&lt;/a&gt;” which explores this topic in more depth and is well-worth a read.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-comments&#34;&gt;12 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-548&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6f7070f6c139c4323f3c96d743f9a1f7?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6f7070f6c139c4323f3c96d743f9a1f7?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.dan-davies.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dan Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-548&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T14:49:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:49pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’ve found the whole debacle really funny.  Dribbble seems to house many designers that believe their opinion is higher than that of Apple themselves. Give it a few months and they’ll be knocking out icons just like Mr Ive whilst sipping on their skinny latte.

Bugger them all, I just plan to do stuff my way.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-549&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae76a5767f2b47318e90deea51aec04d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ae76a5767f2b47318e90deea51aec04d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.andrewhuntdesign.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Andy Hunt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-549&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T14:59:12+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:59pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        My initial reaction is that I don’t like the icons or the colour palette. However, Im also aware I’m looking at the design ‘blind’ and that this direction has been taken due the UX and new features that have been put in.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-550&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f9ad38063f9d406b91efb89ea055f75e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f9ad38063f9d406b91efb89ea055f75e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://mmandbstudio.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Simon Mason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-550&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:01:04+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:01pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I get more irritated by the fact Apple’s website still isn’t responsive, because, you know pinch and zoom is all you need &amp;#8230;

Anyway come October there will no doubt be lots of praise for the new iOS7 shiny.

Funny how people love the new but hate change.

Ho hum
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-551&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/766047c2f4d0bca639f03a66883197f6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/766047c2f4d0bca639f03a66883197f6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.markdixon.ca/design/blog/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-551&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:03:01+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:03pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;It is nice to see designers putting things in context like you are doing here.

Somewhere along the line the idea that flat is better or even the correct way to design established a critical mass. Many designers seem to be adopting it without much questioning.

Careful, do not drink the Kool-Aid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-552&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f202503f0ea3118e596f40fdaf8fb3f8?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f202503f0ea3118e596f40fdaf8fb3f8?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://cliffpro.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Cliff Huizenga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-552&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:11:27+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:11pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I guess the world that revolves around Dribbble has kind of spoiled me when it comes to design. I see all these great works — many of which do follow trends, but also great unique ones — so I expect something mind-blowing from Apple. While the fl*t design in the apps look nice, those home screen icons (mainly Safari and Mail) simply look rushed and condensed. Their design gives the impression that they were changing the look for the sake of “de-Forstall-ing” iOS and getting it ready in time for WWDC, not because it’s truly a better experience. 

Honestly (and I’ll probably be shunned for saying this), the new Weather app is a great example of an excellent design with a pleasant experience. It’s simple, can be used easily, makes sense, and just begs to be used for its visuals. And those backgrounds make them not entirely fl*t in design! ;)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-553&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/76f881f8cd63e66837aeb26023e9dd69?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/76f881f8cd63e66837aeb26023e9dd69?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/Niaccurshi&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Lee Griffin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-553&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:13:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:13pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It’s a tough one, Responsive Design is probably in the same sort of category, I’ve written in the past about how “responsive design” is made up of so many little micro design decisions that vary between implementations that it is ok to use the term even though it isn’t always used the way a purist may want it to be used (completely fluid layouts). In this light flat design has to be seen not as a comment on a design style but a set of design practices that culminate in an end product that resides in the aesthetic group we would call “flat design”.

I guess the problem with the prevalence of the “flat design” trend as a meme (which, let’s face it, is really what this is&amp;#8230;right?) is that it creates an atmosphere that draws an illusionary line between modern professional practice and out dated or unprofessional practice.

The use of the term flat design throughout our literature, magazines are big culprits when it comes to this, actually causes our industry harm. Even if people don’t think they’re doing it, there is a whole ethos that a certain “type” of design is the way things must look, otherwise you are just “not doing it right”. 

I don’t mind people using the term flat design so much as *how* or *why* they use it, I guess is what I’m trying to say.

The whole nonsense with iOS7 is quite funny in this respect because despite any of my personal opinions about it, if Metro was what spawned flat design then iOS7 is by no means a “flat design” solution. The UI world is not either skeumorphic or flat, as you say! If we want to attach a label then one that has been used among plenty of 3rd party android developers over the last couple of years for their UI apps seems more apt and semantically accurate&amp;#8230; minimalistic design.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-559&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cd134162a623773ac42743ed766d7c7c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cd134162a623773ac42743ed766d7c7c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://logopond.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;David Blanchet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-559&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-11T04:08:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;04:08am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        But who wants to say minimalistic when fl*t is shorter and faster and will get you winks from the geeks on their tablets at st*rbucks :D

btw I 100% agree with you.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-554&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f6254feda428f3aadb82a3ddafed2100?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f6254feda428f3aadb82a3ddafed2100?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.laceytechsolutions.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Lacey Tech Solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-554&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:17:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:17pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Talking in very general terms, I prefer an uncluttered interface that uses design elements (gradients, drop-shadow, text-shadow) sparingly.

Just because you have the ability to do something, doesn’t mean you have to. Design in its simplest form (usually) lends itself to uncomplicated user interfaces that are easy to use. Using simple blocks of tonal colour (like your site) looks nice, its simplistic but it lends itself to faster loading times, which always helps.

I’ve seen the iOS 7 interface and icons and whilst I like some aspects of the update I really don’t like some of their new icons. I think Apple lost their innovation with the death of Steve Jobs and now they’re copying what others are doing –; and that will only end in Apple losing everything that made them great.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-555&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1afdbe988a5cebfb1170503a9dc6ca8b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1afdbe988a5cebfb1170503a9dc6ca8b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Michael Hastrich&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-555&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T15:21:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:21pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Yes! You are totally right.

We have absolutely no idea how the designers at Apple got to their design decisions, so to simply dismiss this to following a trend is wrong is so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also one of the things I dislike about show-pretty-picture-sites like Dribbble.

Often we get no background information on the why and how for a design. No idea about the client it’s made for (if any client is involved in the first place), the brief or what so ever.&lt;/p&gt;
Like Aral wrote in his post, we can’t stress enough that design isn’t about pretty pictures. It’s about all things involved in a service or product.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-556&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0a4ec04fdcc7714ee306e26198b574a0?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0a4ec04fdcc7714ee306e26198b574a0?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://iainspad.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Iain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-556&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T19:05:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:05pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I think Flat is a bullshit term. It’s not a new thing, and I’m sick of it being seen as such. Metro is typography based, but inspired by the use of Type and Grids by the Swiss (if you’re a designer and have no idea on the Swiss Style, you REALLY need to be educated about this stuff), which was simple, and minimal. Flat is nothing more than that. The fact it has that word as if it’s a new thing really annoys me.

If you’re going &lt;strike&gt;flat&lt;/strike&gt; **minimal**, at least do it well, and put it good practice. I’m tired of everything “needing” to be flat, let alone the atheistic being more important than the objective. &lt;strike&gt;Fuck&lt;/strike&gt; the flat police.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-557&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ea2b2aef55fd5d08091e4c03b5adabce?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ea2b2aef55fd5d08091e4c03b5adabce?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://steveperrycreative.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Steve Perry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-557&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-14T08:54:34+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:54am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        A great post, Laura, and one that I have been considering myself, and for the same reasons.

Far too many think that a few minutes of subjection to videos of a user interface (of iOS7) qualifies them to over rule many months of painstaking design decisions that Apple have made over the last year or so, most of which will probably go totally un-noticed. Frankly it’s embarrassing to hear these people call themselves designers.

Everyone’s a critic when it comes to the visual elements of design but, as you mention above, that is only one small part of the whole.

Thanks for sharing, Laura.

Steve
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Ways: Design Systems</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 10:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about the design in ‘responsive’ design lately. &lt;a href=&#34;http://24ways.org/2012/design-systems/&#34;&gt;My post on 24ways&lt;/a&gt; is where I started to get some of my thoughts and ideas out. Here I talk about design systems and how thinking in this way, and basing our processes around this concept, can help us create more flexible future-proof responsive designs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>display: none;</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 08:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;or-the-things-you-think-are-common-knowledge-but-really-they-aren-t&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt; The things you think are common knowledge but really they aren’t.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shoptalkshow.com/episodes/040-with-laura-kalbag/&#34;&gt;I was on the ShopTalk show&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago, and a few people have asked me what I meant when I said “&lt;code&gt;display: none;&lt;/code&gt; naughties.” I foolishly thought that people would understand what I meant, (and I’ll come to that later) so I thought I’d better explain myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;display-none-in-responsive-web-design&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: none;&lt;/code&gt; in responsive web design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we’re &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/responsive-web-design&#34;&gt;changing out layouts based on viewport sizes, using media queries&lt;/a&gt;, we tend to switch page elements about a bit. We might make our images display one-on-top-of-the-other for narrower layouts, we might make our text super big to take advantage of bigger spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be a lot of content on one web page, and often there’s a temptation to hide some of it on narrower viewports. This walks hand-in-hand with the assumptions that narrow viewports are mobile devices and people using mobile devices are roving the planet using the web ‘on the go.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;assumptions&#34;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those assumptions are exactly that, you’re just &lt;em&gt;assuming&lt;/em&gt; that’s what the user is doing, you’re not basing that on real research or user testing. Why are you hiding so much of your content if you’re assuming it’s also useful to those browsing your site with a wider viewport?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;don-t-be-lazy&#34;&gt;Don’t be lazy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just hiding content is a lazy design solution. Yes, it’s hard designing for smaller screens, but maybe that will help you ensure that every little piece of content you’re putting on that site is worthwhile. Responsive design should be about rearranging, not changing, your page elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-then-you-re-actually-just-loading-it-anyway&#34;&gt;And then you’re actually just loading it anyway…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re putting content into your page, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; hiding it with CSS, it’s still there, it’s just not visible. So if you’re using this ‘technique’ across your site in numerous places, you’re likely taking a performance hit. And potentially, for narrower viewports/possible mobile devices, in the one place that a slow-loading page is likely to irritate a user. It’s just not worth that risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;changing-the-display-not-hiding-the-display&#34;&gt;Changing the display, not hiding the display&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution I’ve been using is changing the display of the content. It is a real problem that CSS can’t easily manipulate all types of content into a readable fashion on all devices. This is particularly true for navigation that needs to be displayed in a significantly different way, and often tables need to be reinterpreted into a more digestible format for narrow viewports. And in these cases, javascript can be your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mobile-first&#34;&gt;Mobile first&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always start mobile first, that’s not just in markup, it’s in content too. We don’t want to load up unnecessary HTML that creates performance problems, or javascript that may not working consistently on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’ve got a data table, and I think it would be better off displayed as a list of data, I would write the list of data into the HTML. This way it’ll load quickly, and those without javascript (or enough bandwidth to load javascript) will get a decent experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progressively-enhancing-with-javascript&#34;&gt;Progressively enhancing with javascript&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I would use media queries, or some kind of clever javascript, to load in the fancy content for particular viewport widths. I’ve done this to load in tables of data, replacing data lists, and also for navigation, replacing a vertical list of links with a show/hide button that reveals the menu when tapped (as on this site.) None of this requires &lt;code&gt;display: none;&lt;/code&gt;. No markup is wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;edit-accessibility&#34;&gt;[Edit]: Accessibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/SteveMarshall&#34;&gt;Steve Marshall&lt;/a&gt; has pointed out that there are also accessbility issues related to &lt;code&gt;display: none;&lt;/code&gt;. I didn’t want to cover too much in the post, but in case you want to know more about that too, I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/now-you-see-me/&#34;&gt;Aaron Gustafson’s ‘Now You See Me’ on A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://css-tricks.com/places-its-tempting-to-use-display-none-but-dont/&#34;&gt;Chris Coyier’s ‘Places It’s Tempting To Use Display: None; But Don’t on CSS Tricks&lt;/a&gt;. [/edit]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-about-markup&#34;&gt;Writing about markup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a little bit scared of writing about markup. I’m sure there are loads of front-end developers out there who know a huge amount more than me, and I’m worried I’ll get it wrong or make myself look stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also shy away from writing about the ‘easy’ stuff. This post about &lt;code&gt;display: none;&lt;/code&gt; is a fairly simple principle and I really don’t want to patronise anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;people-do-want-to-hear-about-the-simple-stuff&#34;&gt;People do want to hear about the ‘simple’ stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making these assumptions about it being a simple principle, and that everybody would know about it already, was daft. I was quickly proved wrong when people started asking me about it and then I realised how silly it was to think that we all have the same sources of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scattered-learning&#34;&gt;Scattered learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web is a big and varied place. To assume that someone else has read something just because you’ve read it is foolish. How do we learn about these resources? When do we all decide that we’re all going to read these particular sites and articles so that we’re all equally informed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even on Twitter, the resources we hear from, and learn from, are wildly different. We may follow completely different individuals and so the resources we learn from are curated by these individuals, and these may not ever crossover. Even if we do follow the same people on Twitter, noone can be expected to read every tweet, and inevitably you’ll miss some, and then you may not know about this other new thing that everybody else has been doing for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-i-get-to-the-point&#34;&gt;Where I get to the point…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point I’m trying to make is that we shouldn’t be fearful of writing about what we know. Even if you write from the most basic point of view, about something which has been ‘around for ages’, you’ll likely be saying something new to someone. They might be new to the industry, you might just be filling in the holes in someone’s knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week I have a revelation on app.net or Twitter where I wonder how I didn’t know about this old technique or tool before… but we can’t be expected to keep up with everything. I hope this post does that for some people. It’s good to share what we know. You needn’t be the first, you’ll just help if you’re the first that somebody finds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;63-comments&#34;&gt;63 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-350&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/18592fc8bad8f92136390f52303ee29c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://mrgwebdev.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Glover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-350&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T09:55:42+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:55am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks for blogging this Laura, that’s really cleared up the podcast for me. I wasn’t really convinced about starting with mobile first, but using javascript to turn the mobile markup into the desktop markup makes far more sense than using display: none; or, worse, using javascript to turn desktop markup into mobile.

Regarding what people know, I’ve been worrying about the same thing for ages and avoiding writing about things that seem simple to me. I concluded a little while ago that what I’ve learnt so far comes mostly from other people writing about things that seem simple to them. As you say, we all look at different parts of the internet, and not everyone has been doing this job for years. I’m a pretty experienced PHP developer, but I’m perhaps still a little behind the recent changes in frontend development. Other people are probably in the reverse position.

Keep blogging the simple stuff, there will always be someone who needs that piece of knowledge :-) P.S I’d be interested to read a post from you on semantic HTML sometime. I know it’s one of your things, and I feel like I could be doing it a lot better (I still div a lot).
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-351&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c083c7ffc86fab9e831990ad82033f99?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c083c7ffc86fab9e831990ad82033f99?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.jasonbradberry.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jason Bradberry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-351&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T10:12:25+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:12am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks, definitely a helpful post!

I’ve been working using a desktop first approach, and am considering switching to looking at ‘mobile’ first for my next project. One thing I’d like to hear more about – in the podcast you talked about loading content conditionally as browser window size is increased (using the example of the large illustration on the right hand side of your site). Can you recommend any good articles/links for further reading on this?
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-352&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/05a5dfd9e66b566bbb32091bb87ad202?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/05a5dfd9e66b566bbb32091bb87ad202?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://remy.bach.me.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rémy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-352&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T10:17:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:17am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        The last half of this article has really struck a chord with me. In the past, I’ve shelved so many potential blog posts because I think they’re too basic when they might actually have been useful to somebody.

There’s also a lot to be said for how easy something is to Google. Before posting on something, try doing a quick search for what you’re thinking of writing about. I think more often than not, you’ll find that what you want to post about either hasn’t been covered at all, is not visible enough using the search terms you used (which anyone else might easily have searched for as well), or you do it slightly differently. Either way, sharing even the smallest bit of knowledge only makes the web community stronger.

Thanks for the great thoughts (and inspiration) Laura!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-353&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/043af7a7ebf89595bebc3364f933d648?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/043af7a7ebf89595bebc3364f933d648?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Richard Lewis&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-353&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T10:26:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:26am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        very informative laura, no one should assume that everyone knows a certain piece of info. Something that I have learned though is if you have an image for example and display :none on that then yes it still renders, however if you wrap that element in a div and then display none on that parent element the img doesn’t actually load&amp;#8230; thought it may help
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-388&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5b4885089cdfebb57d760e46e6275ad2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5b4885089cdfebb57d760e46e6275ad2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://sarasoueidan.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Sara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-388&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T06:36:16+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;06:36am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        This is a great tip! thanks for mentioning it :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-395&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/565d2abdc8fc487b9cece74271a53d28?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/565d2abdc8fc487b9cece74271a53d28?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Jason&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-395&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T18:01:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:01pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I’d be cautious with this approach as from my testing the images still get loaded.

[http://jsfiddle.net/jlaeser/pCbav/](http://jsfiddle.net/jlaeser/pCbav/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)&lt;/p&gt;
This could potentially make for a larger initial page load.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-400&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c5bd15f36ca445f33618e7aa6ffe5019?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/c5bd15f36ca445f33618e7aa6ffe5019?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;James&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-400&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-06T15:37:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:37pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Yes I tested this also and it does indeed load. Shame though as this could have been an ideal solution.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-354&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/62f1c041b638db2c75f89405510c99ad?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/62f1c041b638db2c75f89405510c99ad?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://graphiceyedea.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Prisca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-354&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T10:42:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:42am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Laura :)

thanks for this post –; well explained :)

Also, just wanted to say that I agree: writing about what might simple is always a good idea. Teaching webdesign is changing all the time and there’s so much out there that it can be a tricky endeavour to point students to good resources. By now, I recommend people and high quality sites as good resources to follow ~ which essentially means that you writing about something simple will always have an audience, from students starting out with learning webdesign to the students of the web who we all are :)&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-355&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a9d07c20116fc86dfb522daaa1f0c923?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a9d07c20116fc86dfb522daaa1f0c923?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://ianwootten.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-355&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T14:26:26+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:26pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hold on. “display: none;” is naughty? In all situations?

Then you Laura, are very naughty. For that’s exactly how you display your top menu at lower resolutions, no?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-356&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-356&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T14:42:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:42pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Heh. Only in the form of a good old dropdown menu. So whilst `display: none;` is used to *temporarily* hide the sub navigation, it is visible on hover.

To be fair, I’m sure there are a lot of use cases where `display: none;` has its uses. As with every rule, there are always exceptions :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-357&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a9d07c20116fc86dfb522daaa1f0c923?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a9d07c20116fc86dfb522daaa1f0c923?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://ianwootten.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-357&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-06T14:57:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:57pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Well, actually at lower resolutions, both menus are only available on click :)

I agree there are many use cases –; but this isn’t what’s implied here. I actually believe for performant web apps, using “display:none;” and modifying markup through js absolutely essential.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-4&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-385&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/058848a8098693e62eff155692cecb1e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/058848a8098693e62eff155692cecb1e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Harry Mansworth&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-385&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-29T16:04:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:04pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Using display:none has other disadvantages. In the (rare) case that javascript has been turned off or the device has insufficient resources to run the script, using something like `$(&#39;#element&#39;).hide();` will ensure that, should JS be turned off the elements will still be visible. **Essential**for things like navigation!
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-358&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/153cbbe84fd0473ce666b479c52fb265?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/153cbbe84fd0473ce666b479c52fb265?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/crisgarner&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Cristian Garner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-358&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-07T16:37:13+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:37pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I don’t think she meant on all situations, display:none is a useful tool, if it were really bad no one would use it, I believe what Laura wants to explain is that it must be used only in what it is needed and to stop over using it.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-359&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8ea29219f41831044d8aba8c8dfb9309?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8ea29219f41831044d8aba8c8dfb9309?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Dean&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-359&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-07T20:45:29+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Most people in this industry seem to fear that they will be found out and ridiculed by those with more experience. I am thankful that there are some of those people who write blog posts, and put themselves in the ‘firing line’ for us unassured types to lap up. I’m yet to see the ridiculing of anybody though, and that’s another thing to be thankful for! :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-360&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/46c9d099a2dcb608f01b1eca5b07eb24?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/46c9d099a2dcb608f01b1eca5b07eb24?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-360&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-08T00:09:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:09am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nice article :)

Like Jason mentioned in the comments I too would like to hear more about how you approach using JS for conditionally loading content.

Cheers&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-362&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e1fb5c40b8e545b29fdf992b4cee083f?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e1fb5c40b8e545b29fdf992b4cee083f?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://ayoungh.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Anthony Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-362&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-08T21:43:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:43pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post :) Very encouraging for me as I want to start blogging about little bits like this, although I doubt it will be as good as yours! Keep up the great articles
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-364&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/766047c2f4d0bca639f03a66883197f6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/766047c2f4d0bca639f03a66883197f6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.markdixon.ca/design/blog/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mark Dixon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-364&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-09T22:58:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:58pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I agree. It is fine to write about web design and front-end stuff even if you are not an “expert”. I have recently launched my new portfolio website and have included a blog section where I plan on writing about web design.

While doing client work we straddle a lot of areas and cannot be expected to know everything about everything.

Mea Culpa –; on my first responsive design I did a fair amount of display:none.

Cheers from Montreal,

Mark&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-366&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/68fc10515bccdf73374acc9fd8eaef1c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/68fc10515bccdf73374acc9fd8eaef1c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://rockfishdigital.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;John Jacobsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-366&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-12T16:55:37+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:55pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Excellent post. Very applicable across design, dev, and content creation. Thanks!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-368&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/156af4791ccd0d858fd2f8aba677d527?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/156af4791ccd0d858fd2f8aba677d527?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://carlhallberg.se&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Carl Hallberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-368&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-13T09:46:14+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Love the part on ‘Scattered learning’! Very important insight that not many of us think of from day to day. I feel safe to say that i’m learning new stuff each and every day, even the most basic tech but also on completely different topics that in hindsight definitely could have been worth blogging about.

Great post!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-370&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf63dd177d3e9e747fa9541789477bec?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf63dd177d3e9e747fa9541789477bec?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://iloveresponsivedesign.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Fredrik Christensson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-370&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-14T08:27:34+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:27am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hey Laura, and thx for the post. I feel when we designing we dont get enough test time to see how the user are using the site. This is one of the biggest problems that I have encountered when iam design a responsive site.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-371&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2a2eb8e1cdf0a995320902d12a8c1580?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2a2eb8e1cdf0a995320902d12a8c1580?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Skweekah&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-371&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-14T23:29:06+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:29pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Very interesting article. I guess there’s always a better way of doing things, and if you can incorporate a little bit of better in each of the projects you are working on, you are challenging yourself and growing as a designer/developer.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-372&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6f9df81e888deeafc991848cccbec28a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6f9df81e888deeafc991848cccbec28a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://velonomad.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Tim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-372&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-15T20:51:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:51pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        How about a concrete example workaround?
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-374&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cf358ee0bbb2df4a67b5ba0445d3ff7b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cf358ee0bbb2df4a67b5ba0445d3ff7b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://lenanghai.net&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Hai Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-374&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-16T15:36:21+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:36pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks bro.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-377&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8041da1c6cb6f4ad87734737c89b742e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8041da1c6cb6f4ad87734737c89b742e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Søren Maarbjerg&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-377&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-20T00:46:06+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Thanks for your encouragement.

Hiding images by display none is a big issue, because they load anyway. The following research breaks the ice by documenting that “background images attached to elements that are inside a element with display none are NOT loaded”: [http://timkadlec.com/2012/04/media-query-asset-downloading-results](http://timkadlec.com/2012/04/media-query-asset-downloading-results&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)

Loading images with a common 1x1px src (because the attribute cannot be empty) AND inline styling its background-image to the ‘original’ src you are able to control the load by conditionally replacing the src with the background-image src – and showing the parent element. Only then will the image load.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-381&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ff99ca2faa838f3836ed90270486551e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ff99ca2faa838f3836ed90270486551e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Rob&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-381&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-22T22:57:23+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:57pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Good post, but I don’t see a concrete alternative solution here. An example would be beneficial.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-383&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8041da1c6cb6f4ad87734737c89b742e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8041da1c6cb6f4ad87734737c89b742e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Søren Maarbjerg&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-383&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-23T11:51:54+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:51am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks Rob. Please see my replied suggestion on how to avoid caching images for a slideshow if viewport &amp;lt; 480, on [http://timkadlec.com/2012/04/media-query-asset-downloading-results](http://timkadlec.com/2012/04/media-query-asset-downloading-results&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-384&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7b28ccde01ebe1b5f26ff4d1fac047d8?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7b28ccde01ebe1b5f26ff4d1fac047d8?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.daydesignz.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dayana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-384&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-27T16:45:47+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post, I always thought the same to myself about posting about things that should be “common knowledge” when indeed there can be several layers of knowledge to uncover. Loading mobile first is a great tip! Thanks for the post
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-386&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cabf735ce7b8b4471ef46ea54f71832d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cabf735ce7b8b4471ef46ea54f71832d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://player.fm&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Michael Mahemoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-386&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T03:46:30+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;03:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Very familiar with this issue as I’ve strived to do RWD without having to customise much of the server-side or the JS. And doing so means display: none; is almost a necessity.

In an upcoming iteration, I’ve resorted to using more Ajax requests with checks for the user-agent. It’s arguably more naughty than just “display: none;”, because now there’s a bit of JS coupled to the stylesheet, but since it improves performance, it’s a net gain.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-387&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9400cb5aeb155ccec614652542fd274d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9400cb5aeb155ccec614652542fd274d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://balupton.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Benjamin Lupton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-387&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T05:08:14+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;05:08am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        The last part raises a very interesting point, and is definitely something I find myself falling into a lot. Although, my train of thought feels that writing another blog post is just adding more noise to an already saturated library of good content –; if I figured it out already, then the answer is already there, what help does it do myself adding yet another article about it?

Perhaps the difference is how people get their learnings in the first place. A pre-supposition of this article appears that learning primarily occurs via blog posts and other forms of subscription based learning. I wonder how this mode of transport contrasts against learning when one encounters a problem then seeks an answer via google and stack overflow.

For instance, stack overflow is a fantastic place to ensure the content that is posted is of top notch quality, whereas with blog posts you do not have that guarantee that what you are reading is correct. However, with blog posts, you do get the subscription benefit.

Perhaps the solution to this dilemma is figuring out a way of combining stack exchange’s peer review and archival for searching abilities with blog posts careful curation, subscription and celebrity benefits.

Thoughts?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-390&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-390&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T07:19:44+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;07:19am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        While I think places like Stack Overflow are very useful and important, you really have to know the question that you want to ask. What if you just want to know tips and tricks?

I agree that me writing this on a blog doesn’t necessarily mean I’m right, or that I know what I’m talking about, but neither do I have that guarantee when I read blog posts written by other people. The ‘peer review’ element seems to come via social networks. If someone that I respect posts a link to a blog post, then they give that post credibility.

I think that learning on the web means we all need to doubt the credibility of what we read. We build up knowledge by reading a lot around these topics and then making judgments on what we choose to believe. These aren’t always black-and-white facts, there are a lot of grey areas where we rely on ‘opinion’ pieces to understand the ‘why’s to help us make more informed decisions about our work.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-389&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/07fcd228af02d476b1b8367d85a903b2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/07fcd228af02d476b1b8367d85a903b2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://christianheilmann.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Chris Heilmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-389&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T06:42:10+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;06:42am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Excellent points! What fascinates me more is that people are not taking advantage of matchmedia() enough –; it is the JS equivalent of mediaqueries. This means you can happily use the same query in CSS and JS to lazy-load content only when it is applicable. [https://hacks.mozilla.org/2012/06/using-window-matchmedia-to-do-media-queries-in-javascript/](https://hacks.mozilla.org/2012/06/using-window-matchmedia-to-do-media-queries-in-javascript/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-394&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/fbdbe8df04185d71dc5a16ee749ad3a6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/fbdbe8df04185d71dc5a16ee749ad3a6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://NoTwoTheSame.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Elliot Lewis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-394&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T17:22:21+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:22pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        That is a great little function. But I didn’t think it worked in IE? I’m sure I tried it before and ended up using work arounds to stop IE exploding at unknown function.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-391&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a2da1a6747c31ab1587c665eb9a44e15?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a2da1a6747c31ab1587c665eb9a44e15?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.maltonwebdesign.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dave Andrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-391&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T09:05:25+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:05am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great points Laura about sharing. IMO the more info the better. If think the more we share the more kudos you’ll gain and that respect may hopefully turn into business.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-393&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/326239aac4f69abe4dc5285f21d6b902?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/326239aac4f69abe4dc5285f21d6b902?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.feliciafortes.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Felicia Fortes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-393&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-10T16:31:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:31pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I like your thoughts and I’ve decided to share more of my newbie learnings.

I think every project has an individual path. For me blogging about things I’ve learnt during a project is a way to remember what I did  and at the same time being able to learn new stuff through the comments. &lt;/p&gt;
Just look at all the new knowledge coming through this blog posts comments.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-396&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2c22ec5e9ac5e4af3a5853fe2fd67e77?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2c22ec5e9ac5e4af3a5853fe2fd67e77?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://overthecounterdesign.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Chatman R.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-396&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-11T12:55:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:55pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I haven’t actually been using `display: none;` very often on its own. I’ve mainly used JavaScript to hide elements I manipulate through a situational `.hide` class. I’ve gotten into a habit of using temporary classes for states to applied through JavaScript. This way, if something effs up, I won’t be hiding critical information from the user. 

If I ever find I’m hiding an element indefinitely, it usually means it’s time to figure out if it’s needed at all. And I liked your last point over not being afraid to contribute something to the pool of knowledge. My reluctance to write blog posts comes from the fact that I’m entirely self-taught, so I have a tendency to assume everything I know IS common knowledge and I have nothing to add. I may have to rethink that.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-402&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/288f43b2e85b2451c08aa86f0e0453ad?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/288f43b2e85b2451c08aa86f0e0453ad?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.lockedowndesign.com/blog&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;John Locke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-402&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-09T09:26:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:26am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Best practices are made up of all these little bits of information that we collect from people we trust in web development, and we don’t always listen the first time we hear things. But when we keep seeing the same things written over and over, then those standards and best practices begin to take hold in our own workflows.

I’m always looking for better ways to do things on the front-end, to make things faster loading, or smoother for the user. 

Thanks for being one of the voices of reason and being a mentor to many in the web industry.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-404&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d064c247ddb15d88a42533a8e1fac72c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d064c247ddb15d88a42533a8e1fac72c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.catalystdesigns.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Paul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-404&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-07-21T18:04:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:04pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Really well written post! Was looking into the use of display none to hide some elements on a responsive design and you’ve persuaded me to think otherwise! 

An article on how to do the JavaScript side of things would be great! Thanks.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-7385&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/21d7459891f57c63e6eb51b4861ce752?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/21d7459891f57c63e6eb51b4861ce752?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.kintoweb.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Kintoweb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-7385&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-01-11T01:48:16+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;01:48am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It may be also possible to use iFrame and display:none on that to stop data downloading
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-33064&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58ec733e2356433d0ec9af50ef904adb?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58ec733e2356433d0ec9af50ef904adb?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.elmnt.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Greg Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-33064&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-18T00:38:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:38am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“I’m a little bit scared of writing about markup. I’m sure there are loads of front-end developers out there who know a huge amount more than me, and I’m worried I’ll get it wrong or make myself look stupid.”

I bet most people feel the same way, so don’t worry. I’ve been designing &amp;amp; (front-end) coding for more than 10 years, and I still read about &amp;amp; play with the fundamentals all the time. I think it’s always important to keep re-visiting the basics, not just the very difficult stuff. Well done. Keep up the great work!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-37332&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/54729a3423ebee623690bfc0c4edfa58?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/54729a3423ebee623690bfc0c4edfa58?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://blog.ki6i.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Kalina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-37332&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-07-09T13:45:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Most browsers like Chrome and Firefox doesn’t actually spend time on the display none content on page load. In other words the load time it about the same as if the content isn’t there.The only browsers that have this issues are IE&amp;lt;11
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-150438&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/93c1dd2037e7b96a0fcdffb20cb82bf4?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/93c1dd2037e7b96a0fcdffb20cb82bf4?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://korosheh.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;korosheh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-150438&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-09-19T21:13:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:13pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Is nice article thanks
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let the technical processes of web development stifle your imagination</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new post from me, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netmagazine.com/opinions/keep-it-creative&#34; title=&#34;Keep it Creative! by Laura Kalbag on .net magazine&#34;&gt;this time at .net magazine. Keep it creative!&lt;/a&gt; There’s some pretty cool comments over there too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will understanding the mainstream affect me as a designer?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 21:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been contemplating how designers can identify better with more mainstream users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a thought last week. What if, by rejecting Facebook, I’m actually missing out on design patterns that are so influential on the mainstream user that it affects their perception on the rest of the web?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the same goes for Google Chrome. I’ve been going through a rebellious anti-Google phase, but now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/5/21/3033566/chrome-most-popular-browser-weekly-may-2012&#34;&gt;Chrome has taken over as the world’s most popular browser&lt;/a&gt;, am I making life harder for myself by developing sites in Safari first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers (and in the creative and tech industries generally) I think we might err on the side of the hipster. We can start to reject brands and products because we’re “too cool for that mainstream stuff the average user falls for…” Or maybe we’re just acutely aware of the downsides, hitches and ill-intentions web services might have because we work in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could it be positive that we arrive at mainstream products, when we need to do research, with the fresh eye of a new user? Or are we tainted by the fact we know too much? We could be saving ourselves from being inspired by standards and conventions that might be poor, but are we better informed for knowing as many potential solutions to common problems as possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I think I’m going to try being more of a mainstream user. I want to understand the web better as other people see it. I’m switching to Google Chrome for now, and I’ve signed up to Facebook again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-d-say-i-ll-post-in-a-month-s-time-and-write-about-whether-i-ve-noticed-a-change-but-i-m-not-sure-it-ll-be-as-conscious-as-that-we-ll-have-to-wait-and-see&#34;&gt;I’d say I’ll post in a month’s time and write about whether I’ve noticed a change, but I’m not sure it’ll be as conscious as that. We’ll have to wait and see…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: throughout this post I keep saying ‘mainstream.’ This is because I feel that ‘average’ or ‘normal’ aren’t really the right words. I’m trying to talk about that majority of users who are consumers, rather than makers or builders, of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-comments&#34;&gt;13 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-268&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8bff715a965594c68c993ca957036af?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8bff715a965594c68c993ca957036af?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://welcomebrand.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;James Young (@welcomebrand)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-268&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-01T21:59:23+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:59pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It’s something I do with ads ([http://www.welcomebrand.co.uk/thoughts/browsing-an-uglier-web-on-purpose/](http://www.welcomebrand.co.uk/thoughts/browsing-an-uglier-web-on-purpose/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)) and I do recommend everyone do it from time to time for the reasons you mention. 

As designers, we’re a million miles away from how many “average” users operate on the net and if you work on any sort of larger scale projects and get the change to watch video tests of users it’ll open your eyes just how differently they use the web. 

It’s also worth reminding mac toting designers everywhere to check what their work looks like on a windows machine, you’d be amazed how many sites (designers portfolios in particular) I see on daily basis that are unreadable due to the differences in font rendering etc. 

J.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-269&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-269&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-01T22:00:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:00pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        That’s a great post, and totally the same way of thinking.

You’re right about Windows. I always test on Windows, but probably not taking as much into account as I should. I tend to look for broken things rather than beautiful things.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-270&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/75ff01d3954ec930eb94da10d49c1182?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/75ff01d3954ec930eb94da10d49c1182?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Gulben&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-270&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-01T23:09:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:09pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’m very much interested hearing about your adventure. I can’t seem to get out of my anti-Google phase :-)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-273&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-273&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-02T22:56:36+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:56pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Oh I still won’t touch Gmail with a barge pole, don’t get me wrong ;-)
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-271&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576951f66442b28f0dded221a59af51c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576951f66442b28f0dded221a59af51c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.100yen.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jonic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-271&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-02T14:33:16+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:33pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        That’s a very good point. I’ve avoided Google+ because I don’t need it in my life, but perhaps I should take another look.

Incidentally, I’ve just started using a Windows phone (won it at Reasons to be Appy). It’s probably going to be beneficial to me to simply use something that isn’t iOS for a little while, although when I can get my company phone I’ll be getting an iPhone :)

But yeah, I think we could do more to be less immediately dismissive of certain things. I’ve avoided Pinterest because it looks a bit like a Tumblr clone, and I already have one of those. Maybe I should have a look since it’s important to just see what’s currently going on in modern site/app design.

Bit of a crap comment, that. I haven’t properly woken up, give me a break!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-272&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-272&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-02T22:56:13+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:56pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        No it’s a great comment, don’t be daft! That’s a good point about Google+ and Pinterest too, but now I’m starting to wonder where it stops. If we’re using everything, can we be paying attention to many things?
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-279&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60f3dac07f59d6fc7987de8227d401c5?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60f3dac07f59d6fc7987de8227d401c5?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://rhcedan.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dan Woods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-279&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T21:43:34+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:43pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @jonic In my opinion, Microsoft really nailed it with Windows Mobile. They have taken a simpler-is-better approach to their UI which has finally made it something that is user friendly and downright interesting to use. I’m not a Windows user in the real world, but I’ve already taken some inspiration from their mobile platform for UI.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-274&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/88581226705b3a5daf9d92c2c385ffe9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/88581226705b3a5daf9d92c2c385ffe9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.katywatkins.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Katy Watkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-274&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-03T00:24:40+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:24am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post! I worry about this as well, trying to find a balance between what I want to use and what everyone in the world seems to be using.  My initial reason for joining Twitter was just to understand what the rest of the world was doing, but I’m avoiding Pintrest because I can’t afford another time-suck, and I don’t see a real need for it in my life. And I have an Android phone instead of an iPhone because I want to know how “the other half” lives. 

But, I feel like a general awareness of other technologies we don’t personally use can often be enough&amp;#8230; as long as you know it exists, there’s always the opportunity to find and talk to someone who does use it.

On an unrelated note, tell me more about your Gmail hatred! Is it because it’s Google, or the service itself? And can I ask what you use instead? I’m trying to wean myself off it, but it’s proving difficult.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-278&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-278&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T20:13:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:13pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I find Gmail a bit odd, but I think it has improved recently. It’s Google themselves, I don’t like the idea of being the product, and I just get this overwhelming creepy feeling from them that it’s not in our favour to be used like this…
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-275&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/610872f5af82d0230363a54fcb0ec4fe?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/610872f5af82d0230363a54fcb0ec4fe?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://futureinsights.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Davin Wilfrid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-275&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T16:42:21+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:42pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post, Laura. I signed up for Google + when it was first announced, then ditched it for about a year. Only recently have I started looking into it again, and only because of the business reasons (SEO nonsense, etc). I’m glad I did, because I think it could be a smarter, more engaging version of Facebook if everyone gave it a chance. I’m now embarrassed for “erring on the side of hipsters” and being so dismissive for so long.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-276&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f75d304a5c933876749f710fce9c5702?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f75d304a5c933876749f710fce9c5702?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://shinytoyrobots.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Robin Cannon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-276&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T17:30:15+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:30pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Good to see such a self-aware post.

It’s definitely true that designers and front-end developers interact with the web in a very different way from the “average” user. We’re certainly likely to be more informed, quicker to pick up on new trends and products. And, yes, often frustratingly hipster-ish in our ability to avoid things that are mainstream.

But you’re absolutely right that to continue to simply behave in that way isn’t the most productive way to go about things. Except in the most specialized or niche projects, we’re all designing and developing for the average user. We need to be aware of that benchmark, and how best to address it.

Certainly we can still try to push the boundaries while acknowledging the mainstream. That’s what the most successful products and services do. So many great successes occurred not because of market research and addressing a need or desire, but by making a cool product which *created* a market demand. That requires an understanding of the mainstream, definitely, but it also involves a desire not merely to remain generic.

That’s the balance I want to keep. So much web design is self-referential and generic, and that’s bad. But understanding what works for the mainstream audience is vital in terms of pushing the boundaries in an effective way.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-277&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e59258d1478e4148bb8dfec35f7b4ddc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e59258d1478e4148bb8dfec35f7b4ddc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://designbyjake.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jake Giltsoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-277&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T18:29:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:29pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Nice and well thought out post.

One of the biggest things I’ve learnt as a design student, is that its all well and good following trends and being hipster as such, however at the end of the day as designers we need to primarily design for non-designers. 

Obviously its more than okay to put in extra things that only people with a certain eye will pick out, typographic niceties and such like. But it’s all to easy to forget that the average user of the end product may well have a slowish computer, run windows and mainly use the internet for Facebook. Design decisions definitely need to be informed by these ‘mainstream’ scenarios.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-280&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/549895c46a63bec3b6fb804ca6d2c6da?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/549895c46a63bec3b6fb804ca6d2c6da?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://hickox.org&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;David Hickox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-280&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-06-05T21:51:48+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:51pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Took me a while to learn this one myself.  It’s our job to be well-versed in the norm in spite of the preferences we develop as experts.  If we want to pull experiences in new and exciting directions, we need to know what the average case is in order for that direction to make sense.  The real magic is when you can make well-designed experiences effortless and intuitive, almost invisible.  It takes knowing the environment of the norm to do that.  

It’s like when you go back and watch a really good kids show and realize how much they put in to satisfy the adults that would also have to watch.  In a way, our craft is like creating that kids show.  In order to do it well, you have to know the psychology of children and how to appeal to them.  And web literacy is still in its infancy.  So we have to create for that environment, but with the depth and experience that we hold as specialists.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critiques, giving and receiving useful feedback</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, a couple of days before &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/markboulton/status/200509667384885250 &amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;Theory: Web designers lack the ability (through practice and traditional schooling&#34;&gt;Mark Boulton said&lt;/a&gt; to critique design effectively.&amp;quot; says Mark Boulton on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markboulton.co.uk/journal/comments/its-not-working-for-me-crit&#34; title=&#34;It’s Not Working For Me by Mark Boulton&#34;&gt;wrote his piece on design critiques&lt;/a&gt;, I’d been thinking about that same topic. I’ve been struggling through an iPhone app icon design, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/laurakalbag/status/199846580407377921 &amp;quot;&amp;amp;quot;2&#34;&gt;had asked Twitter for help.&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve got an app icon design that needs some criticism as I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of it. Anyone free to give me some time via email today?&amp;quot; by Laura Kalbag on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) Knowing that the 160 character limit wasn’t going to help me much, I emailed everyone who offered me assistance and sat back waiting for the criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t expecting in-depth critique. I wasn’t quite sure where I was going wrong, and some gut reactions on what might be the problem was the kind of feedback I really wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was surprised to receive was quite a few responses just telling me exactly what to do. This wasn’t ‘feedback’, it was direction. There is a great difference between someone asking ‘why’ and someone asking ‘how’. Design critiques aim to give the receiver a wider understanding of their work, and design in general, there really are no magic rules in design whereby you follow them and your project becomes an instant ‘success.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-encouraged-poor-feedback&#34;&gt;How I encouraged poor feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A critique isn’t all in what the other side says to you. In order to allow the ‘giver’ to deliver useful feedback, you need to explain the context of the work. Very rarely does design work stand without requiring any explanation. The more the giver understands about your work, the greater insight they are likely to give you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are numerous elements that may have affected your outcome and will need explaining to the giver so that they might understand your decisions (and these are just a few!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your task as a designer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your role within the team (if any)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what you aim to achieve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, when presenting your work it may help to give your justification behind the design of particular elements that stand out. If you think someone is likely to comment on it, and you can see the problem, then explain it so that people can help you with that problem rather than just telling you something you already know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean start with a load of excuses! Often I’m inclined to say “the client told me to do this, and I don’t really want to argue with them…” which is really an excuse for me not standing up for my design work or my principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;giving-useful-feedback&#34;&gt;Giving useful feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most important when giving useful feedback is trying to understand the context of the project. It’s ok to ask questions before giving any advice! If someone has asked for your opinion, then they are likely to value it, but this does not mean that you should blindly give feedback without understanding the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is the designer’s project. They may be sharing their work with you, but they ask for feedback in the hope of understanding better how to improve their work, not to be told what to do. The key to this is really trying to concentrate on understanding the problems together as best you possibly can, rather than offering quick solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However this doesn’t mean that it’s bad to help the designer with ideas. Try to give examples to help illustrate potential solutions, but always back these up with rationalisation, and the reason &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; you think this would work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always be honest, but polite. Egos are no use in critiques, but you don’t want to upset people. Those cruel art school scenarios may be good for destroying the ego that is overly protective of their work, but in a working situation we’re not out to hurt each other. If you find it difficult to honestly convey negative opinions, for fear of hurting a sensitive person, try sandwiching the negative between positive feedback. Negative feedback is definitely more useful, but it can be heartening for a struggling designer to hear the elements of their work that are successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;receiving-feedback&#34;&gt;Receiving feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen listen listen. Forget that ego in the back of your mind that is automatically coming up with defensive excuses and try to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the experience. People are taking the time to help you, it is only polite to listen to what they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note of everything they tell you, even if you don’t understand it or think it is right. You may come to understand later, and it’s not necessarily the comment that is useful, but the interpretation of your work that helps you understand how potential users may see your designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you keep getting the same comments over and over again, don’t dismiss the additional comments as unhelpful. One person may have further insight, and the fact that so many people are reinforcing the same point should really hammer home any improvements you need to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-having-an-art-education-isn-t-the-end-of-the-world&#34;&gt;Not having an art education isn’t the end of the world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know me, then chances are you’ll have heard me rant about my experiences in formal art/design education. Needless to say, it isn’t always a positive way to start your design career, and I fear it is often a source of snobbery in the design/web design industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of education may give people a head-start in critiques because they’ve taken part before, but that really is the only head-start. How does anyone get experience asides from trying something for themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/wrightmartin/status/200604612074536960&#34; title=&#34;&amp;amp;quot;You know what would be good? #crit meet ups. Bring some work, get some feedback from other designers. Oh yeah and beer.&amp;amp;quot; by Martin Wright on Twitter&#34;&gt;Martin’s idea of meeting up for group critiques&lt;/a&gt;. I think it would be something that could benefit a lot of designers if we do it regularly, and get an opportunity to understand each other and our ways of working better. So if anyone is local-ish to the Surrey area (and I’m willing to travel for this kind of interaction!) please let me know. For those of us who are also frequent conference attendees, maybe we should have post-conference crits together?! Let’s get on with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-262&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8789741e8476e1b3b7b7e80e89cddf9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8789741e8476e1b3b7b7e80e89cddf9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kimberleytew.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Kim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-262&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-05-20T22:10:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:10pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’ve been thinking about this since Mark’s talk too. I’d be up for a meetup group to critique work, although I don’t do much design at the moment, but I do work as a usability consultant so I guess I critique people’s work everyday! I’ve been having occasional thoughts about an online critiquing platform for a while since somebody on an e-campaigning list I subscribe to mentioned it but with the focus on critiquing digital campaigns. I started scribbling down more ideas on this during Mark’s talk. What do you think of a website where people could submit designs and ask for honest feedback? I’ve seen people do it on other forums, but nothing specific. Would you use such a site? (and maybe be interested in a little collaboration project on it :) )
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labels in input fields aren’t such a good idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/labels-in-input-fields-arent-such-a-good-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 17:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/labels-in-input-fields-arent-such-a-good-idea/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There’s something that’s been bothering me lately. It seems to be some kind of form interface trend where the labels for text inputs are placed inside the fields themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-full wp-image-422 alignleft&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-16.48.49.png&#34; alt=&#34;a form field where the label is shown inside the text input field&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-might-be-some-pros&#34;&gt;There might be some pros&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, this makes an interface slicker. It saves space where you’d usually have a label, then some padding, then the input field and probably a load of padding around the lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what you’re gaining in a clean look, you’re completely losing through a total lack of usability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-i-m-an-interface-idiot&#34;&gt;So, I’m an interface idiot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know the lowest common denominator, idiot users that we design easy interfaces for? The ones that need to be led by the hand, step by step, across your design to get to the call-to-action?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s me, that is. I am an incredibly naïve user. I skim read, I’m forgetful, I barely pay attention and when I do I’m easily confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-what-i-see&#34;&gt;This is what I see&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example from a site that is otherwise a shimmering beacon of awesomeness over the wasteland that is the web:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-noah&#34;&gt;Project Noah&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Project Noah, you upload photos of nature. The aim is to identify the creature or plant in your photo, and part of that is providing the relevant links to that species’ page on Wikipedia and the Encyclopedia of Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://projectnoah.org&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-423&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-16.55.42.png&#34; alt=&#34;Reference URLs on Project Noah, where the label is shown inside the text input&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;It’s a beautiful interface, but I have an issue. I’ll go and paste in a URL, then I’ll select the other text box:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-424&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-16.59.40.png&#34; alt=&#34;Reference URL input on Project Noah, where one URL input is filled in and the other is focused but empty&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

Then I have this thought:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I put the URL in the right box? Is Encyclopedia of Life the top input or the bottom input? How do I find out?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems pedantic, but I &lt;em&gt;genuinely do&lt;/em&gt; get this sense of panic that I’m entering it wrong and there’s no way to check that I’m doing it right. I have to click back outside the input box, so it no longer has focus, to check what the label was again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example from an interface that I use on a regular basis and generally love. In the 2.8 redesign of the WordPress admin, which is generally a huge amount better than before, the post editor title lost it’s label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-425&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-1-960x617.png&#34; alt=&#34;WordPress 2.7 post editor&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

After:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-429&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-17.19.17-960x624.png&#34; alt=&#34;WordPress 3.1 post editor&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the first input box you’ll click into is the top title input. It actually auto-focuses, and some clever script means that it puts the label back in after the auto-focus, but then the second you start typing you’ve lost that label. If you start typing, then backspace because you made a mistake, you’ve lost that label:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-431&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-17.18.48.png&#34; alt=&#34;WordPress 3.1 post editor with no title label&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;designers-often-make-assumptions&#34;&gt;Designers often make assumptions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all very well to assume that the user will remember that the title belongs in that box, but what if it’s somebody has cognitive difficulties? What if it’s someone that’s just an idiot like me who clicks into boxes without paying attention to the label first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-started-as-an-example&#34;&gt;It started as an example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally we used pre-entered text in an input field as an example, to help users understand the input required. WordPress itself has a great example of this on the Writing Settings page in the WordPress admin:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-433&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-17.30.53.png&#34; alt=&#34;WordPress Writing Settings uses text inside input boxes to help users understand the input required&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These fantastic triggers mean that users who aren’t necessary technically minded can see the type of input that’s required to set up post via email, match that to the information they have and easily enter it into the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When did these useful triggers become a way to hinder users, instead of help them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-the-html5-placeholder-leaves-room-for-abuse&#34;&gt;The rise of the HTML5 placeholder leaves room for abuse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML5 has a fantastic new form input attribute for adding placeholder information into the input boxes so that you can easily give your users cues without the need for JavaScript or CSS hacks:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-434&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-17.38.39.png&#34; alt=&#34;HTML5 form snippet&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; “*name*” should actually be “*id*” here in the text input, I always get those two mixed up! (Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/labels-in-input-fields-arent-such-a-good-idea/#comment-2794&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt;, for the heads up)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-full wp-image-435 aligncenter&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/05/Screen-shot-2011-05-27-at-17.39.00.png&#34; alt=&#34;HTML5 form preview&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		I’m concerned that people will misuse or misunderstand the placeholder attribute as a way to replace form labels
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But it’s not the same thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A label tells you what a form input requires, a placeholder gives you an example of the input required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no accessibility expert, but I can imagine the loss of a label isn’t going to help with screen readers. Forgetful people and people with cognitive disabilities will also struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-think-of-daft-people-like-me&#34;&gt;Please think of daft people like me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might beautify your interface and make you look modern and cool, but a label isn’t the same as a prompt. We need to keep our forms as clear as possible and not let cool technology take over the understanding of basic user behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if I’m alone in struggling with using these inputs, but I’d love to know everybody else’s opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;48-comments&#34;&gt;48 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-200&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2d65a81054bdc80fc05dc74f2740b4c9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2d65a81054bdc80fc05dc74f2740b4c9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://dbushell.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;David Bushell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-200&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T18:06:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:06pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post Laura! I’ve experimented with placeholders instead of labels but any aesthetic gain is totally lost in usability. I have exactly the same problems you’ve highlighted. If us web designers/developers can’t handle it –; what about everyone else? I say use both labels and placeholders.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-221&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3394cf25ac096698c680916a3c6cf336?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3394cf25ac096698c680916a3c6cf336?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://meteoracle.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Westley Knight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-221&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-14T10:16:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:16am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I agree that the use of both labels and placeholders is the way to go. If you are going to drop one, it should be the placeholder and the label should be more descriptive. But ALWAYS have a label. And don’t forget the ‘for’ attribute.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-201&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f202503f0ea3118e596f40fdaf8fb3f8?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f202503f0ea3118e596f40fdaf8fb3f8?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.cliffpro.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Cliff Huizenga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-201&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T18:30:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:30pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I’m definitely on the camp of using both labels and placeholders, but not placeholders by themselves. I recently tried manipulating a search field on my blog to remove the search button and place the word “Search” as a label inside the field. While it looked clean, it was confusing as to what it was after you click inside the box, and it wasn’t obvious how to send the search query (mainly because…well, there was no longer a search button). 

Not everything is obvious to everyone. Even though the design *could* look nicer without labels, a true designer will find a way to make them work visually.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-202&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9be8367907d042cb538af6697549e47e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9be8367907d042cb538af6697549e47e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/markedup&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Pete Fairhurst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-202&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T21:05:18+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:05pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        As an Interaction Designer, I’ve been tackling and retackling this very problem in my forms for a while now.

The current solution to the “activated, anonymous” problem involves standard HTML features, with a dash of jQuery to smarten things up.

&lt;p&gt;1. Layout your form with paired label and input combinations as normal.

2. Use a safe offscreening technique on your labels to maintain accessibility and satisfy your visual requirements.

3. Add the label text to each input as a ‘title’.

4. Add a class of “hint” to each input.

5. Use a bit of jQuery that, on load:

a) sets the “value” of all your “hint” inputs to their title text,

b) adds a class of “hinted” for that light grey text effect,

c) set the “focus” event to remove the “hinted” class and clear the “value” *if* it’s the same as the title on focus,

d) set the “blur” event to reinstate both the “hinted” class and the “title” as value *only* if the value is empty.&lt;/p&gt;
It’s a little bit of faff, but I think it’s worth it for the experience benefits. If your user mouses over an input, they’ll get a tool tip (because of the title). And if they click out of the input without entering anything, they’ll get the hint back again.

And, for an added nicety, you could set a corresponding icon as a background on each input on focus, too –; particularly effective if you need to have several hinted fields close together.

Anyway, hope some of all that is of use. :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-203&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9be8367907d042cb538af6697549e47e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9be8367907d042cb538af6697549e47e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/markedup&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Pete Fairhurst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-203&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T21:14:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:14pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Oh, and one final step!

6. When your form submits, make sure you empty every “hint” input if its value matches its title; otherwise you may cock up any validation you might otherwise have on your form.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-205&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-205&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T22:21:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:21pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks Pete, that’s brilliant. Definitely something I’ll think of using in the future!
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-204&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://zed1.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mike Little&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-204&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-27T22:15:42+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:15pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hi Laura,

I’m passionate about accessibility and usability, and I agree completely; this trend for ultra clean interfaces is causing problems for people who might struggle with this thing called the web.&lt;/p&gt;
These days some of the newest users are those who have been reluctant to do this “internet thing” because it is “complicated and scary”. We shouldn’t be making it any harder than it is. There is huge value in keeping things familiar, especially when it requires non-trivial interaction from the user.

Thanks for raising the subject, it’s important not to forget the user in the pursuit for beauty!

Mike
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-206&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3785543bade130b2613346d12de80dfc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3785543bade130b2613346d12de80dfc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.cvwdesign.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Clive Walker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-206&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-05-28T10:20:21+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:20am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        In these cases, using the title attribute on input fields helps (in a small way) since that is seen on hover. Quite simple to do but not always done (I admit I forget sometimes!)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-207&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://laurakalbag.wpengine.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-207&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-01T17:12:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:12pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        You’re right! I don’t think I ever knew that. Definitely helps the usability of the form if the user holds their mouse over for long enough.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-209&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://zed1.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mike Little&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-209&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-01T17:36:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:36pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It will also be read out for those using screen readers.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-233&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7aa2f48d088eb88d5c65e203cbc5f24c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7aa2f48d088eb88d5c65e203cbc5f24c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://irresponsibleart.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jer Brand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-233&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-20T19:11:24+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:11pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I used to think this as well, however the guys at WebAIM schooled me: Reading of the title attribute is OPTIONAL and can be turned off entirely in most app’s settings. You can’t depend on it.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-208&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4279716d19699a421a5ad1d532fc9a08?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://zed1.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mike Little&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-208&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-01T17:34:28+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:34pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        By the way, the HTML5 example has an error. 

The `for` attribute of the `label` can only take an `id` as a value. But the corresponding `input` doesn’t have an `id`. See the [HTML5 specification](http://www.w3.org/TR/html5/forms.html#attr-label-for&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow).
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-210&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://laurakalbag.wpengine.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-210&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-01T17:38:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:38pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Yes! I realised this when I wrote out a massive form with every single input using `name=` instead of `id=`. Always get those two mixed up :s
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-225&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e6a042553edc475cda59f8f62df2a86c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e6a042553edc475cda59f8f62df2a86c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;dotnetCarpenter&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-225&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-18T02:49:23+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;02:49am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Someone noted on some website that I forgot, but it’s pretty damn useful. Put your &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; inside your &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; and use don’t have to specify &lt;b&gt;for=”[id of input]”&lt;/b&gt;. And never have to remember the difference between name and id. Except that the server guy receiving the form data will appreciate you and give you coffee if you have sane &lt;b&gt;name&lt;/b&gt; properties.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-211&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ded01cdab114abe4ec13511e4c25b9bb?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ded01cdab114abe4ec13511e4c25b9bb?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://andyhume.net&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Andy Hume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-211&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-04T23:37:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:37pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Good post –; and I agree! There’s a worrying trend of people conflating label and placeholder, and an even more worrying one of people thinking that having placeholder text is in any way a replacement for a label *element*.

I checked the WordPress example you mentioned, and they do include the input element which is good. In fact it looks like quite a clever implementation. The label element is actually absolutely positioned on top of the text input, rather than text written to the input’s value property. Then when you click on the label it focuses you into the input.

Having said that it looks like they handle the no JavaScript situation less well. The label element is hidden and there is no visual hint as to what the field is for at all. I tried it with Voice Over switched on and it does read the label for the title input which is good, but then there is no label at all associated with the textarea for the body of the post, and the screen reader is completely lost.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-212&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/32e397a45f37a7102f5bd8c8eff54112?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/32e397a45f37a7102f5bd8c8eff54112?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Mats Svensson&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-212&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-02-16T15:15:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:15pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Putting help-texts or labels INSIDE the texfields,

either with HTML5 placeholder, or some hack,

 is F useless and should NEVER be used.&lt;/p&gt;
I have never EVER ever seen it done in a way that doesn’t break when you fill a field by drag&amp;amp;drop.

&lt;p&gt;Example:

The help text in the field says “Name”.

You select the text “Smith” somewhere and drag it and drop it in the field.

It now says “NaSmithme” or similar.&lt;/p&gt;
I guess you could build something that makes the field transparent , puts the help-text under (lower z-index), and then hides the help-text  when the user start to fill it out.

&lt;p&gt;But NEVER actually put the help-text inside the field itself, like its always done now .

This madness must be stopped!&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-213&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/be750826c14d16592d7f44fa8f952990?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/be750826c14d16592d7f44fa8f952990?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.belron.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Craig Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-213&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-03-19T07:38:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;07:38am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi,

One other thing missing is the ‘affordance’ of the field –; during scanning behaviour.

For example, adding text into a search box simply makes it less visible on the screen so you’re hobbling your interface discoverability.   

We’ve found the best balance is out of field help text –; supporting but not interfering with people’s ability to evaluate the size, information required and type from the input box itself (seen in eye tracking + see [http://www.lukew.com](http://www.lukew.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow) work).

I think that if you test this stuff, you’ll find all sorts of problems.  Visual clarity in the designers eyes does not translate to usability or conversion in a product –; this stuff often looks nice and clever but can suffer from interrupting already known patterns for using an interface that people look for (e.g. an empty bloody box, not something filled with text).

I had a similar discussion regarding phone formatting recently –; splitting it all into nice little boxes for USA phone numbers looks pretty but imposes work and friction on the viewer –; regardless of your design intentions.  In that case, lots of  clicks and eye focus work would have been imposed on the user, even though it looked ‘nice’.

C.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-216&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/05a5dfd9e66b566bbb32091bb87ad202?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/05a5dfd9e66b566bbb32091bb87ad202?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://remy.bach.me.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rémy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-216&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-12T18:35:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:35pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I totally agree with your POV here. It’s the whole reason I made this jQuery plugin! [https://github.com/remybach/jQuery.superLabels](https://github.com/remybach/jQuery.superLabels&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-217&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/94434f1e43403f5c1bf620565f0027cb?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/94434f1e43403f5c1bf620565f0027cb?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.goodsignal.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Blair Keen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-217&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-13T14:23:14+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:23pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

Great post.  I’d be interested to hear what your point of view would be regarding the use of tool tips to display the form label in the event that the placeholder label is either replaced with input text or removed as in your WordPress example?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-218&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/666570c00e7598fbf0090bf4f76f860e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/666570c00e7598fbf0090bf4f76f860e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Stomme poes&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-218&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-04-14T09:21:38+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:21am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hi Blair,

you also mean this tooltip is available to keyboarders using CSS or JS (in the case of IE and similar)?&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-219&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2366090ac3624ea0bbb7e9c04ae5b2da?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2366090ac3624ea0bbb7e9c04ae5b2da?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://koenahn.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Koen Ahn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-219&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-11-30T22:39:26+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:39pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Excellent article!

Forms are always a struggle. I’ll keep this in mind when making one.

Thank you :)&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-220&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a1a15f489279744da38547e1a8d8ae19?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a1a15f489279744da38547e1a8d8ae19?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://danmalarkey.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dan Malarkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-220&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-13T17:30:19+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:30pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great article! “Web Form Design” by Luke Wroblewski goes over many of these exact examples!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-222&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f85dd90f263cc1d9a86a727fb26c21dc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/f85dd90f263cc1d9a86a727fb26c21dc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.artsocket.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dmitri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-222&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-17T22:57:57+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:57pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Sorry guys I just didn’t have time to read all the comments to post mine, so my apologies if it’s a repost of someone else’s idea.

&lt;p&gt;I think this is a review of unfinished or undersigned examples. Or they are just buggy, and those bugs are the problem, not the design. Here’s why:
* When I focus on the field, this should not make the label go away, the label should go away only when I start typing.

*After not entering any text in that field and removing the focus, the label would remain, according to the above. Thus confusion cleared.

*This design will obviously be not a good idea where all the fields look the same and there are plenty of them. It works best on login forms, where you can save some space and make people feel great about using your app.&lt;/p&gt;
To sum it up, if the bugs are fixed and this concept is not over abused, it is a good idea :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-234&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/87a9c125448afeb9108a8b8cf56fd658?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/87a9c125448afeb9108a8b8cf56fd658?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://jarment.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jim Arment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-234&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-26T19:07:30+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:07pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        +1 on that.

Include labels for accessibility reason, but visibility of them isn’t necessary if you’re using the placeholder attribute. The placeholder text is preset on :focus, but hides after you start typing.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-223&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8c2ce39b271184ff4c10c9e971f8bc9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8c2ce39b271184ff4c10c9e971f8bc9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://jamiefarrelly.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jamie Farrelly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-223&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-17T23:14:15+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:14pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Good read, I thought I was the only person who does things like this!

A few weeks ago something similar happened to me and I just had to refresh the page to double check that I knew what was going on.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-224&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0c734018957cef85042f5e4c58ceaadd?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/0c734018957cef85042f5e4c58ceaadd?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.timothywhalin.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Timothy Whalin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-224&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-17T23:21:36+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:21pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

I agree with you 90%. The label is a much needed element that seems to be missing from a lot of web content. However, I would also like to comment that I think there are cases in which a label is not needed. For example, if a search field has a “search” placeholder and a search icon, a user will know what they’ve typed in there even once the placeholder text is gone. This would be similar to anytime a form contains icons.

Another example is when the fields are very straightforward. For example, the contact form on my site has name, email, message. Once a user types in their name, for example, they would remember and know that the field was their name.

I totally agree with the sentiment of your article that form labels are still needed and shouldn’t be removed just for aesthetics. Hope you don’t mind my devil’s advocate comment. :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-226&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1ea75377e8f31300a35d459391be2373?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1ea75377e8f31300a35d459391be2373?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.zivmeltzer.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ziv Meltzer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-226&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-18T14:44:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:44pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Well, thank you! Finally, someone writes it down, as simple as it should be.

Win! :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-227&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/598b7b1a8f45f2a8ed4e3000fa955b14?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/598b7b1a8f45f2a8ed4e3000fa955b14?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.vasiljevski.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Nikola Vasiljevski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-227&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-18T16:17:45+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:17pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Nice point, people tend to forget that technology should help people :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-229&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8486c9e4d3ef6024f449bf9de54b1330?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8486c9e4d3ef6024f449bf9de54b1330?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://carlorizzante.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Carlo Rizzante&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-229&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-27T14:51:20+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:51pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Nice article, Laura (and nice blog). It actually inspired me today while polishing a backend interface (in WordPress). You made me realize that it’s likely time to finally fix my own contact page ^__^ Thanks!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-230&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8486c9e4d3ef6024f449bf9de54b1330?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/8486c9e4d3ef6024f449bf9de54b1330?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://carlorizzante.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Carlo Rizzante&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-230&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2012-12-27T14:55:23+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:55pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Nice article, Laura, thanks for sharing. It inspired me right today while polishing a backend interface I’m developing (in WordPress). And it made me realize that it may be finally time to rethink my contact page! :-o Cheers!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-235&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ad1368d5f36d84983fd58ebdbb90172d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ad1368d5f36d84983fd58ebdbb90172d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Aaron&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-235&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-27T06:24:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;06:24am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I agree with this post but always liked the clean look of using placeholders.

I wrote a jQuery plugin that I think largely solves this problem. It works by dropping the label down below the field after it has focus or a value so the label is still visible, while maintaing the clean look of placeholders before the form is used.

You can find it here along with a demo: &lt;a href=&#39;http://jacware.github.com/fancyplaceholder/&#39; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;http://jacware.github.com/fancyplaceholder/&lt;/a&gt;

Let me know what you all think!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-237&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf2b0d6a0f46d26d5cb5168285107816?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf2b0d6a0f46d26d5cb5168285107816?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://jfeliweb.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jeazy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-237&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-04T19:39:44+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:39pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great Article! This makes complete sense to me and you hit the points well. I can’t count how many times I forget what to put into a form.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-239&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/92340eafa4400eae2b68798a47e077bf?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/92340eafa4400eae2b68798a47e077bf?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kolor-designs.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;razvan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-239&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-05-25T05:08:00+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;05:08am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It always drives me crazy when a form only has placeholders that go away on focus. 

I really like the aesthetic of having the label inside the input field –; just don’t hide it on focus. Here’s an example of how I implemented it on one of the projects I worked on: goo.gl/pzdkg
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-240&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ff5098abb715ee41beda5c4239a3f2f4?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ff5098abb715ee41beda5c4239a3f2f4?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Spencer Edwards&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-240&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-11T16:53:03+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;16:53pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Excellent post!  I agree that this rising trend of only using placeholders as labels is actually knocking down the usability of a form.  I tend to use both as well, as one does accent the other.  There are ways to get a slick design while using both.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-2780&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://laurakalbag.wpengine.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Laura Kalbag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-2780&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-10-25T07:09:31+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;07:09am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        A quick update on this subject: [Brad Frost has written up a great potential float label pattern (designed by Matt D Smith) on his website](http://bradfrostweb.com/blog/post/float-label-pattern/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow).
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-140588&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/000da50f19db5e37a65c29b87fd30956?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/000da50f19db5e37a65c29b87fd30956?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ken Pierce&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-140588&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2015-04-22T04:13:57+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;04:13am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Some good ideas in the comments, but don’t forget that any solution that involves hovering the mouse literally does not exist for any user who lives on a smart phone rather then parked in front of a nice big monitor.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-145915&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3d27a2811e4f7db144ee521ea05ebfcb?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3d27a2811e4f7db144ee521ea05ebfcb?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;loeffel&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-145915&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2016-03-17T10:03:29+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:03am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        This can be done without using placeholder text with pure css. The markup needs to include the label after the input field then just position the label absolutely and resize and move it a few pixels up with something like `input-text:focus + label`. Add a transition and voilà –; no need for a jquery plugin.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day Two</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-two&#34;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethan-marcotte-responsive-web-design&#34;&gt;Ethan Marcotte –; Responsive Web Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70764623061729280&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70765105113088000&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70765603635470337&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aral/status/70765587453837312&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70766758608388096&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70767608542134272&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70768314661617664&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70768677590540288&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70769336872218624&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70769336872218624&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;femi-t-adesina-enhancing-your-creativity&#34;&gt;Femi T Adesina –; Enhancing your Creativity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mis-hastagged the first tweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70776083460534272&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70777226345451520&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70779952345268224&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70780597911564288&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70781453063036928&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70783293863362560&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70784592235335680&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70784592235335680&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;josh-clark-buttons-are-a-hack-the-new-rules-of-designing-for-touch&#34;&gt;Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70796043628974081&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ubelly/status/70796280640704512&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70796934423642112&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70797159473233920&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-thoughts-at-this-point&#34;&gt;My thoughts at this point:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70797424913940480&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70798167960064000&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rougebert/status/70799923569885184&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70798363745992704&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;josh-clark-buttons-are-a-hack-the-new-rules-of-designing-for-touch-continued-8230&#34;&gt;Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch continued&amp;#8230;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70798948784279552&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70799691423555584&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70799969744994304&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70800774992637952&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70801926517829632&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ubelly/status/70802195414646784&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70803480725557248&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70805287333933057&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70806873082826754&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70807634038628352&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70807634038628352&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-mcgarvey-copywriting-is-design&#34;&gt;John McGarvey –; Copywriting is Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70809101566885888&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70809452034531329&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70810047747330048&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70810764176404480&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/samwebcornwall/status/70811269606813696&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70811763192496128&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70812596365832192&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70813093600571392&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nickg_uk/status/70819117720023040&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70835359101091841&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CarlJWood/status/70835809246396416&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nickg_uk/status/70836478288203776&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70837006686629888&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70837006686629888&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;martin-beeby-ie9-the-story-so-far&#34;&gt;Martin Beeby –; IE9: The Story So Far&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70838762313236480&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gp-FQN_v3AM&#34; title=&#34;&#39;What developers think of Internet Explorer&#39; on Youtube&#34;&gt;What developers think of Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt; (The video mentioned in the above tweet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ubelly/status/70838367268507648&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70841406700257281&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70841865779425280&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70841865779425280&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abbey-tosic-standing-out-and-moving-up-in-web-design&#34;&gt;Abbey Tosic –; Standing Out and Moving Up In Web Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70846362970894336&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70846483393544193&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70846949061951488&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70851463445872640&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70851692404543489&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70851692404543489&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sarah-b-nelson-bullet-proof-communication-techniques-a-ux-strategist-s-guide&#34;&gt;Sarah B Nelson –; Bullet Proof Communication Techniques: A UX Strategist’s Guide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70868334941450241&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70868599413280768&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70869099776966658&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70869481605443585&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70871446586535936&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70872151036665856&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70873032301875202&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70873509999550464&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70873998652747776&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ubelly/status/70873946706292737&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveworkman/status/70874946838077440&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70876184799485952&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/globalmoxie/status/70876401598869504&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-steveworkman-status-70876936301330433&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveworkman/status/70876936301330433&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;josh-clark-cage-match-mobile-web-vs-native-app&#34;&gt;Josh Clark –; Cage Match: Mobile Web vs. Native App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70880535500693504&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70881169830461440&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70881617735979008&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70883292450275328&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70883632335691776&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70883861587955712&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70884205403455488&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70885151537758208&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70885345226522624&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70885747149910016&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70886027228749824&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/drewm/status/70885774362558464&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/steveworkman/status/70892165206781952&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-one&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aarron-walter-transforming-ideas-into-interfaces&#34;&gt;Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70412513673613313&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70409366393720832&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70409366393720832&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mike-kus-designing-for-humans&#34;&gt;Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70413019372462080&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70413431215374336&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70414181526016001&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70415868177297408&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dstridsberg/status/70416403051716608&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70419338548625409&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70419338548625409&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ian-stewart-power-your-design-with-wordpress&#34;&gt;Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70433977210650624&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70435244968390656&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70435806216593408&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70436089860603904&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70436403439337472&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70436675712585728&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70437038083674112&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70437815212703744&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70439132249341953&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70439132249341953&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70439785042427904&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70440210487447552&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70440731872989184&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70441391683145728&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70445610720960512&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70445610720960512&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;robin-christopherson-accessibility-and-inclusive-design-what-s-hot-and-what-s-not&#34;&gt;Robin Christopherson –; Accessibility and Inclusive Design –; What’s Hot and What’s Not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a short talk and FOWD get Robin to talk about accessibility every year. It’s always inspiring and shows you how easy it is to make browsing reasonable for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70445610720960512&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70446198737211392&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70446198737211392&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-rhatigan-web-fonts-type-choice-amp-type-use&#34;&gt;Daniel Rhatigan –; Web Fonts: Type Choice &amp;amp; Type Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t at all the sales pitch talk that Monotype presented last year. Daniel Rhatigan was really knowledgeable about fonts on the screen and went way beyond the basics of web fonts that we’re used to hearing all over the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70467135146692609&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70467613569974273&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70468082430263296&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70469069735858176&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70469387596992512&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70469697627369473&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70469697627369473&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;samuel-bowles-extreme-design-secrets-to-successful-design-pairing&#34;&gt;Samuel Bowles –; Extreme Design — Secrets to Successful Design Pairing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70472744009076737&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70473079029108736&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70473463067967488&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70473833257238528&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70474130889252864&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70474769526562817&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70475893138669568&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70476701569789953&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70477339649261568&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70477624924839936&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70478426733150208&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70478481749839872&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70478481749839872&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ian-hamilton-demystifying-accessibility&#34;&gt;Ian Hamilton –; Demystifying Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70483224635252737&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70483525350064129&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70483919191031808&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70484188511469568&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70484384330952705&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70484721804640256&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70485544429297664&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70486348569645057&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70486793019080704&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70487625106067457&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70488399886295040&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70488795245576193&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tweet-https-twitter-com-laurakalbag-status-70489256719687680&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70489256719687680&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dan-james-open-business&#34;&gt;Dan James –; Open Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70508556541100032&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70509293761343488&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70509535030280192&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70509925444485120&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70510302613078017&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70511168229351424&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70511914194714624&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/laurakalbag/status/70513840336535552&#34;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girlguides UK Anti-airbrushing Campaign</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/girlguides-uk-anti-airbrushing-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 10:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/girlguides-uk-anti-airbrushing-campaign/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don’t like to say it, but I think the Girlguides UK campaign (&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23gukforrealimages&#34; title=&#34;hashtag search on Twitter&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23gukforrealimages&#34; title=&#34;hashtag search on Twitter&#34;&gt;gukforrealimages&lt;/a&gt;) call for labelling all airbrushed images of women is unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our girls and young women are demanding action from the Prime Minister to introduce compulsory labelling to distinguish between airbrushed and natural imagesin order to ‘shape a generation of self-confident girls and young women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Tell us the truth –; Girls call for honesty over airbrushing. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlguiding.org.uk/system_pages/small_navigation/latest_news/tell_us_the_truth.aspx&#34;&gt;Girlguiding website&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a girl, and I’ve had all the usual confidence issues growing up that are no doubt in-part created by the unhealthy portrayal of women in the media. Many girls (and boys) would certainly benefit from there being more natural body shapes being shown in advertising and the media in general. If it’s going to be aspirational, then it should give people aspirations of realistic, achievable goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’m not sure that the lines between air brushing (by which I assume they mean altering the appearance of a model) and post-production are clear enough. I think it is probably near-impossible to find a commercial image out there that hasn’t had some kind of post-production applied. It could be anything from changing the colouring and exposure all the way to placing a model into an artificial environment. In post production the artist is designing the image to suit the advertising campaign in every possible way, this will inevitably mean changes from the very raw basic image shot in a studio. If all the images used in commercial campaigns looked like our holiday snaps, they wouldn’t have the desired effect. Commercial campaigns are designed to make us want to be like the people in the photos, be it richer, slimmer or just happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s already been labelling in TV ads. All the mascara advertisements now have a ‘enhanced in post production’ label at some point. It’s obvious that nobody could get eyelashes a mile long with a plain old high street mascara so it’s false advertising. Does this labelling work? Do children understand what post production is? Does everybody read the small text on TV adverts? I don’t really think so. It just means nobody’s going to sue the cosmetics companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do the Girlguides propose these images should be labelled? If there’s an image where nothing has been done except the smoothing of a girl’s skin and applying some extra eye makeup, how is that distinguished by a label from an image where they’ve given her somebody else’s breasts, trimmed her waist by six inches, changed the colour of her hair, the colour of her skin and lengthened her eyelashes. Does each image then have to come with a list of everything the digital artist did to perfect the photo? I’d imagine on most campaigns there’d be more label than photo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where then do they draw the line at what needs to be labelled? TV adverts, magazines, billboards, clothes catalogues so also clothes store websites, packaging, DVD, CD and book covers. You can see where I’m going with this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than going guns blazing into a campaign to label as many commercial images as possible ‘fake’, I think it would be far more productive to try to tackle these problems at the root. Why do we aspire to be ridiculously thin? Who are the role models that make us this way? Can we change the attitudes of the influencers, the magazines and advertisers that insist on these bizarre body images being what we should aspire to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s great that the Girlguides are drawing attention to these issues but there’s much more to them than dodgy photos and a bit of small print to fix the perceptions of young girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-comments&#34;&gt;5 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-36&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;richquick&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-36&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-04T10:25:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:25am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag as ever I agree with you. Please stand as an MP so I can vote for you!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-37&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;richquick&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-37&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-04T10:25:47+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:25am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag I do think Photoshopping out wrinkles in an anti-wrinkle cream ad was beyond the pale, though.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-35&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d2ba25cc379899a37b46acae43f6ddc?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d2ba25cc379899a37b46acae43f6ddc?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;AndyW&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-35&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-04T11:27:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:27am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Don’t forget, Girl Guiders is a bunch of nut cases ;)

I’m not kidding, my wife is involved with them and there are some absolute loonies involved in the organisation. I mean&amp;#8230; who in their right mind would want to hang out with a bunch of squealing girls for a couple of hours a week?

As for the image labelling, I think it’s a nice thought, but everything is “airbrushed” these days. It would basically mean putting a compulsory notice on every advertisement, which is quite frankly a waste of time.

What would be cooler would be to encourage companies NOT to tart up their pics in post-production and announce that fact in the adverts. I think that would gain a lot more respect from purchasers.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-39&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/69e3906339fed4cd6d8790e0b2a42d6d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/69e3906339fed4cd6d8790e0b2a42d6d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Pearly&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-39&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-12-19T22:47:30+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;22:47pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @Andy W

I think really the point is to make people aware how many images really are airbrushed. If people can see groups of images are airbrushed then a response might persuade companies that they could become more popular and save millions of pounds by not airbrushing images and showing the subject in their natural beauty. People would trust and appreciate the company more.

It’s making the small steps to getting companies to CHOOSE not to airbrush images. To use the phrase “all guns blazing” would be to persuade/ force companies not airbrush. Perhaps once images are labelled then companies could be persuaded.

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe it is a waste of time if it can produce a result. It is the images that are part of the reason people especially girls want to be thin etc.

I do agree though that there would need to be some conditions on which images should be labelled. Perhaps a traffic light system?&lt;/p&gt;
As a girl guide I think it shows we are still being a movement and trying to improve the possibilities for women. :D.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
