<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design Issues on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design Issues on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What advice do you give to aspiring designers or typographers?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</guid>
      <description>I was just asked, amongst a couple of other questions, what advice I would give to aspiring designers or typographers.
With my mind focused on the aspiration part, I started writing an answer based on finding your own way of working through studying others, not copying… And then I realised it was a bit superficial. What’s the biggest problem with young designers today? They’re coin-operated*. So I wrote what I hope is slightly better advice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there potential for “ethical analytics”?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 10:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/is-there-potential-for-ethical-analytics/</guid>
      <description>We have Piwik analytics on the Ind.ie site, and I use Gauges and GoSquared on my own site (I was indecisive at the time…) But I use Ghostery so I actually block analytics like this for my own use.
As someone who is a big web fan, and used to work in client services, I understand the value of particular types of analytics for simple sites like ours:
 Amount of hits (required to understand popular/unpopular content and make financial decisions for hosting etc) Browser/browser size/operating system (required to know how to optimise for visitors) Language spoken (required to work out how to best optimise for different languages) Referring links (to track who is saying what about your site)  BUT, I think there are unnecessary metrics that can be on the invasive side for simple sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion Of Free on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Last week, my column on The Illusion Of Free was published on A List Apart. I took a lot of time writing it, as I think it’s an incredibly important issue, and it reflects my thinking around Ind.ie. As ever, a massive thank you to the wonderful editor Rose Weisburd who helped me round things out, made me sound smarter and encouraged me in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at border:none</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking and running a “creator unit” at border:none in Nuremberg. This is incredibly exciting as it’s an event focused around the decentralisation of the web, a topic that I care about a great deal. I’ll be talking about using considerate design and great user experiences to create genuine alternatives to the products that make money from exploiting their users’ data.
It’s also an all-new topic for me to share with other people, so I can’t wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s dConstruct was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Designing for the unknown</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Craig Grannell asked me some questions about designing for the unknown. The result was a really fantastic article called Designing for the unknown: how to design templates and frameworks, and has contributions from some really smart people.
The title image is from my writeup of the Default Perch Theme project I did with Perch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: The future of web design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 13:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>Over the next few days I’m catching up on things I failed to share in recent months. It’s been a very busy few months, but I still like to have a record of what I did and where I’ve been!
In April, I spoke to Neil Bennett about the future of web design, and the challenges we face. There were some good questions, and it’s interesting to see the answers of difference people from different areas side-by-side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Heart Internet</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Heart Internet posted an interview with me on their site. They start off saying some very kind things about me, and then it covers accessibility, design, speaking at conferences and a bit of client work. As a bonus, it’s interspersed with photos of me pulling weird faces at conferences (and being business on the phone!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.
“Devices” It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts.com mockup fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I do like the way that fonts.com do web fonts. (I also like all of the web font services for different reasons and different projects.)
Mockup fonts Fonts.com have this new system that really works. It involves an app called SkyFonts. This allows you to try out different fonts in your desktop mockups as rentals. Great for static mockups of web designs. You choose the fonts you want on the fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fl&amp;#42;t design trend</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</guid>
      <description>I’m about to apply a mute filter to the word “flat” on Twitter. That or start unfollowing a lot of people.
What’s flat? There’s an aesthetic “trend” that’s been around for a while. It involves fewer gradients and textures and has thus been described as “flat” design. It’s often described as the opposite of “skeuomorphism,” (which is an equally irritating word when used in this way.) It was popularised by Windows Metro&amp;nbsp;and, being an aesthetic associated with fewer images, and thus better performance and more flexibility in the development of interfaces, has been a feature of many designs in both apps and on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Ways: Design Systems</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 10:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking a lot about the design in ‘responsive’ design lately. My post on 24ways is where I started to get some of my thoughts and ideas out. Here I talk about design systems and how thinking in this way, and basing our processes around this concept, can help us create more flexible future-proof responsive designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>display: none;</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 08:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/display-none/</guid>
      <description>Or The things you think are common knowledge but really they aren’t. I was on the ShopTalk show a few weeks ago, and a few people have asked me what I meant when I said “display: none; naughties.” I foolishly thought that people would understand what I meant, (and I’ll come to that later) so I thought I’d better explain myself.
display: none; in responsive web design When we’re changing out layouts based on viewport sizes, using media queries, we tend to switch page elements about a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let the technical processes of web development stifle your imagination</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</guid>
      <description>A new post from me, this time at .net magazine. Keep it creative! There’s some pretty cool comments over there too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will understanding the mainstream affect me as a designer?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 21:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been contemplating how designers can identify better with more mainstream users.
I had a thought last week. What if, by rejecting Facebook, I’m actually missing out on design patterns that are so influential on the mainstream user that it affects their perception on the rest of the web?
And the same goes for Google Chrome. I’ve been going through a rebellious anti-Google phase, but now Chrome has taken over as the world’s most popular browser, am I making life harder for myself by developing sites in Safari first?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critiques, giving and receiving useful feedback</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Funnily enough, a couple of days before Mark Boulton said to critique design effectively.&amp;quot; says Mark Boulton on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) and wrote his piece on design critiques, I’d been thinking about that same topic. I’ve been struggling through an iPhone app icon design, and had asked Twitter for help. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an app icon design that needs some criticism as I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of it. Anyone free to give me some time via email today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labels in input fields aren’t such a good idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/labels-in-input-fields-arent-such-a-good-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 17:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/labels-in-input-fields-arent-such-a-good-idea/</guid>
      <description>There’s something that’s been bothering me lately. It seems to be some kind of form interface trend where the labels for text inputs are placed inside the fields themselves.
Example:
   There might be some pros Admittedly, this makes an interface slicker. It saves space where you’d usually have a label, then some padding, then the input field and probably a load of padding around the lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day Two</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Ethan Marcotte –; Responsive Web Design Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Femi T Adesina –; Enhancing your Creativity I mis-hastagged the first tweet!
Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
My thoughts at this point: Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch continued&amp;#8230; Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!
Day One Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.
Tweet
Tweet Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girlguides UK Anti-airbrushing Campaign</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/girlguides-uk-anti-airbrushing-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 10:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/girlguides-uk-anti-airbrushing-campaign/</guid>
      <description>I don’t like to say it, but I think the Girlguides UK campaign (#gukforrealimages) call for labelling all airbrushed images of women is unrealistic.
 Our girls and young women are demanding action from the Prime Minister to introduce compulsory labelling to distinguish between airbrushed and natural imagesin order to ‘shape a generation of self-confident girls and young women.
(Tell us the truth –; Girls call for honesty over airbrushing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>