<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 09:25:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I love this pen</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 09:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</guid>
      <description>It’s a J Herbin metal pen. It’s a rollerball but it takes any standard ink cartridge. I use it with the J Herbin ink cartridges as they come in loads of different colours and packaged in cute little tins.
It’s taken me years to find my ideal pen. I have small hands so I need something that isn’t too chunky or heavy. The J Herbin pen has a quality weight but doesn’t hurt if I’ve been writing for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychology for designers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/psychology-for-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 08:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/psychology-for-designers/</guid>
      <description>This week I went all out and bought all the currently-released Five Simple Steps Pocket Guide digital books. I say “went all out”, they’re an absolute bargain at £6 for a collection of four, or £2 per book. Reading this book thoroughly, following the links in the text, took me about an hour. I’m a fairly fast reader but can be slow to digest new ideas.
 
I started reading with Psychology for designers by Joe Leech first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>I know, this is a funny topic on which to base a blog post but I love the Unfinished Business podcast, and I’d like to elaborate why in something more than a few fawning tweets.
Business, but not suits Business doesn’t feel like the right word to describe what I do. It’s a hobby that makes me enough money to support myself. The word ‘business’ conjures up images of suits, handshakes and networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMACSS –; Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/smacss-scalable-and-modular-architecture-for-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 08:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/smacss-scalable-and-modular-architecture-for-css/</guid>
      <description>I bought Jonathan Snook’s Scalable and Modular Architecture for CSS five months ago and, embarrassingly, I’ve only just read it. As a “flexible guide to developing sites small and large”, it’s fantastic.
   Last month I was lucky enough to see Jonathan speak about State-Based Design (a concept which he covers in SMACSS) at theFromTheFront conference and it reminded me to put the book at the top of my to-read pile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Designing with Data</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 10:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-with-data/</guid>
      <description>Another ubelly post from me, this time a review. Much like my other reviews of books on this blog, just in another location!
A Practical Guide to Designing with Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months of the Fitbit (and the new Fitbit Aria)</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/six-months-of-the-fitbit-and-the-new-fitbit-aria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 16:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/six-months-of-the-fitbit-and-the-new-fitbit-aria/</guid>
      <description>Skip to the main review!
The backstory I’m a fit and healthy person. Probably not your typical work-from-home desk-based screen-faced designer. I go to the gym 4 to 6 times a week, walk my dog every day, I eat fairly healthily and I’m a good weight.
I wasn’t always though. I’m not pretending I was massively fat, but after leaving university three years ago, I’d got some really bad habits (two cans of Relentless a day, anyone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile First</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mobile-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 09:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mobile-first/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on with my chapter-a-day, last week I finished reading the brilliant Mobile First by Luke Wroblewski.
   Mobile design and development has gained momentum over the last few years; with responsive design and designers regularly going giddy over iPhone app UIs, it’s surprising how little the industry discusses the *design* issues. We seem to prefer to get caught up in the more technical and development-based conversations (or the infuriatingly dull native vs web, but I’ll get back to that!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing For Emotion</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/designing-for-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 09:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/designing-for-emotion/</guid>
      <description>I bought Designing For Emotion as part of the A Book Apart deal, alongside Mobile First. After listening to Jeffery Zeldman talking about the release of these books with Dan Benjamin on The Big Web Show, and hearing how they were perfect books to read before a redesign (my site is in a constant state of awaiting redesign) I was really eager to get stuck in. Oddly, I decided to read Mobile First second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Designing the invisible</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-the-invisible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 08:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-the-invisible/</guid>
      <description>After reading Mark Boulton’s A Practical Guide to Designing For The Web and Andy Clarke’s Hardboiled Web Design, I was keen to read another Five Simple Steps’ design book. Robert Mills’ A Practical Guide to Designing the invisible definitely didn’t disappoint.
   It took me a few reads to start getting into it. I haven’t been dedicating enough time to reading lately, so when I did it was stop-start and not concentrating properly, so I’ve decided to read a chapter a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Web Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-web-design/</guid>
      <description>I had ordered Responsive Web Design by Ethan Marcotte as soon as it came out, but being at Ampersand conference, and hearing so many people recommend it, really spurred me to take a few hours out to get on and read it.
  My copy of Responsive Web Design, already featuring a &amp;amp;#39;much used&amp;amp;#39; cover curl...   Responsive web design is a term summarising design that has a flexibility allowing it to be optimised for different browsing experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Review</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-the-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-the-review/</guid>
      <description>Another great event from Carsonified, I really enjoyed Future Of Web Design this year.
The Cost I was actually really lucky to get a ticket. I seriously couldn’t afford the £714 2-day conference pass, even at the super early bird rate (that was about £200 less, I can’t remember exactly.) My lovely friend Scott Coello had done the amazing motion graphics for the conference and very kindly gave me his spare ticket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks and Getting Over Moleskine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/notebooks-and-getting-over-moleskine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 12:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/notebooks-and-getting-over-moleskine/</guid>
      <description>I’m a notebook and sketchbook-aholic. Actually I’m addicted to stationery of any kind. Pens, pencils, post-it notes. It’s incredibly easy to convince myself I need these items when I mostly don’t.
Notebooks and sketchbooks (and maybe some nice accompanying pens), however, are an absolutely vital part of my working life.
Why bother with physical notebooks? Evernote isn’t the same as writing by hand. Neither is any other note-making software. Balsamiq isn’t the same as wireframing by hand, or Photoshop for sketching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardboiled Web Design and Transcending CSS</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/hardboiled-web-design-and-transcending-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 16:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/hardboiled-web-design-and-transcending-css/</guid>
      <description>My history with Transcending CSS In 2006/early 2007 I read this amazing book. I was half way through my first year studying Digital Design, and I’d only been experimenting with standards-based web design for about six months after reading Web Standards Solutions.
I was already well on my way to being a standards fiend, but Transcending CSS by Andy Clarke did, literally, transcend the standards and made me utterly mad about pushing the boundaries of CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the iPad is saving my sanity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 18:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</guid>
      <description>Fan girl I’ve had an iPad since the day it was released in the UK. I bought it because I’m a fan girl. I admit it. I could pretend that I wanted it to take to conferences or use for testing or when I didn’t need a laptop when I went to visit clients. In truth, I only go to one or two conferences per year, I’ve not yet made a site that needed an iPad-specific site and when I go to visit clients I always need my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 For Web Designers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/html5-for-web-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 16:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/html5-for-web-designers/</guid>
      <description>Even though the specification for HTML5 isn’t yet complete, those of us who are a bit eager to get into it now have the perfect book to get us started.
   
HTML5 For Web Designers by Jeremy Keith is the first offering from A Book Apart. It’s a very easy read, not an endless reference, which took me a couple of hours to fully digest whilst I was enjoying the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autodesk SketchBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/autodesk-sketchbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 13:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/autodesk-sketchbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always been a kind-of arty person. I took Art at school, did an Art Foundation and a Graphics degree. I totally loved art when I was small, but as I’ve got older, and more technology and web-obsessed, a lot of the old media went a bit out of the window.
Though I was still loving wireframing and taking notes by hand, I just threw all the paints out in frustration at how slow and difficult they were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zootool — The best and most beautiful tool for storing inspiration</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/zootool-the-best-tool-for-storing-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 21:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/zootool-the-best-tool-for-storing-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>Since I started using Zootool in March I’ve been totally addicted.
I’d been looking for a scrapbook-style app, to stash all the inspiration I find, for a while. On cool sites like Dribbble, Drawar, FFFFound and all over the web, I’m always finding pretty things I’d like to keep and use when I’m designing later on.
I was trying to do this with Little Snapper but found, whilst it’s great for posh and annotated screenshots, it wasn’t quick enough to capture and file the images and sites that I’d found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>