<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 10:18:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Site adjustments</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/site-adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 10:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/site-adjustments/</guid>
      <description>My site is looking a little different, I’m now using the lovely Recia for the type. Fontdeck recently retired, and while they gave loads of notice about the service stopping, I still didn’t update my fonts in time. This left my site looking a little sad and Helvetica-y.
  My site with web-safe backup fonts, Georgia and Helvetica   
I have a redesign in the works. But I’ve no idea when it’ll be finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 29th March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-29th-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-29th-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Back in the office today and we’re working hard and getting a lot done. We can’t wait to share what we’re working on with you all. (Soon, I promise!)
Friday and today, I’ve been getting our Labs and source.ind.ie in tip-top shape. Now with our own logo in the corner, it feels more like home, and Aral has added single sign-on so you can sign up with your GitHub account, as well as adding some new copy on the source homepage to explain a little more about what is housed on source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What advice do you give to aspiring designers or typographers?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/advice-for-aspiring-designers/</guid>
      <description>I was just asked, amongst a couple of other questions, what advice I would give to aspiring designers or typographers.
With my mind focused on the aspiration part, I started writing an answer based on finding your own way of working through studying others, not copying… And then I realised it was a bit superficial. What’s the biggest problem with young designers today? They’re coin-operated*. So I wrote what I hope is slightly better advice:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>130 words on getting creative in Offscreen Magazine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/130-words-in-offscreen-mag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/130-words-in-offscreen-mag/</guid>
      <description>I’m slightly behind on my posts, but I wanted to share my contribution in the latest edition of Offscreen Magazine. Offscreen is a beautiful, printed, independent magazine about the “People behind Bits and Pixels.” I contributed 130 words to Issue 10 on getting into a creative mindset.
You can buy a copy, or get a subscription to Offscreen by visiting their website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A realign for 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-realign-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 17:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-realign-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>Almost a year after last year’s realign, I’ve made some more tweaks to my site. There were a few reasons behind it:
 I’m not freelance anymore, so I don’t need the focus on my portfolio As I’m now working with Ind.ie, I needed to update my about page The navigation needed some accessibility work The colours were beginning to grate on me  Less portfolio, more… My blog has been fairly quiet, but actually that’s because I’ve been writing a lot elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 16:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>Another fab and in-depth article from Craig Grannell on Digital Arts, this time on Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015. Craig asked a load of smart designers (and me) about web fonts, web font services, and how to choose web fonts.
 
My full answers to Craig’s original questions are below:
What do you consider the current best options for working with web fonts? I’m forever changing my mind, but I tend to prefer to host fonts on the site itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’m doing now and why</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</guid>
      <description>I’d been a freelance web designer/developer full-time, working for myself, for six years. I love working with clients, and working with small businesses is a very sustainable business model. You can make a big difference to a small business. You can get paid fairly well. And you can forge long-term relationships with people whose businesses you really care about. I always said I’d never give it up, unless it was for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Stuff on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week my latest column, Breaking Stuff, was published on A List Apart. I’m in a strange transitional period, moving from client work to fulltime at ind.ie, so I think I’ll be writing more about situations like these as time goes on.
I’ve also finally updated that terrible avatar to something much better. I look uncharacteristically pale, but at least I’m normal colours! (Unlike the last terrible photo I’d used.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ind.ie Project Stratosphere announcement</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-project-stratosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 14:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-project-stratosphere/</guid>
      <description>After a few months of being pretty quiet, and working towards our crowdfunding campaign, we’re finally able to reveal some big stuff about ind.ie.
We’re not just designing a phone. A crowdfunding campaign for a phone that you’ll get in two years is not a risk worth taking. We need to build a network and ecosystem around that phone. We need a fantastic and mature platform that the phone to give the phone the ultimate experience on its release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at border:none</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking and running a “creator unit” at border:none in Nuremberg. This is incredibly exciting as it’s an event focused around the decentralisation of the web, a topic that I care about a great deal. I’ll be talking about using considerate design and great user experiences to create genuine alternatives to the products that make money from exploiting their users’ data.
It’s also an all-new topic for me to share with other people, so I can’t wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indie Tech Summit videos and my talk on Universal Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we finally published all the videos from the Indie Tech Summit on the ind.ie site. It was a fantastic event, with two days of talking about how we can create sustainable and ethical alternatives to corporate surveillance. The first day was talks and panels, with everyone discussing the problems and their own free and open solutions. The second day had workshops and discussion groups where we talked about where we could go from there, and what we could do as a community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Designing for the unknown</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Craig Grannell asked me some questions about designing for the unknown. The result was a really fantastic article called Designing for the unknown: how to design templates and frameworks, and has contributions from some really smart people.
The title image is from my writeup of the Default Perch Theme project I did with Perch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: The future of web design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 13:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>Over the next few days I’m catching up on things I failed to share in recent months. It’s been a very busy few months, but I still like to have a record of what I did and where I’ve been!
In April, I spoke to Neil Bennett about the future of web design, and the challenges we face. There were some good questions, and it’s interesting to see the answers of difference people from different areas side-by-side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discount code for WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen that I’m speaking at WXG in Guildford in September. If you didn’t already get a ticket, you might want to use my discount code of kalbagWXG to get £10 off the (already very affordable £99) ticket price.
There’s some great speakers in the lineup, and it’s sure to be a fun day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why accessibility matters to me #GAAD</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/why-accessibility-matters-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 10:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/why-accessibility-matters-to-me/</guid>
      <description>The reason I fell in love with the web was the democratisation of information. I love that so many people can access, learn, and share such a huge variety of resources. That’s why I’ve always considered accessibility so important. To me, access for all is an essential part of the nature of the web.
How I learned accessibility When I started to learn about web design and development, I learned from great books like Dan Cederholm’s Web Standards Solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look inside a designer’s sketchbook</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-look-inside-a-designers-sketchbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 10:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-look-inside-a-designers-sketchbook/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, Ian from logogeek.co.uk, asked if I’d share some of my sketchbook pages on his site. Ian wanted to emphasise the rough, imperfect nature of the way we plan logo designs, and show real work done by real people.
Last week, Ian added some pages from my sketchbook to his post, “A look inside a designers sketchbook”. He included some of my sketches from the Indie Phone and Turbine projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little realign</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-little-realign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 13:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-little-realign/</guid>
      <description>Things are looking a bit different around here. It’s not a redesign so much as a realign. I’ve been tinkering for a few months, and finally got to the point where I’m happy to push it live (even though there’s more I could do.)
There were a few particular goals for this redesign:
Rewrite the CSS I lived in fear that someone might look closely at my CSS. My last redesign came about when responsive web design was still young, and I was incredibly foolish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and My Big Fat Ego on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Today my column on Me and My Big Fat Ego was published on A List Apart. It’s not that I’d say I have a huge ego, but it’s definitely something that’s easily bruised when I feel like things aren’t going my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 10:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/inspiration-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Last week my column on Inspiration was published on A List Apart. It follows roughly the same structure as the talk I gave at Design + Banter a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video interview for Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/video-interview-for-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 17:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/video-interview-for-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 Last week I had a chat with my friend Steve Fisher about my upcoming talk and workshop at Interlink conference and all things Canadian. It was a fun way to end the day, and is complete with me doing a really terrible Canadian accent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March’s Pastry Box thought on purpose</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</guid>
      <description>Today my thought for March was posted on The Pastry Box. It was inspired by First Things First 2014, talks by Cole Peters and Nicklas de León Persson at Design and Banter, and Fictive Kin‘s slashpurpose.org.
I’ve started formulating a draft of my “purpose” for this site, but it’s not quite ready yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 10:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford in September. This is exciting for me because I attended the first ever WXG a couple of years ago, and it’s about as local as a conference is going to get to my hometown, Reigate.
The tickets are a bargain at just £69 for early birds, and there’s already a great lineup with still more to be announced…
I’m going to talk about how we design the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on A Bit More Backendy podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-bit-more-backendy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 12:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-bit-more-backendy/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the fourth episode of the Backendy podcast was released, and I was the guest. It was lovely talking to Darren, partly because he’s been a great client for a while now, partly because I’ve been working on the podcast logo and site, and also because I think a podcast focusing on back-end development is a really good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web workshop at Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 I’m running my ‘Design theory for the web’ workshop at Interlink conference in Canada on the 18th of June.
 
It’s a one day workshop and I’ve written a mega description below for anyone wanting to know more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In my latest column on A List Apart, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview about web fonts on Type Quest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-about-web-fonts-on-type-quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-about-web-fonts-on-type-quest/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago Tyler Sanguinette sent me some questions about design and web typography as part of his thesis on web fonts.
Recently I found that he’d published the interview, and interviews with a load of very smart people, on the Type Quest website. Type Quest also has some really useful information on the OpenType features of web fonts, so it’s well-worth a look.
 
One comment Andy Warburton at 17:40pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love this pen</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 09:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</guid>
      <description>It’s a J Herbin metal pen. It’s a rollerball but it takes any standard ink cartridge. I use it with the J Herbin ink cartridges as they come in loads of different colours and packaged in cute little tins.
It’s taken me years to find my ideal pen. I have small hands so I need something that isn’t too chunky or heavy. The J Herbin pen has a quality weight but doesn’t hurt if I’ve been writing for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on Workspiration</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-on-workspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 11:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-on-workspiration/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I answered some questions for Workspiration on my hardware and software setup, inspiration and dreams.
Workspiration seems to have collected interviews from a huge variety of people working in and around tech, and with everybody answering the same questions, it makes for a really interesting read. Bonus is that they also (eventually) translate the interviews into Russian. It’s nice to see a site that’s open to non-English speakers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Bother With Accessibility? on 24ways</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/why-bother-with-accessibility-on-24ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 09:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/why-bother-with-accessibility-on-24ways/</guid>
      <description> My article for this year’s 24ways has been published today. I wrote “Why Bother With Accessibility?” after giving my Designing For Accessibility talks, and still coming up against the same excuses. I wanted to write something that could be a go-to for people trying to understand why designing for accessibility was worthwhile. Fingers crossed that this helps, because we can’t talk about accessibility enough!
 
3 comments  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Beyond Ink podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the first episode of the Beyond Ink podcast went live. This was a podcast that Rachel had in the works for a while, and we first recorded together a few months ago. Last week we re-recorded that episode, so everything was up-to-date, and I had a fancy new microphone so I didn’t sound as terrible as I did on the last Unfinished Business.
Rachel and I chatted about process, the type of work we like to do and inspiration, amongst other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about building with Typecast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/talking-about-building-with-typecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/talking-about-building-with-typecast/</guid>
      <description>Last November at Build conference 2012, I had fun talking to some of the folks from Typecast about building, web design, responsive design and type. They recorded these videos (along with a load of lovely, smart and cool people!) and made a nice collection that you can watch on their website.
Typecast are also giving away a ticket to Build conference 2013 and some Typecast subscriptions. The draw closes tomorrow, so you’d better be quick!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open for Business on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>My second column for A List Apart, “Open for Business,” is now up. I wrote Open for Business as a follow-up to my Dare conference talk about honesty. It’s not the same as the full talk (and has been edited into a far better shape by Rose Weisburd) but is the essence of why I feel that being open works for my business.
 
One comment Daniel Dogeanu at 18:16pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Next Friday I’m speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin about designing for accessibility, covering problems that affect many different types of screens and devices. It will be my first time in Germany, so I’m very excited!
 
One comment Anna at 10:34am
  Hello there, I very much enjoyed your talk about accessibility at the mobXconference last friday. Is there any chance you can put your slides online?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web, a workshop</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a slightly scary thing: I’m doing my first solo workshop on the 11th October 2013 in Barnsley.
I often get asked about the best way to “learn design”, and I usually say that you learn by doing and you learn by watching how others do it. In this workshop, I want to give new designers, developers, and anybody else wanting to learn how to design for the web, a good foundation with five primers, a bit of doing and a bit of watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.
“Devices” It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass for designers — the talk and the case study</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I gave a talk at the fantastic online conference CSS Summit on ‘Sass for designers’. It uses my new site Web Talk Dog Walk as a case study, and explains the basics of Sass and how to get started using CodeKit.
Usually I wouldn’t recommend checking out my slides, as they’re useless without me explaining them, but as this was an online conference and I wanted the slides to be extra clear in case of technical problems, they hopefully read in a fairly easy-to-follow way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts.com mockup fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fonts-com-mockup-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I do like the way that fonts.com do web fonts. (I also like all of the web font services for different reasons and different projects.)
Mockup fonts Fonts.com have this new system that really works. It involves an app called SkyFonts. This allows you to try out different fonts in your desktop mockups as rentals. Great for static mockups of web designs. You choose the fonts you want on the fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview in Allan McAvoy’s Freelancers series</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-in-freelancers-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-in-freelancers-series/</guid>
      <description>Last week Allan McAvoy posted up the interview he did with me as part of his Freelancers series. Some of the questions are fairly standard, but there’s also some unusual ones like “favourite colour for design” and “typical day in the life…”
 
## One comment  David Griffiths at 23:44pm
  “transparentize” –; I love you –; thought I was stuck with rgba too! And if only I lived on the South Coast my 2 labs would love a walk in your park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring Q and A on .net magazine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</guid>
      <description>After finishing the mentoring project last week, I had a chat with Craig Grannell about mentoring which he published on the .net website: “Laura Kalbag: web designers should mentor newcomers.”
It’s a good summary of the mentoring project and has extracts from a couple of testimonials by Sibylle and Phil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fl&amp;#42;t design trend</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 14:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/flat-design-trend/</guid>
      <description>I’m about to apply a mute filter to the word “flat” on Twitter. That or start unfollowing a lot of people.
What’s flat? There’s an aesthetic “trend” that’s been around for a while. It involves fewer gradients and textures and has thus been described as “flat” design. It’s often described as the opposite of “skeuomorphism,” (which is an equally irritating word when used in this way.) It was popularised by Windows Metro&amp;nbsp;and, being an aesthetic associated with fewer images, and thus better performance and more flexibility in the development of interfaces, has been a feature of many designs in both apps and on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Untangle the Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Nothing quite like a last-minute post… Tonight I’m speaking at Untangle the Web at Google Campus in London. I’m doing a talk on Design Theory for the Web where I do a whistle-stop tour through designing with typography, grids and colour on the web.
I also have a stinking cold so I’m going to be taking industrial quantities of Red Bull and a quarantine zone with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was guest co-host on one of my most favourite podcasts, Unfinished Business. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.
We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred App v2 theme</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/alfred-app-v2-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 20:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/alfred-app-v2-theme/</guid>
      <description>Today I finally got around to playing with Alfred v2. This is the one OSX app I’ll allow to open on login, I use it to launch every app and find every file. I use it to work out maths for my CSS and double-check the meanings of words I’m about to write. And it does so much more.
I was playing around with the appearance and made a really minimal theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed on The Industry</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-on-the-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 07:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-on-the-industry/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a chat with the lovely Conor O’Driscoll and last night he published the interview on The Industry. We talking about design work, education and what I define as success, among other things.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing to display podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a lovely chat with El for her Nothing To Display podcast. We talked about technology and how people get started with technology, accessibility, mentoring and dystopian futures! It was a real treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Feast Designer’s Quest(ionnaire)</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 08:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</guid>
      <description>Design Feast have my answers to their Designer’s Quest(ionnaire) on their site.
Scroll past the scarily large photo of me quickly… their questions prompted me to think about some interesting points, especially challenges for designers:
 What are some of the challenges you encounter as a designer and how do you deal with them?
I think the greatest challenge a designer comes across is their own ego. It’s in our nature, as those that deal in creativity, we have egos that allow us to consider our work good enough to share, and good enough for clients to pay us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: finding the right people</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 10:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>We’ve got a project! I’ll elaborate on the details of the project in a future post, but the importance of having a project was that it’s allowed me to choose the designers/developers who could get something out of being mentees. I didn’t want to do this before securing the right project as I needed to know what I was looking for in a mentee.
Finding the right mentee for the job This has been one of the hardest decisions I’ve ever had to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Wing podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 09:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was a guest on Tim Smith‘s The East Wing podcast. It was a pre-recorded conversation and it was great fun. You can listen to it on the East Wing website, and it’ll be up on iTunes soon.
We discussed how I got started in the industry (really sorry traditional Graphic Design people, I may have generalised a bit…), speaking at conferences, women in the industry and mentoring.
As I said last night on Twitter, Tim Smith is such a great guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live-designing WordPress Admin Icons</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I wrotea post about how I was going to do a talk at WordPress London where I would try to design a WordPress admin icon live. Well, I did it, and it didn’t go too badly. In fact, I was very lucky as the first suggestion for what I should design was a calendar icon. That’s mostly squares, so not too tricky!
  The final calendar icons (as designed quickly in 30 minutes or so)   The WordPress London guys kindly filmed my talk and I’ve included it below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the right project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</guid>
      <description>This post is an update on my mentoring project idea.
Finding the right project If you follow me on Twitter, you might have seen that I’m now looking for a different project to work on. Whilst the previous project I had in mind would have been great fun, the client had a very tight deadline. I didn’t want to push that pressure on to students and freelancers who are likely to have other work they need to do in order to pass their studies or pay the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, a potential project turned up in my inbox. An old school friend wants a website, needs it soon and doesn’t have a huge budget.
Me and freelancing I’m lucky, I get offered a lot of projects, and usually I don’t have any availability for a few months. Little projects like this generally can’t pay the bills for me. It’s a lot of time (particularly admin) for a fairly small return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sharers on The Branch</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a post over on The Branch.
 James Dinsdale emailed me about a new project he was starting out, called The Branch, a site collecting posts about what inspires people. I love these kinds of posts, so I was really keen to be involved.
As a designer, inspiration is a much-discussed topic. Unfortunately, this ‘inspiration’ is often described as particular styles of design and the work of individual designers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New To Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 15:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-to-design/</guid>
      <description>Following my learning design post, I’ve started a little project called “new to design.” At the moment it just consists of a learn-design tag on my Pinboard bookmarks and a Twitter account @newtodesign so that I can share useful design resources (especially for those new to design.)
In the future, I hope it can be useful in other ways. Any suggestions or anything you want to see? You know how to get in touch…  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at the WordPress London January meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the WordPress London January meetup on the 17th of January 2013.
I’ve been using WordPress for years, for my own site and for client sites, and I really love it. I had absolutely no idea what to talk about though. I tend to create custom themes for clients, but these are very different from themes designed for use by many different sites, and so I wasn’t sure whether my experience would be relevant to many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Ways: Design Systems</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 10:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/24-ways-design-systems/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking a lot about the design in ‘responsive’ design lately. My post on 24ways is where I started to get some of my thoughts and ideas out. Here I talk about design systems and how thinking in this way, and basing our processes around this concept, can help us create more flexible future-proof responsive designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bardowl: The Big One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bardowl-the-big-one/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I’ve been working with a great team of people on our iPhone app, Bardowl, an app for streaming unlimited audiobooks for £9.99 a month (think Spotify but for audiobooks.)
It’s not been a quick and easy. Getting publishers to come round to the idea, and securing good audiobooks, has been a lengthy process but we’ve been lucky to have people who really know what they’re talking about behind the scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite apps—fit for purpose</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-favourite-apps-fit-for-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 16:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-favourite-apps-fit-for-purpose/</guid>
      <description>After sitting and waiting for Photoshop to open for five minutes, just to edit an old file, I went off on a bit of a rant about Adobe software.
Tweet A few people asked what I thought the alternatives are, so I thought it might be time to write a post about it.
Photoshop and Illustrator, why not? I’ve been suffering Adobe software for a long time. Since Adobe Photoshop was introduced to me as ‘the industry standard’ when I was at college learning basic photo manipulation, it’s been in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grids, flexibility and responsiveness</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/grids-flexibility-and-responsiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 21:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/grids-flexibility-and-responsiveness/</guid>
      <description>First steps: choosing a typeface The first step in my grid design was to choose an appropriate typeface. I knew this would be everything on such a text-heavy site, and I really struggled because, as with all the elements on my personal site, I wanted it to reflect “me”. I wanted a typeface that felt friendly and not too formal whilst still appearing clean, readable and professional. I sunk money on a few lesser-known typefaces (everybody wants to be different and original, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Really, a redesign? This can’t be real…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/really-a-redesign-this-cant-be-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 07:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/really-a-redesign-this-cant-be-real/</guid>
      <description>It’s about time… So finally I’ve redesigned my website. It’s been about three and a half years since the last version of laurakalbag.wpengine.com (still around at http://2009.laurakalbag.wpengine.com) and that’s a site I designed before I finished university, before I even started freelancing full time. To be fair, it took a while for me to hate it (not that usual kind of as-soon-as-it’s-launched-I-hate-it problem us designers often have) but that’s far too long for a portfolio site to be hanging around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Designing with Data</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-with-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 10:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-with-data/</guid>
      <description>Another ubelly post from me, this time a review. Much like my other reviews of books on this blog, just in another location!
A Practical Guide to Designing with Data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography and the web at Ampersand Conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a big old writeup for ubelly from my notes at Ampersand conference earlier in the month.
This was an event I decided not to live-tweet, as the content is usually more involved and in-depth, making for a better big writeup and less tweetable quotes.
Typography and the web at Ampersand conference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t let the technical processes of web development stifle your imagination</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dont-let-the-technical-processes-of-web-development-stifle-your-imagination/</guid>
      <description>A new post from me, this time at .net magazine. Keep it creative! There’s some pretty cool comments over there too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will understanding the mainstream affect me as a designer?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 21:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/will-understanding-the-mainstream-affect-me-as-a-designer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been contemplating how designers can identify better with more mainstream users.
I had a thought last week. What if, by rejecting Facebook, I’m actually missing out on design patterns that are so influential on the mainstream user that it affects their perception on the rest of the web?
And the same goes for Google Chrome. I’ve been going through a rebellious anti-Google phase, but now Chrome has taken over as the world’s most popular browser, am I making life harder for myself by developing sites in Safari first?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft and Care: Future Of Web Design 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 09:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written up my digest of Future Of Web Design 2012 over at the ubelly blog.
For those who want more of a blow-by-blow account of the day, I’ve compiled all of my live tweets (and retweets) from the day in a Storify feed.
http://storify.com/laurakalbag/laura-kalbag-s-fowd-tweets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critiques, giving and receiving useful feedback</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Funnily enough, a couple of days before Mark Boulton said to critique design effectively.&amp;quot; says Mark Boulton on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) and wrote his piece on design critiques, I’d been thinking about that same topic. I’ve been struggling through an iPhone app icon design, and had asked Twitter for help. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an app icon design that needs some criticism as I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of it. Anyone free to give me some time via email today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving problems with naïvety</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/solving-problems-with-naivety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 14:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/solving-problems-with-naivety/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was at the wonderful Future Insights Live conference in Las Vegas. Annoyingly as I was speaking twice (that bit wasn’t annoying, it was fun!) I missed a load of talks, but had some fantastic discussions around some particularly interesting topics.
The topic of naïvety in user experience first came up in Aral Balkan’s brilliant opening keynote, but using it as an approach it was an ongoing theme through the week, summed up by Josh Clark:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures in Web Design 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-in-web-design-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 10:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-in-web-design-2012/</guid>
      <description>My digest post about New Adventures in Web Design conference –; The Job, The Process and Creativity –; NAConf 2012 is now up on uBelly.
I’m now on board with uBelly to cover conferences and other webby stuff. This post is very much the same style as my previous digest posts, but on a different site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing For Emotion</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/designing-for-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 09:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/designing-for-emotion/</guid>
      <description>I bought Designing For Emotion as part of the A Book Apart deal, alongside Mobile First. After listening to Jeffery Zeldman talking about the release of these books with Dan Benjamin on The Big Web Show, and hearing how they were perfect books to read before a redesign (my site is in a constant state of awaiting redesign) I was really eager to get stuck in. Oddly, I decided to read Mobile First second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Designing the invisible</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-the-invisible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 08:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-practical-guide-to-designing-the-invisible/</guid>
      <description>After reading Mark Boulton’s A Practical Guide to Designing For The Web and Andy Clarke’s Hardboiled Web Design, I was keen to read another Five Simple Steps’ design book. Robert Mills’ A Practical Guide to Designing the invisible definitely didn’t disappoint.
   It took me a few reads to start getting into it. I haven’t been dedicating enough time to reading lately, so when I did it was stop-start and not concentrating properly, so I’ve decided to read a chapter a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>I’ve tried to condense my notes from Ampersand conference into a more useful digest. More than anything this, like my live-tweeting at past conferences, is really a selfish activity to help me absorb the ideas from Ampersand better by reflecting on the themes of the day.
And of course in the spirit of the web and all things good, I may as well share this digest so anyone who wasn’t there might get a taste of the event (albeit through my probably-twisted interpretation and slightly dodgy writing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — Actual Notes</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/notes-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/notes-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>For those who wanted my notes in an undigested, scatterbrained form, here’s images from my notebook. (My digest is available too.)
I’m a mind-mapping fiend, so I try to link with arrows where I can. Where new points were begun I just moved to another space on the page, so forgive the random appearance! There’s not much point apologising for my bad handwriting, I can’t really help that (all caps is a pretty dodgy habit) but there are some points, notably during Jonathan Hoefler’s talk, where the lights were low so it’s particularly illegible there&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks and Getting Over Moleskine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/notebooks-and-getting-over-moleskine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 12:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/notebooks-and-getting-over-moleskine/</guid>
      <description>I’m a notebook and sketchbook-aholic. Actually I’m addicted to stationery of any kind. Pens, pencils, post-it notes. It’s incredibly easy to convince myself I need these items when I mostly don’t.
Notebooks and sketchbooks (and maybe some nice accompanying pens), however, are an absolutely vital part of my working life.
Why bother with physical notebooks? Evernote isn’t the same as writing by hand. Neither is any other note-making software. Balsamiq isn’t the same as wireframing by hand, or Photoshop for sketching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</guid>
      <description>After I finished my last post about Design Tips for Developers, it really struck me how much I wrote to justify my design. I wasn’t just writing tips saying “*do this, it’s good*“, “*don’t do this, it’s bad.*” I put time and effort into explaining why I made these decisions and why I didn’t do it another way.
When I send a design to a client via e-mail, I usually spend around 45 minutes –; 1 hour writing an accompanying ‘justification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips For Developers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>This little post is based around the talk I gave at Bathcamp. Rich Quick came up with the great idea that, whilst Bathcamp attendees are mostly developers, a talk on design for developers was probably appropriate.
And you might have seen on my post from last week, I was looking for a case study to use in my talk. As happens with everything, I just didn’t have time to include the case study in the talk, so I thought I would blog it here as a follow-up from Bathcamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on a design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</guid>
      <description>After discussing Dribbble and Forrst, and my latest post that looked at criticism in design, I’ve been thinking a lot more about how feedback features in my design process.
Getting stuck When I used to get stuck on a design, from ‘creative block’ or a complete lack of inspiration, I would frantically brainstorm, then browse inspiration sites, then ask the opinions of other designers. Usually the feedback from other designers would form the basis of my amendments, I’d gain inspiration from those changes and continue work from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good old designer snobbery is alive and kicking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</guid>
      <description>There’s one thing that I hate about being a designer and that’s the snobbery. Most, if not all, designers are a little bit guilty of looking down on other people’s work. Comments such as “Pah! They used Comic Sans” or “Ergh! Don’t they know reflections are so out of date now?”
These are comments I’m 100% guilty of saying, but I think the problem is the outlet. If it’s a quick chatter between friends then there’s not much lost except making yourself look like a bit of an arse, but start broadcasting these harsh judgements to the world and you’ll rapidly give the impression of a big ego, huge mouth and tiny brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dribbble and Forrst for feedback on a client project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 20:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I created a quickie logo for Andy Warburton’s mobile stock photography service Stockyoo. Andy was really keen on the idea of using Forrst and Dribbble for posting the progress of the project to get the opinions of potential users of a stock photography service and do some early promo for Stockyoo itself.
Dribbble and Forrst Dribbble and Forrst are part of a new wave of sites aimed at (mostly web) designers and developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2010</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</guid>
      <description>I was a bit skeptical about dConstruct at first. The idea of a conference based on ‘creativity and ideas’ made me worry it might be a bit pretentious but I was convinced by a lot of friends on Twitter that it’d be worthwhile, and they were so right.
I went with a notebook and an open mind. I didn’t want to go all reverse-snob on the pretentious (something I’m generally pretty guilty of being) and be ignorant of learning when I’d paid ££s for the pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking Fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/picking-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 19:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/picking-fonts/</guid>
      <description>This little post is an extension of my post on Web Fonts.
Of late, some of the snobbier designers are whining that more fonts available will mean the web will get covered in horrible mis-use of fonts, unreadable body text and general ugliness.
I don’t think this is totally fair, but I’m sure some people might get confused by the variety of fonts that are around, so I thought I’d share a few things I try to keep in mind when choosing fonts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Fonts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-fonts/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a new infatuation; web fonts. Since the second I heard about Typekit (and Fontdeck) last year I’ve been giddy with excitement about being able to use more fonts on the web. Georgia just doesn’t cut it anymore. Even the introduction of ten new fonts to shake things up would have me flustered. Here’s a brief look at my experience of web fonts over the last year or so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>