<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Privacy on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 17:56:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tethered Beings</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tethered-beings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 17:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/tethered-beings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week the Ind.ie roundup returns with a big one. Great news on the UK surveillance legislation front, and lots of corporation news. Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/tethered-beings/&#34;&gt;Ind.ie roundup: Tethered Beings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/tethered-beings/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4782&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-17-at-18.49.31-1024x980.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Ind.ie roundup&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell Caspar</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/farewell-caspar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 10:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/farewell-caspar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We didn’t have an Ind.ie roundup the previous week because we were moving, though &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/july-update/&#34;&gt;Aral wrote a quick update on what’s happening with our move&lt;/a&gt;. Last week we were roundup-less again, as we heard the sad news that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caspar_Bowden&#34;&gt;Caspar Bowden&lt;/a&gt; had died. We decided that, instead of the usual roundup, we’d take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/farewell-caspar/&#34;&gt;Caspar’s privacy advocacy in tribute to his work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/farewell-caspar/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4779&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-13-at-11.41.11.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Farewell Caspar Ind.ie blog post&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Destiny Machine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-destiny-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 08:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-destiny-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/the-destiny-machine/&#34;&gt;Last Friday’s roundup&lt;/a&gt; was back to business as usual, after a couple of weeks of re:publica-related work. We’ve got the latest in the world of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/you-are-the-product&#34;&gt;Spyware 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, and some fun ways that people are challenging the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/the-destiny-machine/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4734&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/05/Screen-Shot-2015-05-25-at-09.49.27.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Ind.ie Roundup titled The Destiny Machine&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on the Subjective podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 16:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the week, I had fun talking to Victor Johnson on &lt;a href=&#34;http://subjective.fm/episodes/9&#34;&gt;Episode 9 of the Subjective podcast, ‘Free As In Liberty.’&lt;/a&gt; I ranted &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;, and we talked about Ind.ie, diversity, my upbringing, and how I got into design and the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://subjective.fm&#34;&gt;Subjective&lt;/a&gt; is also a great podcast in its infancy, with Victor at the helm, it’s definitely one to watch (or listen!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe fights back</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/europe-fights-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 09:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/europe-fights-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/roundup-15-04-10/&#34;&gt;Last Friday’s Ind.ie roundup&lt;/a&gt; had more on corporate surveillance, a couple of great videos with Edward Snowden, and Europe fighting back against Google and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to pull it all together. I’m going to have to start writing my Friday roundups on Thursday! If you know of any interesting or relevant links, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laura@ind.ie&#34; title=&#34;Email Laura at Ind.ie&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Friday Roundup for Ind.ie</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-friday-roundup-for-ind-ie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 15:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-friday-roundup-for-ind-ie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Friday I write a roundup of great links we at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie&#34;&gt;Ind.ie&lt;/a&gt; have seen over the last week. I’m not going to lie, it’s a lot of fun. I finally have an excuse to sit and properly read articles that are related to independence, privacy, human rights, democracy, diversity and more. I feel more well-informed as a result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roundups started out as just lists of links, but have now evolved into a little article each week where I collect the best reads together under common themes and occasionally a bit of analysis. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/roundup-15-04-04/&#34;&gt;Read today’s Friday Roundup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusion Of Free on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-illusion-of-free-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/the-illusion-of-free&#34;&gt;my column on The Illusion Of Free&lt;/a&gt; was published on A List Apart. I took a lot of time writing it, as I think it’s an incredibly important issue, and it reflects my thinking around &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie&#34;&gt;Ind.ie&lt;/a&gt;. As ever, a massive thank you to the wonderful editor Rose Weisburd who helped me round things out, made me sound smarter and encouraged me in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/the-illusion-of-free&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4639&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/04/Illusion-of-Free.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of column on The Illusion of Free&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt; was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-with-the-network&#34;&gt;Living with the network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-freedom&#34;&gt;Technology and freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living with the network is more about social interaction than it is about technology. When new technology is introduced, it brings more issues around social change and social acceptance than it does around the features, gadgets and gimmicks of the technology itself. As an industry, we’ve set up systems that serve the majority, but only provide benefits to the few. Georgina Voss’s talk about distribution systems covered how the postal networks allowed governments to censor media through distribution channels. These examples had alarming parallels with the internet as a distribution channel allowing for censorship through a centralised system. It was a strong warning about the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.battleforthenet.com/sept10th/&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cory Doctorow put it, “it’s not a fight about information, it’s a fight about people. And people want to be free.” And for people (and information) to be free, the information networks need to be free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-and-surveillance&#34;&gt;Privacy and surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to privacy and surveillance, we are currently frogs sitting in a pot of warm water. The water is slowly being boiled around us, our privacy and freedom being slowly taken from us by governments and corporations. We won’t notice we’re being boiled until it’s too late, we won’t notice that our privacy and freedom has been irreversibly damaged until it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already in trouble and this is why we need to talk more, and act more, on the issues of privacy and surveillance. We need to bring these issues to the fore so we don’t become the frogs in the boiling water. As Tom Scott said in his vision of 2030, “privacy was already dead, it’s that not everyone agreed with it yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-diversity&#34;&gt;Technology and diversity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy Brown emphasised how the effect of technology on society around us isn’t just about the individual, and our own selfish gains. At least it shouldn’t be. With the lack of diversity in the web and tech industries, we’re creating technology for the privileged. When we’re creating products to scratch our own itch, and solve our own problems, we’re largely creating products for young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctorow pointed out that business models don’t exist in a vacuum, they reflect political, economic and social needs. And following the lines of Mandy Brown’s talk, the political, economic and social needs that we’re currently serving are largely those of young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-was-a-brief-summary&#34;&gt;This was a brief summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My post is a little summary of some of the themes that jumped out at me over the course of Friday. Lucky for you, &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/dConstruct/tags/dconstruct2014&#34;&gt;all the talks are available in audio format on huffduffer&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re well worth a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4537&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/dconstruct-2014.png&#34; alt=&#34;dConstruct 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiephone.eu&#34;&gt;Indie Phone&lt;/a&gt; for 50% of my working time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What is Indie Phone?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has opened our data up to a lot of potential abuse, including the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.democracynow.org/2013/10/14/edward_snowden_speaks_out_against_nsa&#34;&gt;government dragnet surveillance employed by the NSA and GCHQ (and other governments)&lt;/a&gt;. For users aware of these problems, we can either choose to share our data, or be excluded from the majority of services (and social interactions) on the web. Worse still, the majority of general consumers on the web are unaware of these problems. There are loose, and often misleading, privacy settings on these services. Few people realise that they’re still sharing their data with the companies that own their services, and many other third parties. Even fewer people realise that their email and private messages are being stored, and potentially read and shared, with these services and third parties. To find out more about these issues, I really recommend watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thersa.org/events/audio-and-past-events/2014/Free-is-a-Lie&#34;&gt;Aral’s talk, ‘Free Is a Lie’&lt;/a&gt;, and watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://tacma.net/&#34;&gt;‘Terms and Conditions May Apply’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indie Phone aims to create a smart phone that isn’t just for the tech folk that want to take control over their data. We want to create experiences that combine hardware, software, and the cloud, as well as appealing to the everyday consumer. The fact that it’ll be open, and allows you to take control of your data, and choose what you want to be shared, is an essential bonus. It’s incredibly important that these tools are available to everybody. We don’t want to discriminate against those with less tech experience or knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing like Indie Phone. There are a few fantastic companies and products working towards other &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;indie technologies&lt;/a&gt;. Together we can try to make technology, and the web, more open and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-indie-tech&#34;&gt;What’s indie tech?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data-hungry services have become the norm. Indie Technologies have sustainable business models and offer alternatives to these services. These alternative products need to be design-led and consumer-friendly so they can realistically compete in the consumer market. At Indie Phone, we’re spearheading indie tech, we want to be a great example to other indie technologies. We also have plans to help support and promote other indie tech projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-work-with-indie-phone-when-i-love-client-work-so-much&#34;&gt;Why work with Indie Phone when I love client work so much?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been very trendy lately to switch from client work to a side project or product. A lot of designers and developers don’t enjoy client services. But I do. I really really love working with clients, and helping them achieve their goals. It’s similar to why I love Indie Phone. I like providing services to people who otherwise may not be able to create their own site or understand what would work for them on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been Chief Sounding Board for the last 10 months, as &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral&lt;/a&gt; has researched, planned, brainstormed and agonised over Codename Prometheus and Indie Phone. It’s been his life for nearly a year, so in turn has been a huge part of my life. I have absolute faith in his ability to see it through. It’s been hard sitting on the sidelines, desperately wanting to help, but not being able to dedicate the time and money that a project of this size really needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sale of Aral’s family’s home in Ankara, we finally have funds to afford other people to work on the Indie Phone up to crowd funding. Money is still tight, we can’t afford me to work on Indie Phone 100% of the time, and this works for me. The money is far better spent on other valuable skills required to get us up-and-running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-do-for-indie-phone&#34;&gt;What I do for Indie Phone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design and web development. Web is my specialism, so the most expertise I can offer Indie Phone is in producing the websites, mini sites and other web-based materials. I also work on the branding and other general graphic design tasks. Sometimes I do some writing, and I do a lot of editing. All of my work is collaborative. Aral, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jo-porter.com/&#34;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt; and I all review and critique each others’ work, and this is an exciting new experience for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-other-50-of-my-time&#34;&gt;What about the other 50% of my time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can still carry on the relationships I have with my existing clients, and take on a few new clients, with a decent amount of time to dedicate to client work. I love the variety of client work, and I really enjoy working with different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-want-to-work-with-other-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;I want to work with other indie tech projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been picky with new projects, I only work with clients that I care about and projects that interest me. That’s how I do my best work. And lately, as I’ve been absolutely influenced by Indie Phone, I really care about the success of indie tech projects. Is your project design-led, free and open, and independent in line with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indietech.org/manifesto/&#34;&gt;Indie Technology Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;? Then I’ve got a deal for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;20-off-for-indie-tech-projects&#34;&gt;20% off for indie tech projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to put my money where my mouth is. I want to work on indie tech projects so much, that I will work for 20% less (on my hourly rate) for an indie tech project. This will be expensive for me, but I want to do more to help indie technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-can-i-offer-an-indie-tech-project&#34;&gt;What can I offer an indie tech project?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I’m an all-round designer. With design-led projects, the majority of indie tech projects probably have a designer in place already, but I’m here for support and strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/graphic-design/&#34; title=&#34;Graphic Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. From logos to typography to icons for your avatars, I can create your brand and show you how to use it effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/web-app-and-mobile-design/&#34; title=&#34;Web, App and Mobile Design&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I love the web. If it’s working out the experience for your app, I can help you with design and front-end development. With marketing sites, I can promote your product with an end-to-end solution (copy to content management system, I can do all of that.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in my 20% discount, please &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@laurakalbag.com?subject=Indie%20Tech Project&#34;&gt;send me an email at me@laurakalbag.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-huge-but-also-not-so-huge&#34;&gt;It’s huge, but also not so huge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this hasn’t changed much. I’m still working from home, as the Indie Phone office is currently occupying the largest room in our house. I’m still working on projects I love with people that I love. I’m very lucky :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-29759&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9d852ad65e88b3836261a29d427849b2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://designack.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ngaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-29759&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-04T08:45:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:45am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        What a great idea Laura! I really hope it goes well for you. Having a side project that you’re passionate about can make your client work even better too I think. It’s having that freedom to do something where you can see your creativity bloom while making a difference that is great about side projects.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-32622&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fbf4c8ab7c5db6d39bfbff46042b67?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Ran&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-32622&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-06-16T01:00:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;01:00am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Keep us posted on Indie Phone, sounds good.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
