<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Designers on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/designers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Designers on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/designers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-design/</guid>
      <description>Every now and again someone will email me asking how they should go about learning design. After reading Aral Balkan’s fantastic post on how design is not veneer, a few developers also expressed frustration at there not being many resources telling you how to get started with design. So I thought I’d post a few of my favourite links, books and ways of approaching design.
First off, read Aral’s post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on a design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</guid>
      <description>After discussing Dribbble and Forrst, and my latest post that looked at criticism in design, I’ve been thinking a lot more about how feedback features in my design process.
Getting stuck When I used to get stuck on a design, from ‘creative block’ or a complete lack of inspiration, I would frantically brainstorm, then browse inspiration sites, then ask the opinions of other designers. Usually the feedback from other designers would form the basis of my amendments, I’d gain inspiration from those changes and continue work from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good old designer snobbery is alive and kicking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</guid>
      <description>There’s one thing that I hate about being a designer and that’s the snobbery. Most, if not all, designers are a little bit guilty of looking down on other people’s work. Comments such as “Pah! They used Comic Sans” or “Ergh! Don’t they know reflections are so out of date now?”
These are comments I’m 100% guilty of saying, but I think the problem is the outlet. If it’s a quick chatter between friends then there’s not much lost except making yourself look like a bit of an arse, but start broadcasting these harsh judgements to the world and you’ll rapidly give the impression of a big ego, huge mouth and tiny brain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>