<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 14:21:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 14:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-2014/</guid>
      <description>Well, things didn’t slow down in 2014! So much so that I didn’t manage to write this post yesterday. In 2014 I spoke at 8 events in 4 countries, and worked with 11 clients on 15 projects before starting work full time with Ind.ie in August.
I wrote a lot more, with regular slots onA List Apart and The Pastry Box, and a series on Getting Started With Sass on Web Standards Sherpa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 81 and 82</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 18:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</guid>
      <description>I was so busy last week that I forgot to post about Unfinished Business episode 81: Do you have a dinosaur onesie? This week, Ashley and I recorded episode 82: Love a good pep talk.
It’s been a fun few weeks. It’s been interesting how a lot of people have said that Ashley and I focused more on business-related topics than Andy’s recent episodes. That may well be the case, but it wasn’t really intentional, or because we think the podcast should be more business-focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 72: Big Bad Boy Breakfast Bap</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 16:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-72/</guid>
      <description>This week’s episode of Unfinished Business was great fun to record. After my recent move to working on Indie Phone, alongside my boyfriend Aral Balkan, I was curious to know how Andy and Sue have worked so well together since the beginning of Stuff and Nonsense.
I sent Sue some questions, which she answered and sent back to me, without Andy seeing the answers. During the show, I asked Andy about his thoughts and read Sue’s answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April’s Pastry Box thought on writing</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 09:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I was slow to post aboutmy April Pastry Box post as my realign got in the way. It was really a little insecure thought about how my writing and thinking is improving, but I’m finding it hard.
[  ](https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-april-19)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #64</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-64/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. It was a special episode as Rachel Andrew was also a guest (yeah, I designed her site!) I don’t like to go on about stuff like this too often, but if you’d told 21 year old me (7 years ago) that I’d be appearing on a podcast with Andy Clarke and Rachel Andrew, it would’ve blown my mind. They’re two very lovely people whose writing helped me learn about, and become so excited about, the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love this pen</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 09:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-love-this-pen/</guid>
      <description>It’s a J Herbin metal pen. It’s a rollerball but it takes any standard ink cartridge. I use it with the J Herbin ink cartridges as they come in loads of different colours and packaged in cute little tins.
It’s taken me years to find my ideal pen. I have small hands so I need something that isn’t too chunky or heavy. The J Herbin pen has a quality weight but doesn’t hurt if I’ve been writing for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies In Tech</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, Jeremy Keith introduced me to ladiesintech.com, suggesting that it might be something that’d interest me. After having a chat with the lovely Jenn Lukas over email, I had a story that I wanted to share about my adventures in speaking, and Jenn has now helped me share it on the site.
This was the first time I’ve ever had anybody edit my writing. I’ve had other people proof-read and check my writing for mistakes, but never changing that much (despite often needing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</guid>
      <description>After I finished my last post about Design Tips for Developers, it really struck me how much I wrote to justify my design. I wasn’t just writing tips saying “*do this, it’s good*“, “*don’t do this, it’s bad.*” I put time and effort into explaining why I made these decisions and why I didn’t do it another way.
When I send a design to a client via e-mail, I usually spend around 45 minutes –; 1 hour writing an accompanying ‘justification’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
