<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Pastry Box on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/the-pastry-box/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Pastry Box on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:16:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/the-pastry-box/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 reasons why you should get an office dog</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/5-reasons-why-you-should-get-an-office-dog/</guid>
      <description>Last week I wrote my Pastry Box thought on 5 reasons why you should get an office dog. It’s not just silly photos of Oskar, but actually five reasons why having Oskar for company has helped keep me sane. Through living and working by myself, to living and working with other people, he’s still incredibly valuable as a companion.
And if you do happen to like dog photos, you might want to follow @gigapup on Twitter or app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time, my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April’s Pastry Box thought on writing</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 09:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/marchs-pastry-box-thought-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I was slow to post aboutmy April Pastry Box post as my realign got in the way. It was really a little insecure thought about how my writing and thinking is improving, but I’m finding it hard.
[  ](https://the-pastry-box-project.net/laura-kalbag/2014-april-19)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March’s Pastry Box thought on purpose</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/pastry-box-march/</guid>
      <description>Today my thought for March was posted on The Pastry Box. It was inspired by First Things First 2014, talks by Cole Peters and Nicklas de León Persson at Design and Banter, and Fictive Kin‘s slashpurpose.org.
I’ve started formulating a draft of my “purpose” for this site, but it’s not quite ready yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing on The Pastry Box and my first post on ethics</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/writing-on-the-pastry-box/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my first “thought” of the year is published on The Pastry Box. When Alex asked me if I wanted to be a part of The Pastry Box project, I leapt at the chance. There are some fantastic people who have contributed such interesting thoughts and ideas over there in the last couple of years, and looking at the lineup for this year, I’m sure that won’t be changing anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>