<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:26:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 418:conf web meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the very first 418:conf web meetup on 16th June 2015 in Nutfield (near Redhill) in Surrey. It’s exciting for me because it’s near where I used to live, and it’s a cool new meetup with a lot of potential.
If you’re local, you should get your ticket now. They’re free!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at the Sherpa Summit</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-sherpa-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 10:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-sherpa-summit/</guid>
      <description>Last October, Web Standards Sherpa published my mini series on Getting Started With Sass. It was a whole new experience as I’d never written a technical tutorial as in-depth as this, let alone doing so with a proper editor and technical editor. Web Standards Sherpa is like that; all about the quality. So it was sad to hear about Sherpa closing its doors this year. However, in order to keep the site and all its wonderful resources online forever, Web Standards Sherpa is hosting an online conference on the 23rd April, and I’m speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Web Day at Bath Digital Festival</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-web-day-at-bath-digital-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 14:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-web-day-at-bath-digital-festival/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at Web Day at Bath Digital Festival on the 28th of October. Bath is great, I went to university there, and it’s full of lovely people. I’m looking forward to going back and giving a talk about accessibility. Tickets are a very reasonable £15, and it looks like it’ll be a very interesting day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at border:none</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking and running a “creator unit” at border:none in Nuremberg. This is incredibly exciting as it’s an event focused around the decentralisation of the web, a topic that I care about a great deal. I’ll be talking about using considerate design and great user experiences to create genuine alternatives to the products that make money from exploiting their users’ data.
It’s also an all-new topic for me to share with other people, so I can’t wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s dConstruct was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a diverse speaker lineup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</guid>
      <description>This post is so good, and so incredibly valuable, that it’s deserving of more than just a passing tweet. Julie Pagano has written about ‘Building a Diverse Speaker Lineup.’ This should be the go-to post for conference organisers, and it should be read as soon as you’re even thinking about organising an event.
Julie’s post doesn’t just explain why you want a diverse lineup (also worth reading on this topic: Aral’s post, On design and diversity), but also how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indie Tech Summit videos and my talk on Universal Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we finally published all the videos from the Indie Tech Summit on the ind.ie site. It was a fantastic event, with two days of talking about how we can create sustainable and ethical alternatives to corporate surveillance. The first day was talks and panels, with everyone discussing the problems and their own free and open solutions. The second day had workshops and discussion groups where we talked about where we could go from there, and what we could do as a community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discount code for WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen that I’m speaking at WXG in Guildford in September. If you didn’t already get a ticket, you might want to use my discount code of kalbagWXG to get £10 off the (already very affordable £99) ticket price.
There’s some great speakers in the lineup, and it’s sure to be a fun day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with public speaking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/how-to-get-started-with-public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/how-to-get-started-with-public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the wonderful Ashley Baxter asked me about how I got into public speaking. Ashley asked a few cool people, and published their public speaking stories on the Insurance By Jack blog.
By the way, if you want business insurance, you really should get a quote from Insurance By Jack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at KiwiParty in Strasbourg</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-kiwiparty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 07:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-kiwiparty/</guid>
      <description>On the 13th of June, I’m speaking at KiwiParty in Strasbourg. I’ll be speaking about web accessibility.
It’ll be my first conference in France and I’ll be trying to remember my French from AS Level ten years ago! I won’t be giving my talk in my terrible French, but if you’re coming along, please find me and test my conversational French. Especially if you want a good laugh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video interview for Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/video-interview-for-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 17:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/video-interview-for-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 Last week I had a chat with my friend Steve Fisher about my upcoming talk and workshop at Interlink conference and all things Canadian. It was a fun way to end the day, and is complete with me doing a really terrible Canadian accent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 10:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford in September. This is exciting for me because I attended the first ever WXG a couple of years ago, and it’s about as local as a conference is going to get to my hometown, Reigate.
The tickets are a bargain at just £69 for early birds, and there’s already a great lineup with still more to be announced…
I’m going to talk about how we design the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web workshop at Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 I’m running my ‘Design theory for the web’ workshop at Interlink conference in Canada on the 18th of June.
 
It’s a one day workshop and I’ve written a mega description below for anyone wanting to know more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Design &#43; Banter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at Design + Banter on Monday in London. It’s already sold out, but there’s a waiting list available for the free tickets.
Nicklas Persson and Cole Peters are also speaking so I’m really chuffed to be part of a great lineup!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Interlink conference in Toronto</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 11:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 This is very very exciting. In June, I’m going to speak at Interlink conference in Toronto, Canada. The line-up is incredible, and I can’t believe I’m a part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at DotYork</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dotyork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dotyork/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at DotYork conference in York on the 1st of May. My friend Jonic is one of the organisers, and with the thought and love that they’re putting into the event, it’s got to be fantastic.
It’ll be my first time in York, so I’m looking forward to seeing the sights and feeling incredibly Southern. You should join me! Early bird tickets are coming out soon, so why not go over to the DotYork website and sign up to be the first to hear when tickets are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 12 Devs of Winter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at 12 Devs of Winter on the 22nd January in Shoreditch. Because I’ve clearly lost my mind, I’m going to be doing another new talk. This time on ‘Freelancing for the reluctant businessperson.’ I’m that reluctant businessperson, and I’m hoping to share some silly stories about all the daft things I’ve done and some of the things that have worked out just fine.
For once, I’m ahead of the schedule, and tickets will be released this Wednesday 8th January at 10am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Beyond Ink podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-beyond-ink-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the first episode of the Beyond Ink podcast went live. This was a podcast that Rachel had in the works for a while, and we first recorded together a few months ago. Last week we re-recorded that episode, so everything was up-to-date, and I had a fancy new microphone so I didn’t sound as terrible as I did on the last Unfinished Business.
Rachel and I chatted about process, the type of work we like to do and inspiration, amongst other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MKGN this Thursday</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</guid>
      <description>This Thursday I’m speaking at Milton Keynes Geek Night. Tickets sold out terrifyingly quickly, but I put that down to MKGN always being a great event.
I’m going to talk about self-discipline, it’s a new talk and so that makes me even more nervous than usual &#34; /</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about building with Typecast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/talking-about-building-with-typecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/talking-about-building-with-typecast/</guid>
      <description>Last November at Build conference 2012, I had fun talking to some of the folks from Typecast about building, web design, responsive design and type. They recorded these videos (along with a load of lovely, smart and cool people!) and made a nice collection that you can watch on their website.
Typecast are also giving away a ticket to Build conference 2013 and some Typecast subscriptions. The draw closes tomorrow, so you’d better be quick!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>The lovely people at Dare conference have released the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”
I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that there’s loads of great talks on there, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I also pledge to be better</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 07:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</guid>
      <description>This post was inspired by Faruk’s great post “I Pledge To Be Better (And I Hope You Do Too)” where he speaks about the continuing problems with discrimination and lack of diversity in tech, and how more people should speak up about these issues. Faruk rightly says we all have the power and responsibility to make things better. I believe that when we don’t speak out about discrimination, we’re almost causing as much damage as condoning discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Next Friday I’m speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin about designing for accessibility, covering problems that affect many different types of screens and devices. It will be my first time in Germany, so I’m very excited!
 
One comment ### Anna  at 10:34am
 Hello there, I very much enjoyed your talk about accessibility at the mobXconference last friday. Is there any chance you can put your slides online?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web, a workshop</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a slightly scary thing: I’m doing my first solo workshop on the 11th October 2013 in Barnsley.
I often get asked about the best way to “learn design”, and I usually say that you learn by doing and you learn by watching how others do it. In this workshop, I want to give new designers, developers, and anybody else wanting to learn how to design for the web, a good foundation with five primers, a bit of doing and a bit of watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass for designers — the talk and the case study</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 09:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/sass-for-designers-the-talk-and-the-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I gave a talk at the fantastic online conference CSS Summit on ‘Sass for designers’. It uses my new site Web Talk Dog Walk as a case study, and explains the basics of Sass and how to get started using CodeKit.
Usually I wouldn’t recommend checking out my slides, as they’re useless without me explaining them, but as this was an online conference and I wanted the slides to be extra clear in case of technical problems, they hopefully read in a fairly easy-to-follow way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web talk dog walk, the site</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 17:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-the-site/</guid>
      <description>I’ve finally made a site for the web talk dog walks! It may be a small site, and is probably very broken in places, but it was a fun mini project and worked well as a case study for my Sass for designers talk.
It also makes use of Perch, that wonderful little content management system. I really would recommend it.
 
One comment ### Richelle Cortis  at 16:10pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at Dare conference in September. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.
Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web talk dog walk II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 09:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk-2/</guid>
      <description>The last web talk dog walk was a success, with three of us (plus three dogs) taking in the slightly damp wilds of Sheepcote Valley. Now for the next one!
I was originally planning on making them fortnightly but have already failed as I wasn’t organised enough to sort one out this week. This means the next Web talk dog walk will be:
9am on Wednesday 3rd July 2013 Meeting at the same spot on the corner of Wilson Avenue and Roedean Road planning to walk for an hour or so (maybe slightly longer if I continue navigating badly) in East Brighton Park/Sheepcote valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Critters 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-critters-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 19:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-critters-2013/</guid>
      <description>After winning the .net award two weeks ago, I really wasn’t expecting to win another award. Last night at a fun black tie, storybook-themed ubelly Critters awards, I won Next Big Thing.
 
Like before, I really wasn’t expecting it and made another bad speech, swore a little (I’m sorry!) and almost walked off without having my photo taken. I think you can tell I’m not used to this kind of thing…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Untangle the Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Nothing quite like a last-minute post… Tonight I’m speaking at Untangle the Web at Google Campus in London. I’m doing a talk on Design Theory for the Web where I do a whistle-stop tour through designing with typography, grids and colour on the web.
I also have a stinking cold so I’m going to be taking industrial quantities of Red Bull and a quarantine zone with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web talk dog walk</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 16:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/web-talk-dog-walk/</guid>
      <description>I walk my dog Oskar every day, no matter what the weather. And usually it’s just him and me. So I’ve got this idea. A “web talk dog walk” where a group of us from the Brighton area can meet on a regular basis (probably fortnightly, maybe monthly) to walk dogs and chat about the web. Do you want to join us?
The first walk is 9am this Wednesday 12th June 2013 The best place to walk in the area (and conveniently near to where we live is East Brighton Park/Sheepcote valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at LXJS in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>I’m really looking forward to October, where I get to return to Portugal to speak at LXJS in Lisbon.
One of the reasons I jumped at the chance to speak at LXJS was their fantastic Code of Conduct. After hearing some horror stories from other women speakers, I wish more conferences had this sort of approach. It’s friendly, not strict, and lets everybody know where they stand.
The tickets are incredibly reasonable for a two-day event, and it looks like Lisbon is well-worth a holiday so a conference there is a bonus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#define 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</guid>
      <description>Next Saturday I’m speaking at #define 2013, a “diversity in computing festival” for 11-13 year old students who wouldn’t usually consider careers in computing.
It’s an event aimed at improving diversity in computing and I’m really proud to be speaking. I’m going to talk about a day in the life of a web designer/developer in the hope that I can share the variety involved in this kind of work and how rewarding and fun this job can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.net awards 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/netmag-awards-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 09:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/netmag-awards-2013/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, this happened. I really didn’t expect it; I tripped over on the way up to the stage and mumbled through a thank you while the microphone was mostly switched off. Despite being clumsy and totally inarticulate, I was delighted. It didn’t just make my day, it made my year :)
 
3 comments ### Lucas  at 01:20am
 Congratulations, Laura! You deserved it!   ### enrico  at 12:01pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest co-host on Unfinished Business again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.
I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!
 
Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage One of the sponsors this week was Slide + Stage, a full-day intensive masterclass with Aral Balkan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass For Designers at CSS Summit 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/css-summit-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 09:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/css-summit-2013/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at CSS Summit 2013 about Sass For Designers. CSS Summit is a great online conference, meaning you can attend from anywhere in the world (hooray!)
There’s a huge amount of expert speakers across three days, with a day each dedicated to CSS3 Training, Advanced CSS and Preprocessors. I’m on the third day, covering the basics of Sass with ‘Sass for Designers’. The other talks on that day will cover Sass in more depth, with case studies and more advanced techniques, so I’m hoping to provide a useful introduction for those of us who are less familiar with programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to speak</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year ago, I was in a country I’d never visited, about to give two talks I’d never given before to two large, paying audiences in the space of three days at Future Insights Live. I had only given a couple of talks to small audiences before. It was one of the scariest things I’d ever done.
A helping hand I’d seen Aral Balkan speak a few times before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was guest co-host on one of my most favourite podcasts, Unfinished Business. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.
We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Breaking Borders</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-breaking-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-breaking-borders/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking at Breaking Borders. Breaking Borders is a brand new, totally free, bi-monthly event in Reading organised by my good friend, Ben MacGowan.
The inaugural Breaking Borders event will have the lovely Steve Workman speaking about Front-end web architectures that won’t bite you (in the ass) and me speaking about design systems.
If you’re in the area, I really recommend you join us. If Ben’s events are anything like his front-end development skills, it’s going to be great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies In Tech</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, Jeremy Keith introduced me to ladiesintech.com, suggesting that it might be something that’d interest me. After having a chat with the lovely Jenn Lukas over email, I had a story that I wanted to share about my adventures in speaking, and Jenn has now helped me share it on the site.
This was the first time I’ve ever had anybody edit my writing. I’ve had other people proof-read and check my writing for mistakes, but never changing that much (despite often needing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Wing podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 09:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was a guest on Tim Smith‘s The East Wing podcast. It was a pre-recorded conversation and it was great fun. You can listen to it on the East Wing website, and it’ll be up on iTunes soon.
We discussed how I got started in the industry (really sorry traditional Graphic Design people, I may have generalised a bit…), speaking at conferences, women in the industry and mentoring.
As I said last night on Twitter, Tim Smith is such a great guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and conferences</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 21:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I used to not understand the fuss around women at conferences, I thought that we should all just carry on with what we were doing well already and not get caught up in needless controversy. I even wrote a blog post saying exactly that a couple of years ago. I’d never experienced (to my knowledge) any difficulties because I was a woman.
A bit uncomfortable But then I started hearing more about/was exposed to women who did have bad experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live-designing WordPress Admin Icons</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I wrotea post about how I was going to do a talk at WordPress London where I would try to design a WordPress admin icon live. Well, I did it, and it didn’t go too badly. In fact, I was very lucky as the first suggestion for what I should design was a calendar icon. That’s mostly squares, so not too tricky!
  The final calendar icons (as designed quickly in 30 minutes or so)   The WordPress London guys kindly filmed my talk and I’ve included it below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at the WordPress London January meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the WordPress London January meetup on the 17th of January 2013.
I’ve been using WordPress for years, for my own site and for client sites, and I really love it. I had absolutely no idea what to talk about though. I tend to create custom themes for clients, but these are very different from themes designed for use by many different sites, and so I wasn’t sure whether my experience would be relevant to many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvention and Building Ourselves — Build 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/reinvention-and-building-ourselves-build-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 18:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/reinvention-and-building-ourselves-build-2012/</guid>
      <description>I’ve posted a writeup of Build conference 2012 on ubelly.
Oddly, I’ve not found any other writeups from Build, which may be because (as I mention in my post) the talks weren’t those sound-bite talks that give quick take away tips. If anyone does come across any, please point me in the right direction as I’d love to see how other people approached the wide-ranging stories!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Xmas Special—Integrity and Polarity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 08:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-xmas-special-integrity-and-polarity/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was Insites: The Xmas Special, a brilliant event put on by the lovely Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks. After being well fed, everybody in the room gave a six minute(ish) talk about something they’ve learned in 2012.
It was a personal, open and incredibly meaningful set of talks. There were no slides, and nobody in the room was sat behind a laptop or Twitter. The conversations that ensued afterwards were greater than anything you’d get at any big conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography and the web at Ampersand Conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a big old writeup for ubelly from my notes at Ampersand conference earlier in the month.
This was an event I decided not to live-tweet, as the content is usually more involved and in-depth, making for a better big writeup and less tweetable quotes.
Typography and the web at Ampersand conference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craft and Care: Future Of Web Design 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 09:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/craft-and-care-future-of-web-design-2012/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written up my digest of Future Of Web Design 2012 over at the ubelly blog.
For those who want more of a blow-by-blow account of the day, I’ve compiled all of my live tweets (and retweets) from the day in a Storify feed.
http://storify.com/laurakalbag/laura-kalbag-s-fowd-tweets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving problems with naïvety</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/solving-problems-with-naivety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 14:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/solving-problems-with-naivety/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was at the wonderful Future Insights Live conference in Las Vegas. Annoyingly as I was speaking twice (that bit wasn’t annoying, it was fun!) I missed a load of talks, but had some fantastic discussions around some particularly interesting topics.
The topic of naïvety in user experience first came up in Aral Balkan’s brilliant opening keynote, but using it as an approach it was an ongoing theme through the week, summed up by Josh Clark:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures in Web Design 2012</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-in-web-design-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 10:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-in-web-design-2012/</guid>
      <description>My digest post about New Adventures in Web Design conference –; The Job, The Process and Creativity –; NAConf 2012 is now up on uBelly.
I’m now on board with uBelly to cover conferences and other webby stuff. This post is very much the same style as my previous digest posts, but on a different site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2011 — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2011-my-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 10:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2011-my-digest/</guid>
      <description>It was another inspiring day at dConstruct, the best abstract thought-inducing conference around.
The abstract nature of the conference is part of the appeal for most people. It’s hard to get enthusiastic about a talk that is teaching you more practical techniques, such as writing HTML, when you can so easily learn about it on the web in your own time. Conferences that inspire your passion for the industry, exploring other disciplines and encouraging you to approach your everyday work from a different angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Tour Brighton</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Insites is a mini tour of four cities in the UK where Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks present discussions with well-known people from the web/tech industry. I was lucky enough to go to the first evening in Brighton on Monday where Aral Balkan, Sarah Parmenter and Jeremy Keith were the guests.
The Format The format of the evening was something unfamiliar to most of us. Each guest was interviewed by either Keir or Elliot and then there were questions from the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>I’ve tried to condense my notes from Ampersand conference into a more useful digest. More than anything this, like my live-tweeting at past conferences, is really a selfish activity to help me absorb the ideas from Ampersand better by reflecting on the themes of the day.
And of course in the spirit of the web and all things good, I may as well share this digest so anyone who wasn’t there might get a taste of the event (albeit through my probably-twisted interpretation and slightly dodgy writing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — Actual Notes</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/notes-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/notes-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>For those who wanted my notes in an undigested, scatterbrained form, here’s images from my notebook. (My digest is available too.)
I’m a mind-mapping fiend, so I try to link with arrows where I can. Where new points were begun I just moved to another space on the page, so forgive the random appearance! There’s not much point apologising for my bad handwriting, I can’t really help that (all caps is a pretty dodgy habit) but there are some points, notably during Jonathan Hoefler’s talk, where the lights were low so it’s particularly illegible there&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day Two</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Ethan Marcotte –; Responsive Web Design Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Femi T Adesina –; Enhancing your Creativity I mis-hastagged the first tweet!
Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
My thoughts at this point: Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch continued&amp;#8230; Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!
Day One Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.
Tweet
Tweet Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Review</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-the-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-the-review/</guid>
      <description>Another great event from Carsonified, I really enjoyed Future Of Web Design this year.
The Cost I was actually really lucky to get a ticket. I seriously couldn’t afford the £714 2-day conference pass, even at the super early bird rate (that was about £200 less, I can’t remember exactly.) My lovely friend Scott Coello had done the amazing motion graphics for the conference and very kindly gave me his spare ticket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yeah, so what if I live-tweet at conferences?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/yeah-so-what-if-i-live-tweet-at-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/yeah-so-what-if-i-live-tweet-at-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been at Future Of Web Design The last two days were long, but fantastic, experiences at Future Of Web Design. The talks were high quality, loads of cool people were there and I learnt a lot.
Problem is, (from some people’s point of view) I tweeted a lot. I’m not going to stop, but I thought I should explain why live tweeting isn’t just “trying to make yourself look clever by tweeting everything you hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big M</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 18:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</guid>
      <description>Big M badge   First off, let me declare my complete bias. I’ve been involved with the Big M conference from pretty early on, I was lucky enough to do all the design work and the organisers are lovely guys who I’m proud to call my friends. I’m still on a high from how much I enjoyed myself (and just about recovered from the surreal feeling of being in a place with my own design work everywhere) so this is really going to be the most biased event review you’ve ever read!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who wants a ticket for The Big M?</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/win-a-ticket-for-the-big-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 15:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/win-a-ticket-for-the-big-m/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know if you know, but I made the website for the upcoming super exciting mobile conference, The Big M.
 The Big M website   
As a result, I have 3 conference tickets worth £233.83 to give away to lovely people who want to learn more about mobile (covering topics such as innovation, usability, development, apps and mobile web.)
My 3 tickets are for the first day, the conference part of The Big M, which is on 21st March 2011 at Komedia in Bath (UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 13:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-in/</guid>
      <description>I’ve changed my mind about this subject! To read about why and how I don’t believe this anymore, please read Women and conferences.
Business…Tech…Conferences… Every time I hear these dreaded phrases, “*Women in business*”, “*Women in tech*”, “*Women at conferences*” I just groan. It’s really boring.
Examples. “*There’s only x% of women at this conference*” or “There’s no female speakers at this conference.” Not just as observations (there’s nothing wrong in stating the obvious,) but saying it’s a negative point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2011</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</guid>
      <description>Conferences are my social life As I go to more conferences, I meet more lovely people and get to see friends I’d only ever talk to on Twitter otherwise. In the last two years, I’ve been to about three a year and it feels about the right amount that you rarely see the same talk twice and it’s not just the same topics going round.
Again, I met loads of great people at New Adventures, but unfortunately missed more people than I meant to catch up with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bathcamp plea for bad designs by developers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/bathcamp-plea-for-bad-designs-by-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 19:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/bathcamp-plea-for-bad-designs-by-developers/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a talk for Bathcamp 2010 in the works! Thanks to the ever-helpful Rich Quick for the idea, I’m going to do a talk on Design Tips for Developers.
However, alongside a bit of time, effort and available slot on the day, this is subject to some help from a kind developer. I’m looking for a bad design created by a developer to use as a case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2010</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</guid>
      <description>I was a bit skeptical about dConstruct at first. The idea of a conference based on ‘creativity and ideas’ made me worry it might be a bit pretentious but I was convinced by a lot of friends on Twitter that it’d be worthwhile, and they were so right.
I went with a notebook and an open mind. I didn’t want to go all reverse-snob on the pretentious (something I’m generally pretty guilty of being) and be ignorant of learning when I’d paid ££s for the pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>