<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mentoring on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/mentoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mentoring on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 14:06:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/mentoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry mentoring on Creative Bloq</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/industry-mentoring-on-creative-bloq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 14:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/industry-mentoring-on-creative-bloq/</guid>
      <description>Craig Grannell has written a fantastic article on Creative Bloq about mentoring, looking at loads of different ways the web industry can do mentoring well. Including interviews with Clare Sutcliffe, Greg Hoy, Jeffery Zeldman, Andy Budd, Josh Emerson, Andy Budd, Anna Debenham and me!
It’s well-worth a read if you want to mentor somebody, or would like to find a mentor yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring Q and A on .net magazine</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-q-and-a-on-netmag/</guid>
      <description>After finishing the mentoring project last week, I had a chat with Craig Grannell about mentoring which he published on the .net website: “Laura Kalbag: web designers should mentor newcomers.”
It’s a good summary of the mentoring project and has extracts from a couple of testimonials by Sibylle and Phil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>