<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Charity on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/charity/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/charity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Give and Tell Challenge</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/give-and-tell-challenge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke challenged me to the “Give and Tell Challenge”&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy to comply. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ceoblues.com/archive/2014/august/giveandtell&#34;&gt;Dan James,&lt;/a&gt; inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_Bucket_Challenge&#34;&gt;ALS Ice Bucket Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, came up with the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You donate to a cause, or causes, that have meaning to you and you say why. You then challenge 3 other people to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-out&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en&#34;&gt;All Out&lt;/a&gt;. All Out campaigns for a world where no person will have to sacrifice their family or freedom, safety or dignity, because of who they are or who they love. Living in a country that has a fairly open-minded approach to equality, it’s hard to believe that in 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s illegal to be LGBT in 77 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being LGBT is legal grounds for life imprisonment or execution in 10 countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one transgender person is murdered every 36 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only 17 countries recognise marriage equality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is completely unfair to suffer because of the way you were born and who you love. All Out has run a lot of campaigns focusing on the laws and treatment of people in particular countries, but also on the suffering of individuals who desperately need urgent support. They’re a small organisation who often rely on the expertise of its members, so I recommend you &lt;a href=&#34;https://allout.org/en/about&#34;&gt;join their mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-nominations&#34;&gt;My nominations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy donated to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.wwf.org.uk/adopt-a-gorilla/&#34;&gt;WWF&lt;/a&gt;, and nominated Sean Johnson, so you should go and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;read Shaun’s post&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://thewaterproject.org/&#34;&gt;The Water Project&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to nominate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joanna_p&#34;&gt;Jo Porter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nd_kane&#34;&gt;Natalie Kane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hellofisher&#34;&gt;Steve Fisher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear about an issue that they care about. But I want to change the terms slightly…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-and-or-tell&#34;&gt;Give AND/OR Tell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@boagworld/the-ice-bucket-challenge-e0663fbf6544&#34;&gt;“Give and Tell Challenge” post, Paul Boag&lt;/a&gt; explains the reasons behind giving regularly and how to calculate a reasonable donation size. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/give-and-tell-challenge&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@seanuk/give-and-tell-challenge-834534af3373&#34;&gt;Sean Johnson&lt;/a&gt; both do regular work for charities for free. But not everyone can afford to do so. The element of the Ice Bucket Challenge that I admire the most is that it encourages people to raise awareness of motor neurone disease (ALS). If we can’t afford to donate to charity right now, even though we want to do so, raising awareness is a charitable act in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Jo, Natalie and Steve: I challenge you to give and/or tell. And no time limit this time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
