<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Event on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/event/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;Dare conference in September&lt;/a&gt;. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business. I was only just becoming aware of what I was doing, and writing a talk was a good way for me to dig a little bit deeper. So I wrote a proposal and my proposal was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk has a slightly cheesy name, “My secret is honesty” but I promise you, the content is real. I’ve already tested it on a lovely group of people in Porto, Portugal, and hope to have a shortened version ready in September. It’s a very different topic for me, I usually talk about web design and development, but I think it’s the right place for an open talk about openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3849&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/07/dare-conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dare conference 2013&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to condense &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/notes-from-ampersand-conf/&#34;&gt;my notes from Ampersand conference&lt;/a&gt; into a more useful digest. More than anything this, like my live-tweeting at past conferences, is really a selfish activity to help me absorb the ideas from Ampersand better by reflecting on the themes of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course in the spirit of the web and all things good, I may as well share this digest so anyone who wasn’t there might get a taste of the event (albeit through my probably-twisted interpretation and slightly dodgy writing!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-typography&#34;&gt;Using typography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typography-is-about-context-context-is-about-content&#34;&gt;Typography is about context, context is about content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web ‘industry’ is starting to focus more on content strategy, and that the whole reason our sites are there is generally to showcase content, and this was reflected in the &lt;em&gt;importance of content&lt;/em&gt; being continually brought up throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vincent Connare was the first speaker of the conference. As the creator of Comic Sans, Vincent was the perfect person to explain the significance of fonts being created for a purpose, for a specific context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comic Sans was created for Microsoft Home software, when computers were starting to become used in the home. Its fun, casual, comic-book style was based on comics like Watchmen and Batman Returns and was successfully used in speech bubbles and children’s software. It’s the prolific abuse of Comic Sans in inappropriate signage, documents, and many other places that has made it so well-known and unpopular (&lt;em&gt;or inappropriately popular!&lt;/em&gt;) As Jason Santa Maria said when talking about choosing an appropriate typeface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No type is born evil, it’s the context that dictates if it works.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/xxv/5446317470/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-466&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/comicsans.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comic Sans on an Antiques shop sign&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Comic Sans on an Antiques shop sign (credit xxv, Flickr)
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Tan and Jonathan Hoefler both spoke about Bell Centennial, a font designed by Matthew Carter for phone books. The considerations in creating this font included environmental awareness, such as how the font is used and where it’s used. Matthew Carter made Bell Centennial easy to skim-read at 6pt and used ink traps for where the ink was likely to bleed on the texture of the phone book paper making the small text even harder to read.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/BellCentennial_sample.gif&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-465&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/BellCentennial_sample.gif&#34; alt=&#34;a sample of Bell Centennial&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		a sample of Bell Centennial
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;#### Content first&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Brown and Jason Santa Maria both spoke about how the context of the content gives them meaning when choosing a suitable font and how vital it is to compose your design with accountability. Some points they focused on for selecting a suitable typeface were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The content&lt;/strong&gt;, its message, its reason for being&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The audience&lt;/strong&gt;, who will read it? and how? for how long?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The culture&lt;/strong&gt;, the historical and cultural significance of the content, whether it will be read in other languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The context of the typeface itself&lt;/strong&gt;, its resumé, what it signifies to others, how its production affects its appearance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;content-out&#34;&gt;Content-out&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Boulton got us designers thinking around content in a new way which is less concentrated on the limitations of our canvas (the size of the browser, the device) and discussed possible solutions for designing from the content-outwards. Mark suggested that as designers became fixated on web standards, we started to take the separation of content and style too literally which meant we created meaningless designs separated from our content. The content-out route really involves knowing the content first, which prompted a brilliant quote from Mark:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know your content or audience, go to the pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitting he didn’t yet know any solid solutions, but wanted to encourage discourse, Mark suggested processes such as working on the details first then assembling a modular design from the details. This process is one that complements the &lt;strong&gt;responsive web design&lt;/strong&gt; approach which almost every speaker hailed as a new way of working on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;responsive-design&#34;&gt;Responsive design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Tan explained how typography is one of the elements we can keep consistent across responsive design that reconfigures itself to suit different scenarios. No matter what the layout, screen size or device, the typography (along with colour) can instantly identify a design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Brown explained his process for building responsive design systems around type. The web, with its inherent flexibility, resists the rigid traditional print frameworks using ratios and fixed grids that previously gave designers a structure to work within. Tim suggests creating a modular scale, with the layout and every other element following the type, allowing it to work consistently regardless of device. This is based on the principle that we need a constant to work from in our designs, and type is a perfect constant to use. This is a way of thinking that designers can easily practise and exercise without affecting any of our current processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim went on to describe how using a &lt;em&gt;modular&lt;/em&gt; scale, rather than arbitrary numbers, we can create a design system that is visibly cleaner and more harmonious. He suggested choosing sizes and spaces, such as type, borders, margins, padding, based on a pattern or scale. A couple of examples of ratios that Tim provided were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;golden ration 1 : 1.618&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;musical fifth 1 : 1.5
&lt;a href=&#34;http://modularscale.com&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-467&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/Screen-shot-2011-06-22-at-09.15.55.png&#34; alt=&#34;A modular scale created using Tim&amp;#39;s website modularscale.com&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		A golden ratio modular scale created using Tim’s website modularscale.com
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different ratios traditionally have meaning or significance to different types of people, so these contexts can even be used to choose an *appropriate *scale. This also gives designers a reason and justification to backup our design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typography-is-more-than-text&#34;&gt;Typography is more than text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Santa Maria talked about how typography has a dual life. It’s about both the &lt;strong&gt;aesthetic&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;readability&lt;/strong&gt;. As designers we can often get caught up in how the text looks as a whole, but in reality users see the whole as texture and they skim across it. Users are more likely to stop and fixate on a small area for a moment, and this is where they will notice the typography and if it makes the text difficult to read. Jason emphasised the well-known idea that &lt;strong&gt;good typography is invisible&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s about not making the user think or struggle to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason also made the point that readability isn’t always *can I read it? *but also *do I want to read it? *It’s in these scenarios that good typography can help create emotional experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typography-can-create-emotional-experiences&#34;&gt;Typography can create emotional experiences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Tan really expanded on his &lt;em&gt;New Adventures in Web Design&lt;/em&gt; talk about the lizard brain by emphasising how typography can influence the subconscious. A typeface can convey emotion beyond the words in the text. Jon Tan quoted Paul Rand saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A logo derives meaning from the quality of the thing it symbolizes [&amp;#8230;] what it represents is more important than what it looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is controlled by a part of our brain called the amygdala which can evoke emotional responses without verbal or linguistic input. Jon explained how this means as designers, we need to understand how the brain works, how we need to understand how design makes us &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vincent Connare made an interesting point when speaking about the design of Tahoma as a replacement for MS Sans. Tahoma was designed by Matthew Carter who is a real type designer and he created a technically superior font compared to MS Sans which was created by an engineer. Still, many users complained that they preferred MS Sans. As people get an emotional attachment and loyalty to that which they know, MS Sans was generally considered the ‘better’ font even though it was technically inferior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/tahoma-ms-sans.gif&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-468 &#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/tahoma-ms-sans.gif&#34; alt=&#34;MS Sans and Tahoma samples&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		MS Sans (left) and Tahoma (right) samples
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;typography-is-hard&#34;&gt;Typography is hard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who often feels that typography can be overwhelming, and that it’s very difficult to know when you’re making the right decisions, it was great to hear Jason Santa Maria say that &lt;strong&gt;typography is hard&lt;/strong&gt;. Jason went on to explain that a designer doesn’t need to know *absolutely everything *about typography to use it well, you just need to know how to estimate a font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;guidelines-for-choosing-and-using-type&#34;&gt;Guidelines for choosing and using type&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason went into great depth on how to choose typefaces. He explained that there are no rules in typography, its imperfect precision where you can only be guided by basic principles and understanding the constraints. Some of the top tips that Jason gave were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose workhorse typefaces&lt;/strong&gt;. We shouldn’t feel obliged to choose a new typeface for every project. Create a personal palette of typeface families that work well in display as well as body text. Use different styles from the same family to save having to find multiple typefaces that work well together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid overly themed typefaces&lt;/strong&gt;. These ready-mades show a lack of imagination. Subtle fonts can promote different emotions more effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a list of attributes and feelings that you want to convey, then find typefaces that convey that feeling&lt;/strong&gt;. This also works for looking for typefaces that are similar, but not the same, to a standard that you use (perhaps such as Helvetica or Georgia.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Test your fonts in context **and in the right space. Choose your font appropriately to the line height, line length and size required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-fonts&#34;&gt;Web Fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-web-fonts&#34;&gt;The Benefits of Web Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone at Ampersand was evangelising web fonts. It’s impossible to not do so with all the exciting possibilities playing with lovely new fonts can bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon Tan described it as a time of &lt;strong&gt;renaissance&lt;/strong&gt; considering we were previously forced to use such a minimal font palette, and we’re now being given a chance to prove our skills in design using these new tools. We can now choose type that’s *perfect *for purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Santa Maria echoed what I think everybody else was feeling in that it’s a good time to be a designer. Jason shot down the cynical idea that pople are misusing or abusing fonts and emphasised the benefits that we’re gaining in accessibility through no longer having to provide non-standard fonts through dodgy font replacement techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jon and Jason both spoke about how type can define a brand and how web fonts are helping unify the identity of brands across print and the web, helping convey a voice, facilitate an emotion, and create a relationship between the user and the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-downside-of-web-fonts&#34;&gt;The Downside of Web Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the eagerness to try new web fonts, there was a lot of talk of the downside of web fonts, but with a positive outlook on how the awkward issues can be solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-back-at-font-engineering&#34;&gt;Looking back at font engineering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;metal-typesetting-bitmap-font-creation-and-os-safe-fonts&#34;&gt;Metal typesetting, bitmap font creation and OS-safe fonts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Berlow harked back to working in font engineering when fonts were first needed to look consistent from computer software to printer, explaining how this relates to the web fonts emerging today. One of David’s main considerations is how poor fonts can look at very small sizes. Bearing his experience with metal case type and bitmap fonts in mind, David focuses on how to make web fonts easier to read including basing them on specific size grids, using large x-heights with generally large amounts of whitespace and simplifying fiddly and complicated details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rendering&#34;&gt;Rendering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rendering is a big issue, mentioned by most of the speakers. Jonathan Hoefler spoke about how the type designers at Hoefler and Frere-Jones are creating insane amounts of newly hinted glyphs in order to make their web fonts work as well as they possibly can across the web. Many web fonts are just bad translations of fonts created for print and consequently barely work on the web. A few speakers discussed the difficulties in the differences in fonts across Windows and OSX, with some users preferring Windows’ ‘*crispness*‘ and others preferring Apple’s ‘*soft detail*‘.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://typekit.com/fonts/museo-slab&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-469 &#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/06/museo-slab.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Museo Slab as seen in Safari on OSX and Internet Explorer on Windows&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Museo Slab as seen in Safari on OSX and Internet Explorer on Windows (samples from Typekit)
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Brown emphasised how important it is to check your web font choices live, and repeating these checks across the different environments that will use those fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Daggett described the issues created by web browsers choosing their own fallbacks, such as creating awful synthesised bold fonts through smearing or drawing the letters twice, or obliqueing fonts to give them an italic appearance. Jonathan Hoefler expressed how the lack of being able to distinguish unusual font styles can be an issue, especially for those that have a back slant or are number-only fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;css-working-draft-for-fonts&#34;&gt;CSS Working Draft for Fonts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Daggett’s talk was an intense look at the potential future of web fonts being controlled through CSS. It was at this point that I felt particularly hopeful. There’s something amazing about how quickly the web seems to have gone from a miserable collection of ‘web-safe’ fonts to being able to see how we can potentially use alternate glyphs and handle kerning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think my notes cover all the fantastic features that John described, so for those I recommend you see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-fonts/&#34;&gt;CSS Working Draft for Fonts&lt;/a&gt;, but here are some of the exciting tidbits I fancy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using opentype font features through ‘font-variant:’&lt;/strong&gt;. This means having loads of different font features such as multiple glyphs per character in an easy-to-use package giving us fine-grain control all through CSS. At the moment &lt;em&gt;font-variant&lt;/em&gt; is used predominantly to select small-caps (with limited success.) The potential in &lt;em&gt;font-variant&lt;/em&gt; means we could eventually select font features such as petite caps and automatic fractions, have more control over fallbacks, kerning, ligatures, language support and numerals, as well as supplementing other CSS properties such as &lt;em&gt;text-transform&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security for web fonts&lt;/strong&gt;. Rather than DRM, the idea is to restrict the origin of the font through http headers and the like, requiring a particular protocol, site or port. This could prevent other sites hot-linking your fonts or sniffing your font URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-day-listening-to-clever-people-talk-about-fonts&#34;&gt;A day listening to clever people talk about fonts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that me bothering to write a massive blog post about the themes of Ampersand conference really shows what an amazing day it was. I felt completely inspired, enthused and almost exhausted by the ideas and feelings being expressed by the speakers. I hope this rather disjointed digest might have helped bring some of this excitement to you lot who couldn’t be there on the day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-reading-and-plugins&#34;&gt;Recommended Reading and Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-reading&#34;&gt;Recommended Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abookapart.com/products/responsive-web-design&#34;&gt;Responsive Web Design by Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;strong&gt;everybody&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://codexmag.com/&#34;&gt;Codex magazine&lt;/a&gt; (via Jon Tan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-sites&#34;&gt;Recommended Sites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fontsmith.com/&#34;&gt;Fontsmith&lt;/a&gt; (via Jon Tan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google ‘font font focus’ for Font Font Focus sites (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typography.com/&#34;&gt;Hoefler &amp;amp; Frere-Jones at Typography.com&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulshawletterdesign.com/&#34;&gt;Paul Shaw Letter Design&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fontsinuse.com/&#34;&gt;Fonts in Use&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webfontspecimen.com/&#34;&gt;Web Font Specimen&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://modularscale.com/&#34;&gt;Modular Scale&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.typekit.com/category/font-events/&#34;&gt;Using Typekit font events for responsive and fallback design&lt;/a&gt; (via Tim Brown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-plugins&#34;&gt;Recommended Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://letteringjs.com/&#34;&gt;Lettering.js&lt;/a&gt; (via Jason Santa Maria)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fittextjs.com/&#34;&gt;Fit Text&lt;/a&gt; (via Jason Santa Maria)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-comments&#34;&gt;4 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-241&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4b3678b201d540a500c248e154e8c995?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4b3678b201d540a500c248e154e8c995?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.adamwintledesign.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Adam Wintle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-241&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-22T17:52:44+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:52pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Superb writeup! Makes me really wish I could have been there!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-243&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-243&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-23T09:49:36+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:49am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks Adam! Hopefully if there’s a next time you’ll be there :)
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-242&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/eab5dafdd6573164cf8552c4fcc7a1fe?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/eab5dafdd6573164cf8552c4fcc7a1fe?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://jontangerine.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jon Tan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-242&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-23T09:46:46+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hey Laura, so glad you enjoyed it! Fantastic, detailed write-up. Here’s a couple of more links you might find useful:

Nick Sherman’s history of [Bell Centennial](http://nicksherman.com/articles/bellCentennial.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow). [Wikipedia article on Peter Behrens](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Behrens&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow), consultant artist for AEG, and designer of arguably the world’s first corporate typeface. There’s also a [gallery of Behren’s work](https://picasaweb.google.com/ID100Y/TheVirtualPeterBehrensExhibition&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow). All about the London Underground typefaces, [Johnston and New Jonhston](http://londonreconnections.blogspot.com/2009/09/typeface-for-underground.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow). Finally, a huge collection of [Blue Note covers](http://www.gokudo.co.jp/Record/BlueNote3/nnblue2.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow) that includes many by Reid Miles.

See you next year I hope!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-244&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-244&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-06-23T09:51:03+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:51am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Cheers Jon, those links are great! Some lovely reads to start the morning&amp;#8230;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big M</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 18:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-338 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/badge-242x320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Big M badge&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;First off, let me declare my complete bias. I’ve been involved with the Big M conference from pretty early on, I was lucky enough to do all the design work and the organisers are lovely guys who I’m proud to call my friends. I’m still on a high from how much I enjoyed myself (and just about recovered from the surreal feeling of being in a place with my own design work &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;) so this is really going to be the most biased event review you’ve ever read!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-attendees&#34;&gt;The Attendees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a complete mixture of attendees, ranging from business entrepreneurs to freelancers, mobile operators to web developers and UX experts. What really stuck out was that everybody seemed friendly, enthusiastic and engaged in the day. I didn’t spot any boring/bored looking ‘suits’ and it made for a fun atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-venue&#34;&gt;The Venue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great point made in &lt;a href=&#34;http://adambird.com/the-big-m-went-bold-and-got-it-so-right&#34; title=&#34;Adam Bird&#39;s review of The Big M&#34;&gt;Adam Bird’s review&lt;/a&gt; was that Komedia in Bath made for a great conference day venue as it usually hosts comedy and music events. Such a good point. The venue being a slightly dark and very colourful room made for a relaxed and informal feel to the conference. It was the right size for about 200 people so it didn’t feel over-crowded or empty at any point. The chairs were a bit hard, but I don’t think I’ve ever been to an event where that wasn’t a problem&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-speakers&#34;&gt;The Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, and a previous attendee of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://open-mic.org.uk/&#34; title=&#34;openMIC mobile innovation events&#34;&gt;openMIC events&lt;/a&gt;, I usually expect most of the talks to go over my head. I’m not a big business brain, never really worked in the mobile industry and mobile development is a lot more complicated than the majority of web markup/frontend development that I do. However, this wasn’t the case at all at The Big M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speakers were all experienced presenters. Often you’ll find one ‘dud’ talk at a conference, but there wasn’t one here. Whilst some of the speakers presented on more controversial topics that I wouldn’t necessarily agree on, each made their points well, engaging the audience and inspiring loads of discussion in the Q and As and breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a brief rundown of some of the main points (and some of my terrible iPhone photos) I tweeted from the talks as well as some brilliant tweets from &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf&#34;&gt;@bigmconf&lt;/a&gt; where all the talks were live-tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;raam-thakrar-app-distribution-and-monetisation-the-only-things-more-important-than-lines-of-code&#34;&gt;Raam Thakrar –; App distribution and monetisation –; the only things more important than lines of code&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-341 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0537-238x320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Raam Thakrar&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thakrar: We need to think about why a consumer buys a phone, what part we play in the decision &amp;amp; how can we monetise this &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49767361464647680&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;software and apps are now a deciding factor when people are buying handsets, so app devs should use this to work with operators&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thakrar: Specific lessons: develop an app that consumers love and thus influences their choice about what they do with their money &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/497710145524326400&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;aral-balkan-beyond-usability-on-mobile&#34;&gt;Aral Balkan –; Beyond Usability on Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-342 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0540-239x320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Aral Balkan&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The differentiating factor that allows Apple to charge more for phones, tablets, mp3 players and PCs is user experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usable is akin to being edible (credited to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/Cennydd&#34;&gt;@Cennydd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/aarron&#34;&gt;@aarron&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common sense is a dangerous myth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-led-by-dan-appelquist-openness-open-standards-source-data-in-mobile&#34;&gt;Panel: led by Dan Appelquist –; Openness: Open Standards/Source/Data in Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-full wp-image-339 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0546.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Panel session&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openness is about giving developers choice so they can come to one platform and create content they can use on other platforms &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49810212210737153&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Openness: At some point you are going to die and your work is going to live on, but the only way it can do that is to be locked in &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49811351819923456&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Openness often hits the barriers of brand protection and content protection &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49814525934968832&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bruce-lawson-breaking-out-of-the-walled-garden-html5-and-open-technology-for-mobile-development&#34;&gt;Bruce Lawson –; Breaking out of the “Walled Garden”: HTML5 and open technology for mobile development&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-340 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0544-320x239.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bruce Lawson&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using new web technologies, make use of them, but don’t rely on them. Always use progressive enhancement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider using &amp;lt;a href=”tel:xxx”&amp;gt; for linking phone numbers to be click-to-call on mobile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessibility isn’t just about being legal, it’s a moral obligation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ewan-macleod-state-of-the-union-mobile-address&#34;&gt;Ewan MacLeod –; State of the Union –; Mobile Address&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-343 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0547-239x320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ewan MacLeod&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps being separate from the handsets and operators are barriers to the most &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; mobile experiences. It needs to be seamless&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thakrar: Specific lessons: develop an app that consumers love and thus influences their choice about what they do with their money &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/497710145524326400&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thakrar: Specific lessons: develop an app that consumers love and thus influences their choice about what they do with their money &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/497710145524326400&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;paul-golding-future-innovations-in-mobile&#34;&gt;Paul Golding –; Future Innovations In Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-344 alignright&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2011/03/IMG_0549-239x320.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Paul Golding&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golding: There is a myth that being first is really important. You want to be the first to win not the first to market &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49872937783799808&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golding: Study what else has succeeded, what has failed, and what you can take and project out in order to innovate &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49873438013267968&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golding: You need to conceive the product, choose the platform, develop the product, deliver the product and engage the market &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bigmconf/status/49876234582237184&#34;&gt;From @bigmconf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-wifi&#34;&gt;No Wifi!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the conference day of The Big M there was no wifi and very little 3G or Edge signal (O2 isn’t much good in Bath!) This is the second conference I’ve been to this year without wifi (the other being &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/&#34; title=&#34;My blog post on the New Adventures in Web Design conference&#34;&gt;New Adventures&lt;/a&gt;) and I think it’s a great choice that more conference organisers should make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/m1ke_ellis&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; quite rightly pointed out that even when organisers pay for expensive wifi, it usually gets overloaded, and is an additional cost that the attendees pay in their ticket price. I couldn’t agree more. Having so little signal meant people were talking to each other rather than being stuck to laptop screens. There was just about enough signal for the occasional tweet about the event but not enough for any anti-social so-and-sos to sit and work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-workshops&#34;&gt;The Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Two was a smaller affair, with about a quarter of Day One’s attendees returning for the workshops. I was really lucky to go to Aral Balkan’s &lt;em&gt;iPhone Design Principles&lt;/em&gt; and half of Patrick Lauke’s *HTML5 and Mobile *before we had to head back home to Surrey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;aral-balkan-iphone-design-principles&#34;&gt;Aral Balkan  –; iPhone Design Principles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aral really is a talented presenter. After a quick introduction of everybody in the room, he managed to pitch a perfect level workshop helping us to understand the different development choices you have when creating web apps and native apps for the iPhone. I wrote pages and pages of notes and feel like I understand the development process so much better now (and that’s considering I’m no programmer, just a designer!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;patrick-lauke-html5-and-mobile&#34;&gt;Patrick Lauke –; HTML5 and Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half of this was a great intro to HTML5 and expanded on many of the points that Bruce made in his talk the day before. As someone who is already using HTML5 on most projects, I found a lot of the talk was probably better suited to those just getting to know HTML5 but the great explanations of concepts such as the viewport really helped cement what I already knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-in-all&#34;&gt;All in All&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bookmeister&#34;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/m1ke_ellis&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; would run a fantastic event, and I hope this encourages more smaller and informal conferences. Conferences that freelancers can afford that enthuse, engage, feed, water and inspire. Here’s hoping there might be a Big M II&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/markleepower/5554271518/&#34; title=&#34;bigm2011-1066.jpg by markleepower, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5022/5554271518_15a564a873.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bigm2011-1066.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; &gt;}}
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(My favourite Big M photo, taken by the super talented &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/markleepower/&#34; title=&#34;Mark Power on Flickr&#34;&gt;Mark Power&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2010</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit skeptical about dConstruct at first. The idea of a conference based on ‘creativity and ideas’ made me worry it might be a bit pretentious but I was convinced by a lot of friends on Twitter that it’d be worthwhile, and they were so right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went with a notebook and an open mind. I didn’t want to go all reverse-snob on the pretentious (something I’m generally pretty guilty of being) and be ignorant of learning when I’d paid ££s for the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I ended up writing reams. Well, seven sides of a scruffy notebook, so here are the best bits I remember from each talk for the benefit of my friends who couldn’t be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summaries&#34;&gt;Summaries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to summarise the main ideas from the talks. If I totally missed the point or didn’t do it justice, I’m really sorry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;marty-neumeier-the-designful-company&#34;&gt;Marty Neumeier — The Designful Company&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding is about how the consumer &lt;em&gt;feels&lt;/em&gt; about your product. To differentiate your brand from others, you must be good &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;brendan-dawes-boil-simmer-reduce&#34;&gt;Brendan Dawes — Boil, Simmer, Reduce&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect as much inspiration and information as possible, consider it all and the reduce it down until there’s nothing left to take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;david-mccandless-information-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;David McCandless — Information Is Beautiful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infographics can be used to help us understand and relate to the huge amount of information and data we’re drowning in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;samantha-warren-the-power-and-beauty-of-typography&#34;&gt;Samantha Warren — The Power and Beauty of Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letters can say more than the words they spell. Picking fonts for a project is like picking shoes for an outfit, you must pick the most contextually appropriate font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;john-gruber-the-auteur-theory-of-design&#34;&gt;John Gruber — The Auteur Theory Of Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like in film production, collaborative web projects can benefit from an auteur who acts as an arbiter of taste and strives for high quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hannah-donovan-jam-session-what-improvisation-can-teach-us-about-design&#34;&gt;Hannah Donovan — Jam Session: What Improvisation Can Teach Us About Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can learn about improvisation in design from improvisation in music. Making sure tools don’t get in the way, we have a structure to follow and roles to keep, to help us free our self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;james-bridle-the-value-of-ruins&#34;&gt;James Bridle — The Value Of Ruins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to make sure information is being kept, given history, value and versions to help us understand its context, the world and protect the information from cultural destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tom-coates-everything-the-network-touches&#34;&gt;Tom Coates — Everything The Network Touches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future is in the connectivity of data, up to huge scales such a cities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;merlin-mann-kerning-orgasms-amp-those-goddamned-japanese-toothpicks&#34;&gt;Merlin Mann — Kerning, Orgasms &amp;amp; Those Goddamned Japanese Toothpicks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerd are cool because they really care about something. It’s great to be a nerd because you suck up huge quantities of information. It’s important to ensure you keep the information up-to-date and relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;various-points-and-ideas&#34;&gt;Various points and ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to capture some of the ideas from my notes in this mind map thing, in addition/support to the summaries. If you can read my writing, you might find it interesting. I just did it to help cement the ideas in my head as I’m one of those people who has to write something down a million times to get it to stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2010/09/finished-mindmap.gif&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-211&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2010/09/finished-mindmap-960x676.gif&#34; alt=&#34;dConstruct 2010 ideas mindmap&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2010/09/finished-mindmap.gif&#34; title=&#34;View the above image full size&#34;&gt;You might want to view it full-size to attempt to read the text&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-conference-thoughts&#34;&gt;Overall conference thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more people I know, the better conferences always are. It can be pretty hard to get chatting to somebody you don’t know in a room full of people who are stereotypically shy (especially when you’re in a minority of girls and so stick out like a sore thumb!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved Brighton as a destination (pretty easy travel for me) and the venue was very smart. It was a bit tricky to write notes in the darker parts of the theatre but wouldn’t be so hard on back-lit devices (I opted for paper as I’m still really slow on iPad.) It would have been great to charge my iPhone/iPad during the talks as most of my break times were spent out of the venue trying to find non-coffee/tea refreshments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I noticed in particular was that there weren’t any questions at the end of the talks. In a way this was good because it prevented the awkward silence that is often heralded with ‘Any questions?’ at other conferences. However, it did give you the feeling of one-way communication. Much more like being at a lecture than being in a lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good to see speakers I hadn’t seen before too. I think I’d already seen a variation of Brendan Dawes’ talk at Future Of Web Design, but otherwise the talks and speakers were totally new to me. This was refreshing over some of the conference veterans, because how much do you practice what you preach when you spend your whole time touring a talk?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-comments&#34;&gt;7 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-101&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;crispinheath&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-101&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T11:26:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:26am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag love the mindmap
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-100&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b044f70c056d8b959d812b28d57bfad7?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b044f70c056d8b959d812b28d57bfad7?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Tom&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-100&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T12:20:23+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:20pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        The big question&amp;#8230; will you go again next year!?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-102&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-102&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T13:41:38+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:41pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Definitely! It&amp;#039;s such good value for money.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-106&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;timhastings&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-106&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T12:31:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:31pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag your #dConstruct mind map is awesome, great job!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-105&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/49f2afdf84fdc75ddb70fe2fc1701a37?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/49f2afdf84fdc75ddb70fe2fc1701a37?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://andyhume.net&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Andy Hume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-105&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T14:43:01+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:43pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Justin and Laura,

These are exactly the goals of dConstruct –; always have been. There are workshops alongside the conference which teach more practical skills-based stuff, but the conference day itself is all about getting people to think outside of their day-to-day work: to inspire, to excite, and (perhaps most of all) to motivate.

So glad you enjoyed it –; and see you next year!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-103&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae049867321650db92f74bfb926a8551?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae049867321650db92f74bfb926a8551?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.surferm.ag&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Justin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-103&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T14:56:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:56pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I was a little bit dubious about the conference at first as well.

By lunch time I was thinking that the Web Directions conference in London was much better.  At Web Directions they were talking about technologies that we could use now and running through real life examples, something that gave the dev side of me some excitement to get home and straight to work.

At the end of dConstruct I met up with my girlfriend who was eager to hear about the day.  I started with &amp;quot;Actually the last conference I went to was much better, but&amp;#8230;.&amp;quot;

What followed from that &amp;quot;but&amp;#8230;.&amp;quot; was 90 minutes of explaining my thoughts and ideas and the concepts the speakers discussed during the conference.

I realised it *was* an awesome conference, and I think you&amp;#039;re descriptions and mind map are great examples of that.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-104&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-104&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-07T15:14:18+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:14pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Couldn&amp;#039;t agree more! When there are so many technique-driven talks out there, it can be easy to judge the more ideas-based talks as pretentious when they&amp;#039;re actually really valuable fuel for the brain!
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
