<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Event on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at Dare conference in September. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.
Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ampersand conference — My Digest</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digest-from-ampersand-conf/</guid>
      <description>I’ve tried to condense my notes from Ampersand conference into a more useful digest. More than anything this, like my live-tweeting at past conferences, is really a selfish activity to help me absorb the ideas from Ampersand better by reflecting on the themes of the day.
And of course in the spirit of the web and all things good, I may as well share this digest so anyone who wasn’t there might get a taste of the event (albeit through my probably-twisted interpretation and slightly dodgy writing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big M</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 18:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-big-m/</guid>
      <description>Big M badge   First off, let me declare my complete bias. I’ve been involved with the Big M conference from pretty early on, I was lucky enough to do all the design work and the organisers are lovely guys who I’m proud to call my friends. I’m still on a high from how much I enjoyed myself (and just about recovered from the surreal feeling of being in a place with my own design work everywhere) so this is really going to be the most biased event review you’ve ever read!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2010</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2010/</guid>
      <description>I was a bit skeptical about dConstruct at first. The idea of a conference based on ‘creativity and ideas’ made me worry it might be a bit pretentious but I was convinced by a lot of friends on Twitter that it’d be worthwhile, and they were so right.
I went with a notebook and an open mind. I didn’t want to go all reverse-snob on the pretentious (something I’m generally pretty guilty of being) and be ignorant of learning when I’d paid ££s for the pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>