<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design Theory on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/design-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/design-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web workshop at Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 I’m running my ‘Design theory for the web’ workshop at Interlink conference in Canada on the 18th of June.
 
It’s a one day workshop and I’ve written a mega description below for anyone wanting to know more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Untangle the Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Nothing quite like a last-minute post… Tonight I’m speaking at Untangle the Web at Google Campus in London. I’m doing a talk on Design Theory for the Web where I do a whistle-stop tour through designing with typography, grids and colour on the web.
I also have a stinking cold so I’m going to be taking industrial quantities of Red Bull and a quarantine zone with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography and the web at Ampersand Conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/typography-and-the-web-at-ampersand-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a big old writeup for ubelly from my notes at Ampersand conference earlier in the month.
This was an event I decided not to live-tweet, as the content is usually more involved and in-depth, making for a better big writeup and less tweetable quotes.
Typography and the web at Ampersand conference</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
