<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweden on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/sweden/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sweden on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/sweden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 21st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a busy few weeks.
Ethical Design Manifesto refresh Last week we launched a refresh of the Ethical Design Manifesto, along with a video. As it was a short-ish video, I felt like I had no excuse but to do the captioning for it too. I couldn’t get Subtitle Horse (my usual favourite web software) working with the video, so I ended up using Jubler instead.
It took a while to get my head around how to use the interface, but I found using the audio track from the video very useful, as I could sync the subtitles to the wave forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 1st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 10:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Well… we’re here! In Malmö, sitting in our new office at Media Evolution City.
It’s been a busy and exhausting week. Oskar and I made our 800 mile trip in one day, thanks to the wonderful “courier” and took another day to recover. Then it was straight into the office.
The last week has been meeting new friends, relocation admin, and arranging a few events for the year. All the while Aral has been coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 16th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>It’s nearly time! We’re moving to Sweden next Tuesday, and it’s currently at equal parts exciting and stressful.
The storage locker in Brighton is almost empty, and we’ve stashed all our sentimental stuff—the things you want to keep, but probably aren’t worth putting in a suitcase to a foreign land—at my family’s house. We’re only taking a couple of suitcases of clothes, our work equipment, and of course Oskar. If we can squeeze Aral’s fancy Anglepoise lamp and a few nice bits of artwork into the pet transportation van, then we’ll have those along too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 5th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</guid>
      <description>Note: I’ve been writing diary entries on the Ind.ie forum for a while now. I’ve decided to start sharing these on my site now too, as I’ve not been posting much else! (They have bonus dog photos.)
I’ve been meaning to write a diary entry for ages, and 8am on a Friday morning is the first opportunity I’ve had to get to it (and I’ve already been working for an hour…)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>