<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Sweden on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/sweden/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/sweden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 21st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethical-design-manifesto-refresh&#34;&gt;Ethical Design Manifesto refresh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we launched a refresh of the Ethical Design Manifesto, along with a video. As it was a short-ish video, I felt like I had no excuse but to do the captioning for it too. I couldn’t get Subtitle Horse (my usual favourite web software) working with the video, so I ended up using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jubler.org/&#34;&gt;Jubler&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a while to get my head around how to use the interface, but I found using the audio track from the video very useful, as I could sync the subtitles to the wave forms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.05.01.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4828&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4828&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.05.01-1024x601.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Jubler with highlighted wave forms for subtitle editing&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Jubler in action
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creative-mornings-malmö&#34;&gt;Creative Mornings Malmö&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday I also gave my first ever talk in Malmö/Sweden. It was at Creative Mornings Malmö which had a lovely venue at Djäkne. The topic was “Change” and I spoke about Ethical Design, and why we need it. Aral took lots of bad photos of me, and one of them is below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.12.00.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4829&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4829&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.12.00-1024x768.png&#34; alt=&#34;Me talking with a slide of the Ethical Design Manifesto (The 3 Rs of Ethical Design) in a fluffy black cardigan&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Me doing my impression of a crow
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re settling into a good routine here in Malmö. We’re working from the office all week, 8:30-5ish, and doing a better job of taking time off during the evenings and weekends. It’s still tiring though! I underestimated the sheer cognitive load of dealing with an unfamiliar language and culture. Of course, everybody speaks English and is very kind and friendly. But just going to the supermarket, finding our way around, and learning how things work, takes a little more time and a little more effort. It’s a great adventure! But makes us well worn out at the end of every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.17.54.png&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4830&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-large wp-image-4830&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/Screen-Shot-2016-03-21-at-17.17.54-1024x767.png&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar paddling in the sea in front of the Turning Torso in Malmö&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Enjoying the beach life!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-monday-21st-march-2016&#34;&gt;posted on the Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-monday-21st-march-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 1st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 10:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-1st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well… we’re here! In Malmö, sitting in our new office at Media Evolution City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy and exhausting week. Oskar and I made our 800 mile trip in one day, thanks to the wonderful “courier” and took another day to recover. Then it was straight into the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last week has been meeting new friends, relocation admin, and arranging a few events for the year. All the while Aral has been coding. (And he intends to write a moving-related update on our blog ASAP!) Things will move much faster now we’re in a city with a supportive community and a proper place to work…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/2016-03-26.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4823&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-4823&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/03/2016-03-26.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar the dog on the sandy beach in Malmö&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Loving the beach!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-1st-march-2016/1099&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-1st-march-&lt;sup&gt;2016&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;1099&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 16th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 09:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-16th-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s nearly time! We’re moving to Sweden next Tuesday, and it’s currently at equal parts exciting and stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The storage locker in Brighton is almost empty, and we’ve stashed all our sentimental stuff—the things you want to keep, but probably aren’t worth putting in a suitcase to a foreign land—at my family’s house. We’re only taking a couple of suitcases of clothes, our work equipment, and of course Oskar. If we can squeeze Aral’s fancy Anglepoise lamp and a few nice bits of artwork into the pet transportation van, then we’ll have those along too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of pet transportation, Oskar and I will be making our way to Sweden by road with pet couriers. It’s not cheap, but it means that I don’t have to drive across five countries on the weird side of the road, and me and my pup get to travel together. It’s going to be a long trip, with at least one overnight in Germany, so I might keep myself occupied by blogging the experience as we go…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the admin and accounting side, Aral and I are taking this “fresh start” opportunity to wind down our own limited companies that we used for consultancy/freelancing, and simplifying our accounting. Neither of us are doing anything that isn’t in some way related to Ind.ie, so there’s no point us spending money on maintaining all the accounts. That’s also particularly good news for me, as it should lessen my admin tasks and leave me more time to work on design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One week to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-16.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4819&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter wp-image-4819 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar the dog lying curled up on a leather sofa&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		If I look cute, I won’t be told off for being on the sofa…
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-16th-february-2016&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-tuesday-16th-february-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 5th February 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 11:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-2016-02-05/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note: I’ve been writing diary entries on the Ind.ie forum for a while now. I’ve decided to start sharing these on my site now too, as I’ve not been posting much else! (They have bonus dog photos.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to write a diary entry for ages, and 8am on a Friday morning is the first opportunity I’ve had to get to it (and I’ve already been working for an hour…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is going well. You might’ve heard that we’ve decided to move to Sweden. Our visit at the end of January saw us finding a beautiful apartment in Davidshalltorg in Malmö, and the wonderful people at Media Evolution City going out of their way to organise us an office space where Oskar can join us. It’s been an arduous six months, and we’re really excited to move to such a friendly and welcoming space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy few weeks, with us both working hard on the hush-hush project (not long to go!) Aral speaking in Amsterdam, our two-night house-hunting trip to Malmö, and my speaking on two panels this week. Now we have just over two weeks to move everything we need to Sweden, and sort everything else. Including transporting Oskar across 5 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/office-furniture-for-sale/&#34;&gt;we’re selling some of the stuff from our storage room&lt;/a&gt; on the 13th February. If you’re interested in any of it, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:laura@ind.ie&#34;&gt;give me a shout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oskar-status&#34;&gt;Oskar status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-05.jpg&amp;quot; rel=&amp;quot;attachment wp-att-4816&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter wp-image-4816 size-full&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2016/02/2016-02-05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oskar on a muddy path in 10m visibility fog&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
		Making the most of the British countryside!
		
			
		
		&lt;/p&gt; 
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-friday-5th-february-2016&#34;&gt;Ind.ie forum at https://forum.ind.ie/t/laura-s-diary-friday-5th-february-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
