<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Diversity on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/diversity/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:19:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/diversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sticky, Pocked Underbelly Of The Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/&#34;&gt;This week’s roundup&lt;/a&gt; covers Swiss Cheese Internet vs The Database Of Ruin, The Right To Be Forgotten, and Diversity. Lots of variety!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/blog/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter wp-image-4792 size-large&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-07-at-20.33.08-894x1024.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Ind.ie blog roundup The Sticky, Pocked Underbelly Of The Web&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on the Subjective podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 16:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the week, I had fun talking to Victor Johnson on &lt;a href=&#34;http://subjective.fm/episodes/9&#34;&gt;Episode 9 of the Subjective podcast, ‘Free As In Liberty.’&lt;/a&gt; I ranted &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;, and we talked about Ind.ie, diversity, my upbringing, and how I got into design and the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://subjective.fm&#34;&gt;Subjective&lt;/a&gt; is also a great podcast in its infancy, with Victor at the helm, it’s definitely one to watch (or listen!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt; was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-with-the-network&#34;&gt;Living with the network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-freedom&#34;&gt;Technology and freedom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living with the network is more about social interaction than it is about technology. When new technology is introduced, it brings more issues around social change and social acceptance than it does around the features, gadgets and gimmicks of the technology itself. As an industry, we’ve set up systems that serve the majority, but only provide benefits to the few. Georgina Voss’s talk about distribution systems covered how the postal networks allowed governments to censor media through distribution channels. These examples had alarming parallels with the internet as a distribution channel allowing for censorship through a centralised system. It was a strong warning about the importance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.battleforthenet.com/sept10th/&#34;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Cory Doctorow put it, “it’s not a fight about information, it’s a fight about people. And people want to be free.” And for people (and information) to be free, the information networks need to be free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy-and-surveillance&#34;&gt;Privacy and surveillance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to privacy and surveillance, we are currently frogs sitting in a pot of warm water. The water is slowly being boiled around us, our privacy and freedom being slowly taken from us by governments and corporations. We won’t notice we’re being boiled until it’s too late, we won’t notice that our privacy and freedom has been irreversibly damaged until it’s too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already in trouble and this is why we need to talk more, and act more, on the issues of privacy and surveillance. We need to bring these issues to the fore so we don’t become the frogs in the boiling water. As Tom Scott said in his vision of 2030, “privacy was already dead, it’s that not everyone agreed with it yet.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-and-diversity&#34;&gt;Technology and diversity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandy Brown emphasised how the effect of technology on society around us isn’t just about the individual, and our own selfish gains. At least it shouldn’t be. With the lack of diversity in the web and tech industries, we’re creating technology for the privileged. When we’re creating products to scratch our own itch, and solve our own problems, we’re largely creating products for young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cory Doctorow pointed out that business models don’t exist in a vacuum, they reflect political, economic and social needs. And following the lines of Mandy Brown’s talk, the political, economic and social needs that we’re currently serving are largely those of young white men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-was-a-brief-summary&#34;&gt;This was a brief summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My post is a little summary of some of the themes that jumped out at me over the course of Friday. Lucky for you, &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/dConstruct/tags/dconstruct2014&#34;&gt;all the talks are available in audio format on huffduffer&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re well worth a listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4537&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/dconstruct-2014.png&#34; alt=&#34;dConstruct 2014&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a diverse speaker lineup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is so good, and so incredibly valuable, that it’s deserving of more than just a passing tweet. Julie Pagano has written about ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://juliepagano.com/blog/2014/08/26/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/&#34;&gt;Building a Diverse Speaker Lineup&lt;/a&gt;.’ This should be the go-to post for conference organisers, and it should be read as soon as you’re even thinking about organising an event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie’s post doesn’t just explain &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you want a diverse lineup (also worth reading on this topic: &lt;a href=&#34;https://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-design-and-diversity/&#34;&gt;Aral’s post, On design and diversity&lt;/a&gt;), but also &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not about collecting random people from a demographic to fill some token slot, so the mean people on the internet don’t yell at you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a woman, I’m not 100% white, and I’ve spoken at (according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/profile/laurakalbag/&#34;&gt;Lanyrd&lt;/a&gt;) 30 events. Being invited to speak is still a very tricky situation. I’ve had situations where I could very easily tell that I was invited at the last minute to be a token speaker to boost the diversity of the event. But I’ve had far more situations where the organisers knew me, knew the kinds of things I like to talk about, and considered me a good fit. My experiences are largely very positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as a “minority” speaker you can feel a horrible amount of pressure to speak. There’s the feeling that if you say no, you’re allowing your groups to be under-represented. Or worse, the conference organiser can say “well I asked her, and she said no, so it’s &lt;strong&gt;her&lt;/strong&gt; fault we don’t have a diverse lineup.” It’s horrible and wrong, but it happens. And following the guidance in Julie’s post can help organisers understand how to approach speakers, and how to make their Call For Proposals more friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other problem I have as a speaker is finding the event itself generally unfriendly and alienating. I am one of those people who feels intensely uncomfortable in a dark room with lots of alcohol and loud music. I’ve avoided a lot of after parties because of casual sexist remarks that made me feel like I didn’t belong there. Julie’s section on Conference Environment can help prevent these awkward situations, and make everyone feel more welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to a few organisers complaining about being bullied for their event’s lack of diversity, Julie finishes on a brilliant note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing a conference is hard work. Nobody is denying that. Working on making your conference diverse should be part of that work. I just gave you some insight into how you can do that. If you don’t want to do the hard work, you may receive criticism or people may not want to attend your event. That’s not bullying. That is holding you accountable for failing to do your job well. Work hard and avoid falling into the trap of the homogeneous conference lineup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juliepagano.com/blog/2014/08/26/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4534&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/09/Screen-Shot-2014-09-02-at-09.16.19.png&#34; alt=&#34;Julie Pagano: Building a Diverse Speaker Lineup&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indie Tech Summit videos and my talk on Universal Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we finally published &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/summit/videos&#34;&gt;all the videos from the Indie Tech Summit&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/&#34;&gt;ind.ie site&lt;/a&gt;. It was a fantastic event, with two days of talking about how we can create sustainable and ethical alternatives to corporate surveillance. The first day was talks and panels, with everyone discussing the problems and their own free and open solutions. The second day had workshops and discussion groups where we talked about where we could go from there, and what we could do as a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching the videos was a longer process than we anticipated, but for many good reasons. We wanted all of our videos to have transcripts. We’re very committed to accessibility (see my talk below) and sometimes, people just prefer reading to watching. We also had a couple of false-starts with our video player. We didn’t want to use any of the services with corporate surveillance business models (Youtube is out) and we couldn’t afford for our videos to get a lot of views with expensive hosting (we had a $300 Wistia bill for a week of views!) We ended up using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videojs.com/&#34;&gt;VideoJS&lt;/a&gt; with some customisation made by Andy, Aral and I. It may still have bugs in some places and on some platforms, so if you spot any, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@ind.ie&#34;&gt;please let us know&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;universal-design&#34;&gt;Universal Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a five minute talk about Universal Design, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/summit/videos/laura-kalbag/&#34;&gt;the video and transcript&lt;/a&gt; are available alongside all the others. It was very difficult to condense such a huge topic into a short talk, so I tried to just cover the question of “why should we care?” Luckily, I was then on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/summit/videos/designing-independence-panel/&#34;&gt;Designing Independence panel&lt;/a&gt; with Cole Peters, Ivanka Majic and Lena Reinhard. This panel was a life highlight. Cole, Ivanka and Lena are all such incredibly smart and caring people. It was a fascinating discussion, and we managed to cover the connections between our talks in a way we didn’t have time to cover individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would really recommend watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/summit/videos/&#34;&gt;all of the videos&lt;/a&gt;, and please blog about your thoughts. It would be lovely to hear more people talking about ethical and sustainable business models in technology, and how we can make the industry a more diverse and accessible place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.ie/summit/videos/laura-kalbag/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4526&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/08/universal-design-talk.png&#34; alt=&#34;Laura Kalbag on Universal Design&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.learningpeople.co.uk/blog/blog-posts/finding-your-inspiration-an-interview-with-web-designer-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me&lt;/a&gt; about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.learningpeople.co.uk/blog/blog-posts/finding-your-inspiration-an-interview-with-web-designer-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-4093&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/10/thelearningpeople-734x1024.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of The Learning People: Finding your inspiration, an interview with web designer Laura Kalbag&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I also pledge to be better</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 07:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post was inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/10/698-i-pledge-be-better-and-i-hope-you-do-too&#34;&gt;Faruk’s great post “I Pledge To Be Better (And I Hope You Do Too)”&lt;/a&gt; where he speaks about the continuing problems with discrimination and lack of diversity in tech, and how more people should speak up about these issues. Faruk rightly says we all have the power and responsibility to make things better. I believe that when we don’t speak out about discrimination, we’re almost causing as much damage as condoning discrimination. Because it won’t just go away if we pretend it’s not there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/&#34; title=&#34;Women and conferences&#34;&gt;spoken about it before&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m all too aware of how I used to be one of those &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/about-work/e82b7ca7de03&#34; title=&#34;Fantastic post by @Shanley about women in tech for the patriarchy&#34;&gt;“Fuck You, I Got Mine”&lt;/a&gt; women. I want to make up for that. I also believe it’s important that women aren’t scared to be vocal about discrimination and diversity. In fact, it’s of the utmost importance that &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; is scared to be vocal about these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As women, we need to be better allies to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogjustine.wordpress.com/2013/10/12/because-it-needs-to-be-said/&#34;&gt;those who have suffered&lt;/a&gt;. For me, this starts with acknowledging that, whilst my own experiences have been mostly very positive, this doesn’t mean that I’m reflective of the whole industry. It’s too easy to sit in your own self-absorbed bubble. I have so much respect for the people who are standing up and speaking out for diversity, I want to show my support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-not-all-bad-but-it-s-more-than-bad-enough&#34;&gt;It’s not all bad, but it’s more than bad enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get defensive when you’re reading posts like this, it’s easy to get annoyed at people “focusing on the bad”. I want to be clear that I love 99.99% of the people that I’ve met in the industry, and that a huge majority of people are good and mean well. But we’re not going to make anything better by refusing to see the dark side. We need to confront our problems so we know how to find the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pledge&#34;&gt;The pledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/10/698-i-pledge-be-better-and-i-hope-you-do-too#pledge&#34;&gt;Faruk’s pledge&lt;/a&gt; (which you also can &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/KuraFire/7002725&#34;&gt;find and fork on Github&lt;/a&gt;) is a clear set of intentions to help make the industry a better place. I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/laurakalbag/7013814&#34;&gt;forked my own version&lt;/a&gt;, and tweaked it so that it represents my own intentions. This has mostly been removing the part about declining speaking opportunities if it’s an exclusively white/male lineup. As I’m a woman, this puts me in a slightly different position. Still, I want commit to voicing my concerns to organisers if I feel a lineup I’m included in lacks further diversity (within reason). This is a bit wooly, and is all about intentions and contexts, so isn’t so easy to put into a pledge!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-pledge-to-be-better&#34;&gt;I Pledge To Be Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want our industry to be a safe, welcoming and inclusive place for everyone, regardless of their gender, abilities, skin colour, sexuality, age, class, neuro-diversity or any other attribute. I acknowledge that this is not currently the case, and will do my best, to the extent that I can afford to dedicate to this, to help make ours a better community and industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value the diversity of perspectives that people with different backgrounds bring to the table. I will call out exclusionary practices, behaviours or cultures and see how, together, we can perhaps reshape them to be inclusive and supportive instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will take some time to read up on, and educate myself about issues such as sexism in our industry. I acknowledge the onus is on me to be decently informed before speaking out, calling out, or participating in these discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will examine my own privileges, uncomfortable though it may be, and do my best to recognise them going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will call out people for behaviours that I deem offensive or unacceptable, but I will do so respectfully and with civility. I will strive to educate, not antagonise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge that I will make mistakes, and that I may offend someone unintentionally with my words or actions. Rather than get defensive when called out on it, I will try my hardest to listen respectfully, and learn more instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not attend events that do not have clear &lt;a href=&#34;[http://adainitiative.org/what-we-do/conference-policies/](http://adainitiative.org/what-we-do/conference-policies/&#34; title=&#34;The Ada Initiative Conference anti-harassment policy&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct policies&lt;/a&gt;, like an anti-harassment or diversity statement. I will also decline to attend events that feature, or permit to attend, any known offender of sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pledge to be better, and set a positive example for others in our community, industry, and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-appeal&#34;&gt;The appeal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please blog about diversity. It doesn’t matter if you want to pledge for yourself or not, we just need to make it clear that we don’t accept discrimination in our industry. If you don’t have a blog, why not post a quick tweet? If you’re feeling unsure, &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2013/09/696-primer-sexism-tech&#34;&gt;read these two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/notes/on-false-dichotomies-and-diversity/&#34;&gt;primers first&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at LXJS in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m really looking forward to October, where I get to return to Portugal to speak at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.lxjs.org/&#34;&gt;LXJS in Lisbon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I jumped at the chance to speak at LXJS was their fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.lxjs.org/code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. After &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jenseninman.com/blog/13737040/speakingupitstime&#34;&gt;hearing some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sazzy.co.uk/2013/02/speaking-up/&#34;&gt;horror stories&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sazzy.co.uk/2013/02/speaking-up/&#34;&gt;from other women speakers&lt;/a&gt;, I wish more conferences had this sort of approach. It’s friendly, not strict, and lets everybody know where they stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets are incredibly reasonable for a two-day event, and it looks like Lisbon is well-worth a holiday so a conference there is a bonus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.lxjs.org/&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3477&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/06/lxjs.png&#34; alt=&#34;JAVASCRIPT MEETS LISBON - A 2-day not-for-profit by-the-community and for-the-community international conference about the New Worlds of JavaScript. Event Details: Lisbon, Portugal October 2-3, 2013&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/markdown&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#define 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next Saturday I’m speaking at #define 2013, a “diversity in computing festival” for 11-13 year old students who wouldn’t usually consider careers in computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an event aimed at improving diversity in computing and I’m really proud to be speaking. I’m going to talk about a day in the life of a web designer/developer in the hope that I can share the variety involved in this kind of work and how rewarding and fun this job can be. I’m also hoping to promote a more independent way of working, showing that you don’t have to go and work for somebody else when you leave school, and that working for yourself isn’t necessarily the financial hardship that it’s often painted as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/06/define-2013.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3361&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/06/define-2013.png&#34; alt=&#34;#define Diversity in Computing festival - Rugby School, Warwickshire 15th June 2013 - Incorporating a workshop day for students aged 11-13 as well as a simultaneous programme of talks, panel discussion and networking for adults&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
