<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diversity on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/diversity/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:19:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/diversity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sticky, Pocked Underbelly Of The Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sticky-pocked-underbelly-of-the-web/</guid>
      <description>This week’s roundup covers Swiss Cheese Internet vs The Database Of Ruin, The Right To Be Forgotten, and Diversity. Lots of variety!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview on the Subjective podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 16:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/subjective-podcast/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of the week, I had fun talking to Victor Johnson on Episode 9 of the Subjective podcast, ‘Free As In Liberty.’ I ranted a lot, and we talked about Ind.ie, diversity, my upbringing, and how I got into design and the web.
Subjective is also a great podcast in its infancy, with Victor at the helm, it’s definitely one to watch (or listen!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dConstruct 2014</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dconstruct-2014/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Keith is a master curator of brilliant talks from wonderful speakers, and Friday’s dConstruct was a great event. Gone are the days where I write long connected writeups on conference themes. I wish I had the time, and venues like the Brighton Dome are far too dark to take notes. However, I really wanted to record and share some of the thoughts I got out of dConstruct, as I think the themes are very important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a diverse speaker lineup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</guid>
      <description>This post is so good, and so incredibly valuable, that it’s deserving of more than just a passing tweet. Julie Pagano has written about ‘Building a Diverse Speaker Lineup.’ This should be the go-to post for conference organisers, and it should be read as soon as you’re even thinking about organising an event.
Julie’s post doesn’t just explain why you want a diverse lineup (also worth reading on this topic: Aral’s post, On design and diversity), but also how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indie Tech Summit videos and my talk on Universal Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-tech-summit-videos/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we finally published all the videos from the Indie Tech Summit on the ind.ie site. It was a fantastic event, with two days of talking about how we can create sustainable and ethical alternatives to corporate surveillance. The first day was talks and panels, with everyone discussing the problems and their own free and open solutions. The second day had workshops and discussion groups where we talked about where we could go from there, and what we could do as a community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I also pledge to be better</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 07:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-also-pledge-to-be-better/</guid>
      <description>This post was inspired by Faruk’s great post “I Pledge To Be Better (And I Hope You Do Too)” where he speaks about the continuing problems with discrimination and lack of diversity in tech, and how more people should speak up about these issues. Faruk rightly says we all have the power and responsibility to make things better. I believe that when we don’t speak out about discrimination, we’re almost causing as much damage as condoning discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at LXJS in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>I’m really looking forward to October, where I get to return to Portugal to speak at LXJS in Lisbon.
One of the reasons I jumped at the chance to speak at LXJS was their fantastic Code of Conduct. After hearing some horror stories from other women speakers, I wish more conferences had this sort of approach. It’s friendly, not strict, and lets everybody know where they stand.
The tickets are incredibly reasonable for a two-day event, and it looks like Lisbon is well-worth a holiday so a conference there is a bonus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#define 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</guid>
      <description>Next Saturday I’m speaking at #define 2013, a “diversity in computing festival” for 11-13 year old students who wouldn’t usually consider careers in computing.
It’s an event aimed at improving diversity in computing and I’m really proud to be speaking. I’m going to talk about a day in the life of a web designer/developer in the hope that I can share the variety involved in this kind of work and how rewarding and fun this job can be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
