<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts from Clients on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/clients/</link>
    <description>Recent posts from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/clients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/delivery-logistics&#34;&gt;my latest column on A List Apart&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/delivery-logistics&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4258&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/02/Delivery-Logistics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Delivery Logistics on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Heart Internet</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Heart Internet posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heartinternet.co.uk/blog/article/interview-with-web-accessibility-champion-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;an interview with me&lt;/a&gt; on their site. They start off saying some very kind things about me, and then it covers accessibility, design, speaking at conferences and a bit of client work. As a bonus, it’s interspersed with photos of me pulling weird faces at conferences (and being business on the phone!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heartinternet.co.uk/blog/article/interview-with-web-accessibility-champion-laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4203&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2014/01/heart-interview.png&#34; alt=&#34;Interview with Laura Kalbag on Heart Internet&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including “ask me anything” in my contract</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At Dare conference in September, I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.dareconf.com/videos/hoffman&#34;&gt;a great talk by Kevin Hoffman on “How To Rebuild Amidst Crisis.”&lt;/a&gt; I loved this talk, there was so much in it, but one thing struck me as something I could carry over into my work: Kevin said he included “ask any question and I’ll answer it” in his contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like stating the obvious at first, but really there’s nothing obvious to a client who is new to you, and your process. And this is even more true for a client who is new to having a website built, or working with web professionals for the first time. There’s no book on how to be a client, and many of us (regardless of whether we’re on the client or consultant side) can often be fearful of asking the wrong questions in case it shows us up as ignorant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want my clients to feel comfortable, and that they know what’s going on. I’m sure that sometimes I don’t explain things as well as I could do, or fail to explain some things at all, so having something in my contract that lets a client know that they’re encouraged to ask questions can help make up for my shortcomings. I also believe it’s good for a designer to be challenged. &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/&#34; title=&#34;Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification&#34;&gt;I’ve said before that communication and justification are a large part of our work as designers&lt;/a&gt;, and encouraging clients to ask me “why” will only make me better at understanding my own design decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the new section I’ve now included in my contract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ask-me-anything&#34;&gt;Ask me anything&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want you to feel that you understand what’s happening, and why, throughout the duration of the project. Please feel free to ask me any question that comes to mind. I’ll always be happy to answer your questions, explain what I’m doing or how I work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might make a difference, it might not. Contracts are a great way to set the tone of your working relationship with your client, so I hope that this will do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-3196&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5e6d8ee2e4f6b434b9f1ab262cca33a3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5e6d8ee2e4f6b434b9f1ab262cca33a3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Kris Marissens&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-3196&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-11-04T10:31:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:31am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Loved this article. Learned a few things too. For instance the way English is written by a “native” writer/speaker. Native speaker/writer sounds so stupid, don’t you think? :) Anyway, I hope you don’t mind me sending this, sometimes I guess I’m like that Warren Zevon song. Thanks, Laura!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-3213&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9942aaf87a25db4f85091cb366ca8811?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/9942aaf87a25db4f85091cb366ca8811?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://@artisanshannon&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Shannon Lerner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-3213&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-11-04T15:26:14+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:26pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Lovely.

Your &lt;i&gt;Ask Me Anything&lt;/i&gt; paragraph has such a friendly tone, much like everything else you publish. Your clients are sure to understand exactly what to expect from you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week the &lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/good-designers-good-clients&#34;&gt;first post was published on my A List Apart column&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alistapart.com/column/good-designers-good-clients&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-4064&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/09/good-designers-good-clients.png&#34; alt=&#34;Good Designers, Good Clients, my post on A List Apart&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday I was a guest for today’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.happymondaypodcast.com/episodes/laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;Happy Monday podcast&lt;/a&gt;. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.happymondaypodcast.com/episodes/laura-kalbag&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4033&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/08/happy-monday.png&#34; alt=&#34;HAPPY MONDAY. A new, short-burst, industry podcast available every Monday from 7am GMT.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devices&#34;&gt;“Devices”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry. There’s no way of telling which device is being used without testing for user agents, and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://farukat.es/journal/2011/02/499-lest-we-forget-or-how-i-learned-whats-so-bad-about-browser-sniffing&#34;&gt;it’s likely that the user agent string is lying to us anyway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-sizes&#34;&gt;“Screen sizes”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, many of us started talking about device-agnostic “screen sizes”. Being device-agnostic meant we’d hopefully stop trying to make assumptions about user behaviour based on the particular type of device they were using. Mobile phone users could be “mobile” but it wouldn’t make a difference to use because we were basing our designs on screen sizes and using the knowledge that some people could possibly be “mobile” to improve usability and performance for all our users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then we still keep hanging on to those devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that smart phones tend to start at around 320px, tablets possibly around 760px and then we often count anything upward of 900px as if it’s a desktop computer. If we talk about screen sizes like this, they still correspond to the screens on particular types of devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;browser-windows&#34;&gt;“Browser windows”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I talk about “browser windows”. Yeah, these are often non-resizable fullscreen apps on the screens of various portable devices, but on desktop operating systems, a browser window could be &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I check out my own site’s analytics, there are visitors from 24 different browser window widths upward of 800px. And my responsive media queries are responding to those browser window sizes. Not the device, not the size of the screen, but the width of the browser window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s only counting browser sizes at 800px and above. Who’s to say that a user doesn’t resize their browser window so that it’s narrower than 800px? They might be using two windows side-by-side. This would mean that they’re viewing a narrow version of a site, responding to media queries we may have designed with mobile phones in mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trying-to-be-clear&#34;&gt;Trying to be clear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we’re explaining what we’re doing as designers working on responsive sites, speaking in terms of “browser windows” helps clients (bosses, stakeholders, coworkers, whatever…) understand what we’re really doing. It helps them understand what we can and can’t detect, what we do and do not have control over and help us collectively truly embrace a responsive device-agnostic approach. We need to take care with the language we use, and choose accuracy, even if it means we sometimes have to educate others, over the dumbing-down which inevitably results in expectations we can’t, and don’t want to, meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-567&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/980339c2fa3195876f7389fa0db3ed3e?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/980339c2fa3195876f7389fa0db3ed3e?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://kruegerdesigns.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Adam Krueger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-567&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-08-08T19:23:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:23pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

Great post, referring to the browser when talking about RWD makes a lot of sense. I’ve heard “mobile-first” miss used a lot at my office. This post should help clear up some confusion.
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts on the mentoring project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the idea&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the right project&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the right project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/&#34; title=&#34;Mentoring a project: the project&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/&#34; title=&#34;Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it. They really wanted to get to the bottom of the ideal processes when creating sites and working with clients and it made me want to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tricky-areas&#34;&gt;Tricky areas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three problem areas, all of which could have been overcome with more planning and attention on my part. However I think all of these tricky areas are very much reflective of the problems we come across in everyday project management. Maybe I just need to up my project management skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;working-in-a-team-with-strangers&#34;&gt;Working in a team with strangers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that splitting the project tasks across multiple people would lighten the load, but in reality it also required strangers who had never worked together to get to know each other, the best times to work together, and how to collaborate effectively. That’s a huge first step in the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As happens with many client projects, each time they had a face-to-face interaction, or a voice chat, productivity increased. In a remote working environment it can be hard to value the importance of hearing another person’s voice when trying to communicate effectively; seeing facial expressions to understand intent and less formal chatter to just get to know each other better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sharing-roles-and-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Sharing roles and responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I divided the three main tasks for the website project into branding/visual design, front end development, and back end development/WordPress. Despite emphasising that I expected the workload to be spread, with each mentee working as a hybrid, the whole new-to-working-together thing had made this difficult. These roles are not as clear-cut or as simple as they may appear. This led to an unfair, unbalanced workload that was tricky to correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hybridisation&#34;&gt;Hybridisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be a successful freelancer, I strongly believe a designer/developer must be a hybrid with a range of skills and a wide knowledge that they not only need to call on for different projects, but can also use to better inform their work with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in giving each mentee a clear non-hybrid role, I was actively discouraging this with the division of roles. I could ask them to “collaborate” until I was blue in the face, but I hadn’t made it easy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is what we inevitably struggle with on all projects. This was no different. It’s hard to estimate how long a web project will take, and when nobody in the project is working full-time, it makes it even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wish I had more time and given more attention to the project. I started out with the best of intentions, I waited until I had some time to dedicate to mentoring. But, as ever, my client work expanded to fill all available space, making it harder to keep a closer eye on process and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made sure I read every email and Basecamp message; checking in when I thought it necessary and answering every question as quickly as possible. But I could have done a lot better. I could have pre-empted more issues before they arose and given tighter guidelines on working process to make the ride smoother for the mentees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;successes&#34;&gt;Successes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-gislingham-village-website&#34;&gt;The Gislingham village website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I genuinely believe that the resulting website, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gislingham.com/&#34;&gt;gislingham.com&lt;/a&gt;, that Sibylle, Yago and Phil have worked on is a triumph. Its branding, design, structure and underlying code is more than fit for professional web design and development. In fact, in many areas I think it’s exemplary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-type-of-project&#34;&gt;The type of project&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to our fantastic client, Mallen Baker, the village community website was a great fit for a mentoring project. Even though the quality of the resulting site was incredibly important, the idea of a not-for-profit community site feels less high-pressure compared to a money-making corporate site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had challenges in the best way to display the unique content it already contained, and was going to contain in the future. It also had emphasis on ease of use for less tech-savvy users. This meant continually checking and ensuring ease of use for all potential users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mixed-disciplines&#34;&gt;Mixed disciplines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I split, and may have unevenly weighted, the roles within the project, the whole team had a good idea of what was required, assisted each other in key decisions and could take over from each other when required to do so. This was a testament to the varied skills of the mentees and their flexibility, as well as being a successful element of my hybrid ideology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;great-teamwork&#34;&gt;Great teamwork&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were times where enviable teamwork took place. Smooth communication, smart analysis and decision-making, and effective collaboration. This made me particularly proud (though it was nothing to do with me!) As someone who often works in teams, but rarely as closely, the fact the team managed to establish these close bonds in such a short time was impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;guidelines-for-better-mentoring&#34;&gt;Guidelines for better mentoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first go at mentoring a web project and I knew it was unlikely to be perfect. I was unprepared for how much it would challenge me, my working processes, and my abilities (or lack thereof) as a leader.&amp;nbsp;I wasn’t great, and I really appreciate the risk Sibylle, Yago and Phil took in joining me on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are guidelines to help me do better next time, I hope they might be helpful to anyone else looking to mentor other people who are new to the industry or client work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Guidelines for a better business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of things I learnt from the project (and the mentees) that I think could improve my business in the long term. Both of these involve an evolution of my current contract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t just stop at copyright: specify the exact licenses (Creative Commons, MIT, GNU etc) and whether these are retained by you or the client. I already do the latter but have previously failed to research the former. Doing this should result in a clearer contract with more detailed and universally-understood terms without having to add much more text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a contract with a payment schedule of 50% up front and 50% on launch, specify exactly what will prompt the final invoice. I haven’t had this structure in my contracts for a while but when I did my contract was vague at best, leaving me to bill when I felt it was the “right time.” This can lead to confusion and uncertainty on both sides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### One-to-one mentoring probably works better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a team, and the equal division of labour sounds like it might make for a smooth project, there are many issues brought about by many people learning to work together for the first time. If anything, I’d now recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;http://ryanhavoctaylor.com/business/traditional-apprenticeships-fall-down-for-the-web/&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Traditional Apprenticeships fall down for the web…by Ryan Taylor&#34;&gt;an apprenticeship model&lt;/a&gt;. Make yourself, the mentor, the other team member, so you can lead by example. Allow the mentee to take responsibility by doing, but also let them learn by seeing more closely how it’s done by a professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Face-to-face is probably better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really is too easy to forget the value of face-to-face interaction when working with other people remotely. I believe that for a truly useful mentoring experience on both sides, frequent face-to-face, or at least voice-to-voice meetings are invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Ensure the roles are clear from the beginning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shouldn’t be as easy as assigning “you can do the visual design” to a mentee, sitting back and expecting them to know the rest. The whole point of the project is to provide guidance and so you should be pro-active in suggesting the responsibilities and tasks associated with that role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Set out standards for client communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, you cannot expect the mentees to know the best way to communicate with clients when they are there to learn from you. Tell them what you’ve found to be most effective and set guidelines and milestones for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Allow more time than you think is necessary, and multiply that by 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re used to working fulltime on projects and your estimates for project duration will probably be based on your experience of similar projects. Remember that your mentee is learning on the job, so multiply by two again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been so lucky to work with such passionate and hard-working people. I can’t recommend mentoring enough to others more experienced in client work. Much like people say of teaching or speaking, it really does compound the knowledge you already have, and makes you realise more about yourself than you’d think possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-561&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf246b467b75482dc989bb255a48fe4a?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/bf246b467b75482dc989bb255a48fe4a?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.daisywheelinteractive.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Mallen Baker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-561&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-06-26T11:46:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Well done to you –; and to Phil, Jago and Sibylle, for the great job they did on the site. It was a pleasure working with you all, and I could not be more pleased with the end result.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Last Friday I was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/19&#34;&gt;guest co-host on Unfinished Business&lt;/a&gt; again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/19&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2345&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/02/unfinished-bz.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andy &amp;amp;amp; Anna have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oh-and-one-more-thing-slide-stage&#34;&gt;Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the sponsors this week was &lt;a href=&#34;http://thelink.is/unfinishedbusiness&#34;&gt;Slide + Stage&lt;/a&gt;, a full-day intensive masterclass with &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com&#34;&gt;Aral Balkan&lt;/a&gt;. It’s going to be brilliant and I’m going to be there. I’ve already &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/&#34; title=&#34;Learning to speak&#34;&gt;written a post about how much I’ve learnt from Aral&lt;/a&gt;, and if you want to speak at events, or even just become better at presenting your work to clients, I really recommend you come along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;[
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-3297&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/05/slideandstage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Slide &amp;#43; Stage&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
](http://thelink.is/unfinishedbusiness)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts on the mentoring project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the idea&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the right project&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the right project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/&#34; title=&#34;Mentoring a project: the project&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted. I use an evolved version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/projects/contract-killer/&#34;&gt;Andy Clarke’s Contract Killer&lt;/a&gt; for my client projects. Over the last four years I’ve amended it, and added in extra chunks, to prevent myself from repeating the same mistakes on multiple projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reused this contract again for this project, adding in some extra text about my responsibility as a mentor to the client and mentees. We then decided, prompted by the client’s desire to potentially share the code with other community projects, and Yago’s knowledge of &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons licenses&lt;/a&gt;, to license the code under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;licensing-code&#34;&gt;Licensing code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting and important part of the contract, and merits discussion. Previously I had always used the Contract Killer’s lines about licensing where the client has all the rights to the graphics/design elements, whereas the developer has the rights to the code and licenses it to the client for one use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This always seemed to make sense to me before, it restricts the client from rehashing your code for a different project, or even reselling it to others. But code is not a static one-off document. A website, and subsequently its code, is a living document which is usually frequently updated, fixed and improved upon. How does this then work with a one-use license? Are we then telling clients that if they need any code to be changed, they must re-hire us for the job? This wouldn’t work for most client-developer relationships. As an industry, we seem to have mostly moved to a model where we give clients the tools and knowledge to keep their own sites updated. Maintenance contracts are a thing of the past for all but the most complex systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yago found the perfect license for our particular case, where we wanted to allow the client to share the work on a not-for-profit basis, but I do urge you to &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/choose/&#34; title=&#34;choose a Creative Commons license&#34;&gt;look into the correct license which &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; makes it clear what the client is and isn’t allowed to do&lt;/a&gt;. And the wonderful thing about Creative Commons is that they write the licenses in plain English. This means the licenses work with the Contract Killer, and also makes it easy to find the best license for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-all-takes-time&#34;&gt;It all takes time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorting out the contract took a lot more time than I’d have liked. When so many parties need to sign a contract, it can take a lot of to-ing and fro-ing before it’s agreed upon. Add in email-based communication and people working on the project part-time, and it took us a good couple of weeks to get it all ironed out. Far too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://rightsignature.com/&#34;&gt;Right Signature&lt;/a&gt; to get documents signed online, and I was jumping into it too quickly. It’s fairly quick to email a PDF (or even better, pasted text) of the contract for all the signers glance over before they need to sign. As fantastic as &lt;a href=&#34;https://rightsignature.com/features&#34; title=&#34;features of Right Signature&#34;&gt;Right Signature’s sequential signers option&lt;/a&gt; is, it’s a complete pain if you get to the last person to sign the contract and they need to make an amendment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-contract&#34;&gt;After the contract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the contract was signed, having roles within the project actually become useful. Whilst I expected Yago, Sibylle and Phil to work as hybrids, collaborating on design and development, their responsibilities to lead on front-end development, content and WordPress and design (respectively) meant each could be responsible for planning more in-depth requirements for that area. These requirements took a while to nail down but provided a structure to work from, and gave each mentee a better idea of what the others were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-541&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2b4421b2aa8931592c57b61ca3b39d45?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/2b4421b2aa8931592c57b61ca3b39d45?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://next-nexus.info/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Michael.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-541&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-05-08T11:46:32+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:46am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        When it comes to licenses for code, I see nothing wrong with the old standards: the GNU General Public License, and the GNU Lesser GPL. Particularly when working with WordPress, where plugin and theme code is meant to be GPL compatible, using the GPL just makes sense. Yes, it does mean that the client could turn around and re-use, re-sell or whatever, the code. But considering that your name should be clearly identified anyway (in the license block at the top of each file), it will be obvious who to turn to to fix any issues. 

Moreover, by using a license that permits re-use, modification, etc., you are clearly saying, “I am not locking you in to my services, if you’re not happy, you can go else where with no problem; I’ll try and keep you happy”. And I think that’s valuable in and of itself.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I was guest co-host on &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/&#34; title=&#34;Why I love Unfinished Business&#34;&gt;one of my most favourite podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/12&#34;&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/a&gt;. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/12&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2345&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/02/unfinished-bz.png&#34; alt=&#34;Andy &amp;amp;amp; Anna have Unfinished Business - A weekly discussion show about the business end, the sharp end of web, design and creative industries.&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts on the mentoring project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the idea&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 13px;&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the idea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: the right project&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: the right project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/&#34; title=&#34; target=&amp;quot;_blank &amp;quot;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&#34;&gt;Mentoring a project: finding the right people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous posts, I mentioned that I was going to explain the details of the project later on. This was because I didn’t want to get bogged down by the details of the brief while I was focusing on finding the right team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’ve got our team together, I can elaborate on our client and the brief. I was very lucky to be contacted by the lovely &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mallenbaker.net/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&#34;&gt;Mallen Baker&lt;/a&gt;, who had a great project in mind and was willing to give me, and the mentees I chose, a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gislingham-village-website&#34;&gt;Gislingham village website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gislingham is a rural village in Suffolk which has a thriving community with a number of local organisations and businesses. The village website is to be revamped to be able to provide an excellent online support to that community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gislingham.com&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&#34;&gt;http://gislingham.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website is an old site, using now outdated development techniques (tables!) created by Mallen around ten years ago. Whilst the site has been maintained and updated, it’s in need of a redesign to help it better serve the local community. We are at two distinct advantages here. The existing website means that we can learn from what does and doesn’t work on the existing site. Also, having a client who works in the web industry gives us the advantage that we won’t have to teach the client about the web as we work on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-first-client-meeting&#34;&gt;Our first client meeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mallen was keen to meet Phil, Yago and Sibylle, and it was a good opportunity to kick the project off. We met last Friday in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In preparation for our first meeting, the mentees dissected the brief and assembled a list of questions for the client. They each made their own lists and then collated these together in a master list which covered a huge range of detail and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yago, Sibylle and Phil explored tools and file formats that everybody could use together without causing compatibility issues, wrote a very thorough content inventory and started looking at personas based on the brief and existing users, and researched project management systems at length to find one that was best suited to us, settling on Basecamp. This meant that we had somewhere to keep our discussions as all the email was becoming unruly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-meeting&#34;&gt;The meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to stay out the way in the meeting. All of the preparation and research that the mentees had done assured me that they were very capable running the meeting. I tried to only jump in when I thought something might be overlooked (rarely) and to assure them the role I would take for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mallen started by explaining more background on the project and what he was looking for in the new site. This informal start already answered a lot of the questions that the mentees had prepared and helped us get to know Mallen better. Then the mentees ran through the list of questions they had, asking any other questions they came up with as they thought of them. This was exactly what I was hoping would happen. Everybody was comfortable enough to ask questions at any point but we didn’t all end up speaking over each other either!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;money&#34;&gt;Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, I went over how I thought the project should be run, and we talked about money. I’ve been getting better at discussing money with clients, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&#34;&gt;listening to Andy and Anna on Unfinished Business&lt;/a&gt; has given me more confidence and reassurance that this is the best way to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want the project to be run as much as possible like I would run a client project myself. This means taking payment in stages, not just in one lump sum. Over the last six months I’ve successfully moved my clients to a structure where I bill 50% of the estimated project as a deposit/retainer, then bill every first and third Thursday of the month (pretty much every two weeks) to ensure a sensible cash flow and that nobody has to wait for, or pay, enormous invoices at the end of a long project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mimicking this process, we decided that, as we’re looking at a nominal payment of £500, breaking it into less than two stages would become a little too much of an admin nightmare. I will have to take the payment, and then pass it on to each mentee. If this got down to sending £10 payments around, it would be more hassle than it was worth. So we decided on a 50% up front and 50% on completion (the details of which will be ironed out in the contract).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-steps&#34;&gt;The next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we kick off the project, the mentees are going to assemble a proposal/estimate where they break down what needs doing and how long each task should take. This will help us plan how best to run the project and work out if our deadline is realistic. My next step is sorting out a contract for all of us to sign to make sure we understand our roles and responsibilities over the next couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-comment&#34;&gt;One comment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-496&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d8ea827f7b8b0d3a267f52a91eb31361?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d8ea827f7b8b0d3a267f52a91eb31361?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://redheaded-geek.blogspot.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;John Wickee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-496&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-03-27T19:22:40+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:22pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I really love this project you’re doing. It’s a great idea and can provide some great experience for those you selected. It’s great of you to share and help them. Mentoring can be invaluable. 

I’m really interested to follow along and see how it plays out.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Feast Designer’s Quest(ionnaire)</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 08:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Design Feast have my answers to their Designer’s Quest(ionnaire) on their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll past the scarily large photo of me quickly… their questions prompted me to think about some interesting points, especially challenges for designers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the challenges you encounter as a designer and how do you deal with them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the greatest challenge a designer comes across is their own ego. It’s in our nature, as those that deal in creativity, we have egos that allow us to consider our work good enough to share, and good enough for clients to pay us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, too much ego and we’d never iterate past our first draft of any design work, we’d never pay attention to client requirements, and we’d never allow anyone to tell us if we’re wrong. In my experience, my best work has been done when I’ve set my ego aside and worked collaboratively with clients and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/02/design-feast.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2261&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2013/02/design-feast.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot of the Design Feast website&#34;/&gt;
	
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: finding the right people</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 10:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a project! I’ll elaborate on the details of the project in a future post, but the importance of having a project was that it’s allowed me to choose the designers/developers who could get something out of being &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mentee&#34;&gt;mentees&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t want to do this before securing the right project as I needed to know what I was looking for in a mentee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-right-mentee-for-the-job&#34;&gt;Finding the right mentee for the job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been one of the hardest decisions I’ve ever had to make. After my idea &lt;a href=&#34;http://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/blog/about/thoughts-on-mentoring&#34;&gt;gained significant&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://unfinished.bz/4&#34;&gt;(kind) exposure&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve also felt the pressure to make sure I get it right. What’s made it even harder is that every designer/developer that sent me an email about the project was sweet, enthusiastic and incredibly willing. I had thirty-two candidates and no idea how best to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shortlisting&#34;&gt;Shortlisting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-on&#34;&gt;Early on&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;payment&#34;&gt;Payment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut down into short list whilst I was looking into the original project idea. I knew that it wouldn’t be a high-paying project; I wanted the majority of the value to be in the learning experience, and I made that clear in my first email to everyone who had contacted me. This meant a couple of candidates who were already serious freelancers, looking for a well-paid project, withdrew themselves. It’s always good to talk money up front! A few people didn’t reply at all, and that was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-stage&#34;&gt;First stage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;team-work&#34;&gt;Team work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I needed to work out the best way to eventually reduce my list of now thirteen to just a few. I was wary that nobody could take on a low-paying project, dedicate a huge amount of time to it and deliver great results; I asked which candidates were willing to work in small teams. As I knew all the candidates already had other work or studies, I thought it unrealistic to expect one person to do all the work. It would also require a hybrid designer-developer who was capable in front-end and back-end development. Now these people are rare in the industry, and would be almost impossible to find in anyone just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made my short list even shorter. There were a few people who would prefer to work solo and so this project wouldn’t be the right match for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;specialism&#34;&gt;Specialism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this first stage I also asked whether the candidates preferred to work in design, front-end development, back-end development, or a combination of two or three skill areas. I was concerned I might end up with a surplus of one skill area, but actually it was a fairly even spread of all three, with most expressing interest in at least two areas. Hoorah for hybrids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;enthusiasm-vs-talent&#34;&gt;Enthusiasm vs talent&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I was keen to emphasise at this point was &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;interest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in skill areas, not experience and not ability. If I’m asking to mentor people who are starting out in the industry, I can’t possibly expect them to have a wealth of experience in all the relevant areas. And those areas that they do have experience in may not be those they enjoy. Likewise, I can’t expect anyone to be fully proficient in their skill of choice. I can always advise them the best place to learn relevant new knowledge. All I need is for them to know the basics and &lt;strong&gt;really want&lt;/strong&gt; to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;favourite-work&#34;&gt;Favourite work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fairly typical interview-style question. You could ask someone what their “best” piece of work was, and you may get their favourite piece of work, but you’re equally likely to get their most technically-proficient piece of work, or that which they think is most impressive, even if they hated the project and don’t like the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I asked for the candidate’s favourite project and why it was their favourite. I think this got me more of an insight into what they really cared about, and what holds the most value for them in a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;too-early-for-this-information&#34;&gt;Too early for this information&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it was good to know I had an even coverage of skill areas at this stage, and what their favourite project was, it was too soon to use this information. Without knowing the project we were going to work on, how was I to judge how well the project would suit them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-stage&#34;&gt;Second stage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I knew what the project was going to be, there was more purpose in my questions. I sent another email to the remaining eight candidates. At this point I became sure that I was looking for three mentees to work as a team. I thought that this wouldn’t be too many people to make communication difficult, but enough to cope with the project in a way that would give them time to enjoy what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;still-interested&#34;&gt;Still interested?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked again if they were still interested. I wanted to make sure nobody felt like they’d committed to the project just through expressing their interest over a week ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wordpress-experience&#34;&gt;WordPress experience&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project brief states that the website needs to be based on WordPress. Without going too much into the project or client (yet!) I knew that this was an appropriate solution for the project, so I really needed to find at least one candidate with some WordPress experience to lead that part of the development. Everybody showed willingness to learn even if they didn’t have any experience (love them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;blogging-the-process&#34;&gt;Blogging the process&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After realising that a lot of people were talking about the project on Twitter, and I’d promised to blog about it, I realised that I’d have to make sure that any mentees were happy with me doing this, and trusted me to do the right thing. So, lastly I asked if they were happy with me writing about them. I emphasised that this wasn’t really about me picking the right match, I was just wondering how much to blog and how much to mention them. Obviously I would never post anything that just pointed out flaws in somebody’s work, but if we learn from our mistakes through constructive criticism, I think that’s a positive experience that we can collectively share and use to help other people learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody was happy with me blogging; I was starting to worry as their supportiveness was making it harder to choose!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-stage&#34;&gt;Third stage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I was desperately trying to work out the best ways to narrow down the list. I decided that it would be most sensible to ask what everybody’s weekly availability was, and which timezones/locations they were based in. I was fully expecting remote working, but it was important that the mentees were able to work together in a team and communicate easily. This helped me find three people whose availability suited each other, and whose skills complemented each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-final-decision&#34;&gt;The final decision&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I didn’t anticipate was deciding that a couple of candidates were over-qualified for working in these teams. Looking at their experience, I was concerned that if they worked in a team, they would end up picking up too much of the slack because they had a significantly broader knowledge in web design and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dream-team&#34;&gt;The dream team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got my team down to the following three:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sibweber&#34;&gt;Sibylle&lt;/a&gt; –; Lead on WordPress and Content Strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yagohimself&#34;&gt;Yago&lt;/a&gt; –; Lead on Front-end Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/philippickering&#34;&gt;Phil&lt;/a&gt; –; Lead on Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another benefit to team work would be that roles needn’t be fixed,  I expect the team to work together as closely as possible. Still, I thought I’d recommend that each mentee has their area to lead so they know how valuable they are to the project’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;onwards&#34;&gt;Onwards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we will have our first client meeting and get started on the project. I’ll have another update then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-comments&#34;&gt;4 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-481&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/62f1c041b638db2c75f89405510c99ad?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/62f1c041b638db2c75f89405510c99ad?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://graphiceyedea.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Prisca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-481&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-11T11:06:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:06am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Laura,

thanks for this write-up –; nice to read about how you made your decision, bet it wasn’t an easy task :) Curious to follow this project now and see how it will work out—good luck to you all :)&lt;/p&gt;
*PS: from my perspective as their tutor, I am so very happy that your final selection included Yago and Sibylle ~ they’re both lovely as well as talented and will contribute some great work ;)*
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-482&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/288f43b2e85b2451c08aa86f0e0453ad?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/288f43b2e85b2451c08aa86f0e0453ad?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.lockedowndesign.com/blog&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;John J. Locke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-482&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-11T11:22:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:22am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I think this is a really wonderful thing that you are doing, Laura. In order to make the future of the Web better, we need to start with the people. One of my goals for this year is to find a mentor as well. I realize that I have many areas that I need to improve, but I also believe I have a lot to offer to the right team somewhere. 

I look forward to seeing how your mentees progress over the coming weeks and months. Keep making the web a better place. :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-483&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d79515da471fd47145164f59f137b97c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d79515da471fd47145164f59f137b97c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.shaundunne.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Shaun Dunne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-483&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-11T15:38:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:38pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Laura, 

This is such an inspiring thing to do, made me consider how I might go about mentoring more people and helping them build skills. Looking forward to seeing this work and how we can all help usher in new designers and developers onto the web.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-484&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/40e5f43ea869f4943cae2b04e0b25d0d?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/40e5f43ea869f4943cae2b04e0b25d0d?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.andrewsmorris.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;andy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-484&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-02-12T07:05:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;07:05am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I was disappointed not to be picked for this, but I’d like to wish you the best of luck for the project! 

Can’t wait to see how it turns out, it’s such a nice thing to do for folks.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the right project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is an update on &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/&#34; title=&#34;Mentoring a project: The idea&#34;&gt;my mentoring project idea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-the-right-project&#34;&gt;Finding the right project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Twitter, you might have seen that I’m now looking for a different project to work on. Whilst the previous project I had in mind would have been great fun, the client had a very tight deadline. I didn’t want to push that pressure on to students and freelancers who are likely to have other work they need to do in order to pass their studies or pay the bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that typical situation where the client can have it two of three ways “fast, cheap, good quality.” Working on a project that doesn’t allow time for good quality isn’t going to help anyone get worthwhile experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-would-be-the-right-project&#34;&gt;What would be the right project?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to think about what would make the ideal project in this kind of situation. This is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 13px;&#34;&gt;A website project where the end goal would be to launch the site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new website or a complete redesign, so new ideas can be generated and developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A project where every element (design, development, hosting) is entirely in the freelancer’s hands, so they can get a wide experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A project with one or two stakeholders (clients) so that communication is fairly straight-forward (but still of utmost importance!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A modest budget. I want everyone to gain something, so there may not be a huge budget for the project, but I want there to be &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; budget. Of course, the experience is supposed to be the valuable part of this project, but I wouldn’t work for free so I wouldn’t encourage anyone else to do it either.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-you-have-a-project-that-we-could-use&#34;&gt;Do you have a project that we could use?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means I’m now looking for a more suitable project. If you’re in need of a small(ish) website, and don’t have the budget for a fulltime professional web designer or developer, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/contact-me/&#34; title=&#34;Contact Me&#34;&gt;get in touch with me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grid Frameworks and why I’m not keen on them…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 19:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written &lt;a href=&#34;http://12devsofxmas.co.uk/post/2013-01-01-day-7-grid-frameworks&#34;&gt;a post for 12 Devs of Xmas on Grid Frameworks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending months whining about grid frameworks, 960.gs and Bootstrap, I’ve finally backed up my tweet-sized complaints with some context and examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew it would be contentious and that some people would feel antagonised by my saying that developers who don’t consider accessibility shouldn’t be on the web. And possibly also that I suggest some developers lazily fail to customise frameworks to appropriately suit their needs. So far, the reasons behind these feelings seem to be a lack of control over their own work, blaming clients or bosses. I don’t know what to say to be helpful in these situations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me, I would refuse to do a job that wouldn’t fit my idea of quality development. If there’s not enough time to make a site accessible (the idea of this still baffles me as I consider accessibility part of core development) then there’s not enough time to finish the project. It does feel rather unhelpful telling someone that, if their boss/client is forcing them to do things in the wrong way, they should quit their job, and I probably care about these things a lot harder than many, but honestly, that’s what I’d do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m sure I’ll be dealing with more accessibility-related issues in the future. It’s far too easy for me to go off on a rant and a ramble, I just want more people to care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-comments&#34;&gt;7 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-435&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3368e6126004d4fe7b1f7edfdbf7e5d6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3368e6126004d4fe7b1f7edfdbf7e5d6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.craigmcpheat.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Craig McPheat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-435&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-02T15:26:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:26pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I appreciate and agree with your sentiment about semantic markup, and accessibility, but I think you may have jumped the gun in [Day 7: Grid Frameworks](http://12devsofxmas.co.uk/post/2013-01-01-day-7-grid-frameworks&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow) by implying grid frameworks are inherently inaccessible.

I argue against front end frameworks in my day to day job. The reasons I cite are:

&lt;p&gt;1) developers need to learn the framework, not the underlying technology

2) our web standards require semantic markup, which frameworks often lack out the box

3) frameworks look like a framework –; sometimes as much work is required to theme it as there would be to build from scratch

4) frameworks often mean extra bytes –; superfluous markup contradicts my requirements for mobile first / every byte counts&lt;/p&gt;
I get where you’re coming from and agree in most parts. I’m not saying I’ll never use a front end framework, but I do campaign for refining and building our own internal boilerplates.

It’s important to be careful when choosing arguments to protect accessibility. To say using a grid framework would introduce a risk to the accessibility of the site would be careless if not untrue, thus risking the importance of the accessibility argument. Like all things, the devil is in the detail. If those grids had semantic class names rather than grid_whatever they’d be no more accessible. You rightly point out some basic semantics required for a good accessible build –; lists, heading levels, good anchor text –; but these are separate from the structure provided by a grid framework. (Of course, all this goes without mention of landmark areas, aria, skip to main content etc)

(As an aside, is it terrible to use a grid as the structure and object orientate the theme with semantic classnames alongside the grid_whatevers?)

I agree accessibility and semantics are both important, but I think there’s a lot of detail missing to get from point A to point B in your post and subsequent comments, which is very dangerous when promoting the cause to senior stakeholders and those who need to understand the cold hard facts without emotion.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-436&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-436&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-02T17:06:57+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:06pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks Craig, there’s some great points in there, and I think you’re right in saying that I was making a bit of leap, here’s my explanation why:

I was really trying to create an argument around your point 2. “Our web standards require semantic markup, which frameworks often lack out of the box.” But then I came to ask myself: why do semantics matter? Why bother making anything semantic? I know that **I** think that semantics are important, but how do you explain it to someone who just thinks that semantics are about being fussy?

So I went one level deeper. Why are semantics so important to me? Chiefly, accessibility. Then reusability, maintenance etc. Thus my post became about these things, brushing over the semantics that people often disregard as purist.

I’m sorry if I didn’t convey the point well enough, and you’ve definitely given me some food for thought in terms of how I represent accessibility.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-437&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3368e6126004d4fe7b1f7edfdbf7e5d6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/3368e6126004d4fe7b1f7edfdbf7e5d6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.craigmcpheat.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Craig McPheat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-437&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-02T17:57:55+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:57pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        No apology necessary Laura, any constructive discussion on accessibility is good discussion.

I too am incredibly passionate about semantic markup and accessibility, but the reason I need to be careful is there’s always someone ready with a counter; a supplier, external developers, project managers&amp;#8230; I push back on poorly structured content all the time. As you mention, the basic but big ticket items like heading levels, form inputs, lists, good anchor text are all essential –; but would I push back on someone for using a grid framework? Probably not, as the site can be completely accessible whilst using a grid system, just as much as a more semantic site can be inaccessible.

If I’m honest, I would actually have to pay more attention if a supplier uses HTML5 sectioning elements to &lt;b&gt;structure the document “semantically”&lt;/b&gt;, as these cause problems with the document outline when not implemented correctly:

[HTML5 sectioning elements, headings, and document outlines](http://www.456bereastreet.com/archive/201103/html5_sectioning_elements_headings_and_document_outlines/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)

[HTML5 document outline revisited](http://www.456bereastreet.com/archive/201104/html5_document_outline_revisited/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-438&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ed2eb293beec01de6d0081a2371fae06?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ed2eb293beec01de6d0081a2371fae06?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Marc&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-438&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-03T08:10:10+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:10am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I largely agree with your opinion on inaccessible, non-semantic grid systems. However, your post would have been more balanced if you had paid some attention to the existing alternatives. More semantic grid systems, such as [Susy](http://susy.oddbird.net/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow), [Singularity](http://singularity.gs/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow) and [Zen Grids](http://zengrids.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow) make it very easy to apply a custom grid to your own semantic HTML structure.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment byuser comment-author-laura bypostauthor even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-439&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-439&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-03T08:44:42+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;08:44am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I would if I were more familiar with the alternatives! That’s why I cautiously tweeted that Sass is probably the answer. And whilst I do use Sass, I still write all my grids from scratch. This might be foolish, or because I’m a creature of habit having done that with CSS since I started out……I’m not sure which!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-440&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ed2eb293beec01de6d0081a2371fae06?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/ed2eb293beec01de6d0081a2371fae06?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Marc&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-440&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-01-03T09:04:56+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:04am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        OK, I didn’t see that tweet. I’d say just give Susy a try and keep an eye on [Susy Next](http://oddbird.net/2013/01/01/susy-next/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)!
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Tour Brighton</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://insitestour.com/&#34;&gt;Insites&lt;/a&gt; is a mini tour of four cities in the UK where &lt;a href=&#34;http://keirwhitaker.com/&#34;&gt;Keir Whitaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://elliotjaystocks.com/&#34;&gt;Elliot Jay Stocks&lt;/a&gt; present discussions with well-known people from the web/tech industry. I was lucky enough to go to the first evening in Brighton on Monday where &lt;a href=&#34;http://aralbalkan.com/&#34;&gt;Aral Balkan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sazzy.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Sarah Parmenter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://adactio.com/&#34;&gt;Jeremy Keith&lt;/a&gt; were the guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-format&#34;&gt;The Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of the evening was something unfamiliar to most of us. Each guest was interviewed by either Keir or Elliot and then there were questions from the audience. Except it was much less formal than that. There were breaks in between and a comfortably small amount of people (I’m rubbish at estimating amounts of people so I’ll save you the pain) so there was a really relaxed and casual environment where everybody seemed happy to chat about anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The genius was really in the way it was run. Keir and Elliot asked really interesting and leading questions and Aral, Sarah and Jeremy were all open and honest so they genuinely did provide insight into their lives in the web/tech industry. I don’t think it would have worked had the interviewers been unfamiliar with the guests, and with Keir and Elliot both working in the industry doing similar jobs to most people in the audience, their questions always felt appropriate and had something of the &lt;em&gt;that’s-just-what-I-wanted-to-ask&lt;/em&gt; about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-actual-insights&#34;&gt;The Actual Insights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that struck me about each of the guests (and a lot of people I spoke to) was that everybody was self-taught in some way. That’s really inspiring for anybody wanting to work with the web or iOS. Each of the guests hadn’t studied design or development formally yet they’re helping lead the way and set the standards in user experience, iOS design and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, despite not having formal education, Aral, Sarah and Jeremy each teach workshops. It goes to show how well they know their subject matter in order to host successful workshops, but also how the semi-formalisation of education can work and enough people seem to enjoy learning that way (rather than self-teaching through books or the web.) And a lot of people must prefer this way of learning as the amount of workshops seem to be on the up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;client-work&#34;&gt;Client Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the directions that a lot of web industry professionals seem to be taking lately is moving away from client work and towards making their own products. Aral was incredibly passionate about how much more he enjoyed working for himself in every sense, rather than having ever-changing clients for bosses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah provided some great advice on the warning signs when starting work with potential clients, as she’s had her fair share of painful client relationships, and relayed that she thinks she’s just* too* nice and so clients take advantage. As someone who completely identifies with the niceness approach, it was heartening to see that Sarah has found such great clients that she’s considering working for two exclusively. This is also interesting as it shows more of that same direction of moving away from working with different clients and towards maintaining products as a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy was honest in saying he preferred to just get on with the development, and is very fortunate to work as part of an agency where Andy Budd enjoys handling the clients and accounts sides of a project. I think many freelancers find the sales and admin are the worst part of the job so it made sense that forming an agency with like-minded people would be a good idea, but Jeremy pointed out that this does only really work if there is one individual who is happy to work on the ‘business’ side whilst the others work on the project itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outlooks&#34;&gt;Outlooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I took away in summary to these talks was really one big point, &lt;strong&gt;everybody there was following a career path based around what makes them happy and fulfilled over what might make them rich&lt;/strong&gt;. And this really emphasises what I love so much about the industry. People are there because they enjoy it, people want to make a difference and make the web a really cool place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-the-rest&#34;&gt;And The Rest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of the Insites tour, people came with a willingness to discuss work, process and dealing with clients rather than focusing on the techniques and technologies that we go on about during the working day. This lead to a few good discussions outside of the talks with the guests where I felt my brain buzzing from finally starting to understand a bit more about how we work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-endlessly-lucky-with-the-clients-i-have&#34;&gt;I am endlessly lucky with the clients I have&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assumed that most people had good clients. From the various discussions it does look like I am very lucky in having ended up with *predominantly* lovely, responsive, &lt;strong&gt;paying-on-time&lt;/strong&gt; clients. After talking to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrqwest.co.uk/cc/&#34;&gt;Croydon Creatives&lt;/a&gt; bunch (and also something Sarah mentioned,) we really seemed to conclude that having a top contract is one of the most important aspects of client work. Not necessarily a boring law-speak contract, but something that appealed to the client and showed that you’re a human who deserves to be paid for your hard work, as well as laying out some &lt;em&gt;just-in-case&lt;/em&gt; terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;labels-and-titles&#34;&gt;Labels and Titles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the final fascinating conversation that was really ongoing throughout the evening outside of the talks was about labelling. It stemmed from Aral and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.andybudd.com/&#34;&gt;Andy Budd&lt;/a&gt;‘s disagreement on what makes a UX Designer, but lead to discussing how we describe ourselves to clients and each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally learnt the different between ‘&lt;strong&gt;indie&lt;/strong&gt;‘ and ‘&lt;strong&gt;freelance&lt;/strong&gt;‘ (indie means you produce work for yourself or customers, freelance means you work for clients) and that Jeremy Keith works somewhere between a rotating job title and none whatsoever because it’s the work that do that speaks for you, rather than what you call yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion that I came to was that labels are a pain. Everybody is judged on what they call themselves and, within the industry, it doesn’t really matter as soon as you’re familiar with somebody’s work. What we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need labels and job titles for is accurately communicating what we do to potential clients. This means we should forget about the acronyms and jargon and sometimes the most appropriate description is ‘&lt;strong&gt;I make websites&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-if-you-re-in-manchester-or-bristol-this-week-go&#34;&gt;So if you’re in Manchester or Bristol this week, go!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a day to write this post, so I’m a bit late in telling people to go to the London leg of the Insites tour, but Manchester is tonight and Bristol is tomorrow night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was definitely one of the best events I’ve attended in a while, and one that just gave me faith in how the industry and community is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;brilliant&lt;/strong&gt; (and probably the best ever.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: please forgive my enthusiasm in this post, I hope it’s not &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; annoying, but I had a really good time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-comments&#34;&gt;3 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-249&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e447058d3157368c3919157905bd8de3?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/e447058d3157368c3919157905bd8de3?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://mrqwest.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Anthony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-249&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-07-20T13:20:17+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:20pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great write up Laura, and pretty much summed up the way I felt after the evening too! 

@MrQwest
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-250&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/77b178c0c5bec748485307a18e73c6b9?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/77b178c0c5bec748485307a18e73c6b9?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.simoncox.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Simon Cox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-250&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-07-20T17:07:04+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:07pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great write up Laura –; captured the essence very well. Excellent evening and a pleasure to meet you.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-251&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b47e4f9448a175c868e8088abe08f778?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b47e4f9448a175c868e8088abe08f778?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.georgewiscombe.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;George Wiscombe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-251&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2011-07-20T18:33:53+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:33pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I couldn’t agree more with your thoughts on labels &amp;amp; titles, I think the same applies to CV’s (in the creative industries at least).  A list of academic achievements or awesome companies you’ve worked at doesn’t matter to me, it’s all about the quality of work *you* produce and the way in which you can articulate your ideas. 

The merits from working with great people &amp;amp; big brands definitely go some way to helping with that, but it’s not everything.

Great post, thanks for sharing –; sounds like a great evening! I’ll write the London night up when I get a chance to breathe :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After I finished my last post about &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/&#34;&gt;Design Tips for Developers&lt;/a&gt;, it really struck me how much I wrote to justify my design. I wasn’t just writing tips saying “*do this, it’s good*“, “*don’t do this, it’s bad.*” I put time and effort into explaining why I made these decisions and why I didn’t do it another way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I send a design to a client via e-mail, I usually spend around 45 minutes –; 1 hour writing an accompanying ‘justification’. I really have no idea if I’m the only one that does this? I assume not. I know a lot of people don’t, they just send static images. Does this mean it’s not worthwhile?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-do-justifications&#34;&gt;How I do justifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an excerpt from my last post, giving a classic example of how I write justifications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve limited the ‘Latest Happenings’ to only five events on my design. My reasoning being that if you have many more than that, they’re not really ‘latest’ anymore. This way we can ensure that the amount of happenings are well-balanced with the content on the left side of the page. Although the ‘What is Lift?’ content is liable to changing, I imagine that it wouldn’t increase too much more in length, as any further information and you’re going into the depths of documentation that probably isn’t suitable for a home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to cover all the basics of the design. I explain my choices regarding layout, typography, colour and imagery. I summarise any other methods or angles I tried that didn’t work, and explain why I thought they didn’t work. If I’m not actually sure why I did something on impulse, I’ll really think about it, analyse my decision and explain it to the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-write-justifications&#34;&gt;Why I write justifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#### Not all design work can speak for itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clients aren’t design specialists so you can’t expect them to ‘get’ your thinking behind a design just by looking at it (And you probably couldn’t expect most other designers to ‘get’ it either!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#### I don’t often get to speak to the client in person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fairly easy to quickly summarise your design when you can look at a person’s face and see if they understand you. When you’re lacking face-to-face communication, you really have to make up for it in writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#### Even if I do see a client face-to-face, I’ll often forget something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting down and writing a proper explanation helps me look over the design from top to bottom and take it apart. It also takes a while for a client to mull over a design. They might be unsure of part of it later on at home. Having your justification there to reassure them can be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-was-also-taught-how&#34;&gt;I was also taught how&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every now and again I realise the huge value in being taught art and graphics at school, college and university. From secondary school art lessons onwards, one-third of the work was research, one-third was the practical application and the final third was evaluation. Even if the rest of the work wasn’t perfect, if the evaluation was good then you’d be on to a winner. It wasn’t about being skilled with a pencil or paintbrush, it was about being able to reflect, evaluate and actually understand what you were trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-able-to-give-a-reason&#34;&gt;Being able to give a reason&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe a huge part of your ability as a designer is understanding why you do what you do. In order to create an appropriate and usable design, you’ve got to be able to do better than ‘pretty.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a designer &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be able to tell a client the reasoning behind their design decisions. There’s nothing worse than the ‘professional’ who says “&lt;em&gt;I like it best like this and I’m the professional so you should respect my opinion&lt;/em&gt;.” Of course, everybody has their own preferences, theories and leanings, but if you can’t come up with a reason beyond “I like it” or “everybody’s doing it”, then what service are you actually providing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;value-for-a-client&#34;&gt;Value for a client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading a description about your design decisions lets a client know you’ve really thought their design through. I’m hoping I show my clients that I spend a long time considering my design work and trying to make something that will work for them. When you’re providing a service, rather than a physical product, it’s good to remind people that you’re good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;value-for-a-designer&#34;&gt;Value for a designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sending a justification I find there are fewer arguments. Full stop. As I’ve got better at writing them, I’ve found more clients agree with my decisions. I hope I’m also improving as a designer, but it’s also incredibly difficult to disagree with a design element when someone has given you a very good logical reason why it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t get “make my logo bigger”, “can you do another version?” or “I want it in Papyrus”. I know I’m fantastically fortunate to work with lovely people, but I reckon explaining yourself (and maybe being a bit persuasive) might also have something to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on a design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/&#34; title=&#34;Using Dribbble and Forrst for feedback on a client project&#34;&gt;discussing Dribbble and Forrst&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/&#34; title=&#34;Good old designer snobbery is alive and kicking&#34;&gt;my latest post that looked at criticism in design&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve been thinking a lot more about how feedback features in my design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-stuck&#34;&gt;Getting stuck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I used to get stuck on a design, from ‘creative block’ or a complete lack of inspiration, I would frantically brainstorm, then browse inspiration sites, then ask the opinions of other designers. Usually the feedback from other designers would form the basis of my amendments, I’d gain inspiration from those changes and continue work from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow it didn’t feel right though, I didn’t feel like I was working for myself, asking other designers could feel a bit like cheating. I didn’t like how detached it made me feel from the design when I started to follow the ideas of other designers that have completely different approaches and styles from my own. I decided I don’t feel comfortable sharing work in those stages with other designers as they can be a negative influence on me. Not because they make bad suggestions, but because I work to satisfy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No longer craving that kind of approval, I’ve realised that I make extensive use of two new types of feedback, client feedback and ‘boyfriend’ feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;client-feedback&#34;&gt;Client Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it might sound totally obvious. Inevitably, you will always get feedback from the client at &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; point. However I’ve found myself doing this at earlier and earlier stages since I starting working freelance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I’ve been going straight into talking to the client as soon as the design slows down or is coming suspiciously quickly (usually a sign that I’ve jumped on a bandwagon or just acted on my first, badly thought-out idea.) I came to the conclusion that there’s no point searching for answers so far away from the problem. The client is the one person who set the brief and will approve the results, they’re the beginning and the end, so why not involve them more in the middle as well?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feedback-now-polish-later&#34;&gt;Feedback now, polish later&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number one newbie mistake is showing a client a 100% complete mockup (or even live) page design. I’ve done it, and kicked myself for it. Chances are you’ll have really jumped on an idea and run with it. The problem is that the client might not like your angle or approach. You’ve just wasted a huge amount of hours on something that is rejected outright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;you-re-designing-for-the-client&#34;&gt;You’re designing for the client&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no need to be fearful of showing something incomplete. Clients aren’t stupid, and if you explain that the work is unfinished but you’re looking for their input on what you’ve done so far, they’re likely to be grateful that you’re keeping them in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfinished work doesn’t necessarily mean bad work either. You’re not posting your work online for the world to see, you’re sharing progress and developing designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-feedback-now&#34;&gt;The benefits of feedback now&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the client is finding it hard to understand your approach, or flatly hates it, you’ve got time to discuss, justify, rework and whatever else is needed to create something that your client loves and you know will work for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is just creative problem solving. If the client isn’t keen on what you’ve shown them and you’ve got some useful criticism, you’re further refining the problem which will help get you closer to the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;boyfriend-feedback&#34;&gt;Boyfriend Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelance designer, I’m very lucky to have another person around me while I work. My boyfriend &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MatthewFuller&#34; title=&#34;Matt Fuller on Twitter&#34;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; works in the same room at home and is an honest critic of everything I do, whether I want his opinion or not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-client-and-non-designer-feedback&#34;&gt;Non-client and non-designer feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt is great at giving me reactionary critiques. In this way, he’s far more like a client or a user. He’ll tell me he thinks it’s rubbish, and give a vague idea of why, usually based on reactions and associations such as “it reminds me of X.” Matt’s reasons are never because it’s not on trend, or it doesn’t make use of available technologies. In fact, he often hates the fashionable styles and can convince me to be more reasonable and not succumb to “but this looks pretty.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that struck me about the discussions about criticism on Dribbble, and the Gap logo, is that the type of feedback a designer gives is totally unlike the thoughts and opinions of clients and users. Those thoughts and opinions are exactly that. They’re not necessarily put in context or very constructive but they are the emotions and associations which are so hard to put into words but have a huge impact on your design’s effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;community-helps-and-hinders&#34;&gt;Community helps and hinders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the amount of apps and tools showing up to help designers communicate more effectively with other designers. It’s fun to share, and it’s fun to have a bit of mutual-appreciation going on. However I think I’m likely to fall into the trap of designing for these communities, for approval of other designers and developers, and totally forgetting the blindingly obvious user needs and client necessities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I the only one? I think it’s hard to tell from the outside. Some people are very capable of creating work that is incredibly satisfying to users, clients, other designers and themselves. The order in which they aimed to please isn’t obvious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-comments&#34;&gt;2 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-149&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aff5641764408271f7bc398f2097edd0?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aff5641764408271f7bc398f2097edd0?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.robotregime.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Dennis Kardys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-149&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-10-15T19:44:10+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:44pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura,

I also find it challenging to ask for feedback early on since there are so many different directions a design might take. For me, changing the way in which I frame my request for feedback has been a big help, both when talking to clients and with other designers. Instead of an entirely open invitation for critique (which may come later when the design is more complete), I usually try to pose very direct questions that identify the problems as opposed to recommending the solution. &amp;quot;Do you think the call to action should be more prominent?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;What type of feeling does this color scheme evoke&amp;quot;, etc.

Your post also made me think about ownership of a design, and how there is a pride that goes along with coming up with the ideas and inventing the solutions. I think it&amp;#039;s important to be aware of times when that sense of pride may conflict with the best interest of the project. Does that make sense?

I also totally agree that it&amp;#039;s helpful to have someone who is not the client or another designer, but who can be brutally honest to tell you what they think.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-150&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;damilare&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-150&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-10-16T00:06:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;00:06am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag I think a huge difference between client feedback and designer feedback is aesthetic vs business goals, the latter, the better.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me vs We</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 10:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There’s something that’s been niggling at me for ages. The way people act as if they’re a multi-person company when they’re really just one individual. This whole ‘we’ syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great new client now working with us at Just Little Old Me Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it makes me giggle when I know somebody is an individual ‘me’ and they’re saying ‘we’ as if they’re some kind of medieval queen. I just can’t help feeling it’s a little bit deceptive to act in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother&#34;&gt;Why bother?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see there’s a couple of reasons why people feel the need to pretend to be bigger than they really are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes them look big and official to others, making them look more trustworthy. &lt;em&gt;That company won’t run away with my money, but that single cowboy there might do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems to give them some kind of prestige over that teenage kid working in his bedroom. &lt;em&gt;Oh, it’s not just a student, they’re a proper company&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-really-why-do-we-do-this&#34;&gt;But really, why do we do this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web is still young, and it’s incredibly difficult to tell the hardworking souls from the shady characters. If most of your communication is web-based, without meeting face-to-face or even speaking on the phone, it’s hard for a client to pick up on those gut instincts and little signs that tells you somebody can’t be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve come to inherently trust bigger companies. People will eat in a chain restaurant because they know what to expect. Companies made up of multiple people appear to be more stable because there’s more people to get the work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can understand why it looks good to be big company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-just-being-deceptive&#34;&gt;It’s just being deceptive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really don’t understand about people who create this façade of a multiple person company is that they’re losing all the benefits of appearing to be trustworthy and stable. If you’re lying (however well-intended that lie is,) you’re no-longer credible. I have an immediate distrust of anybody who claims who says ‘we’ when they’re really just a ‘me’ as I wonder what other truths they’re bending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying ‘we’ and talking as a company and not an individual also makes you seem detached. Is your company persona all that different from your individual persona? If it is, then why? Why do you have to pretend to be a different person to do business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-really-not-all-that-bad-being-a-me&#34;&gt;It’s really not all that bad being a ‘me’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Laura Kalbag, I’m a sole trader and my company is called ‘Laura Kalbag’. What you see really is what you get. Sometimes I sense a lack of trust in me because I’m not an agency or a big company. You know what, I don’t care. I’d rather not work with somebody who suspects I might not be reliable. If we’re starting out with some big fat negative preconceptions, it’s going to be harder to get positive feelings from that person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an individual, people can be assured that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m the one doing all the work. They will talk to me and I will execute the designs, development etc all based on our direct conversation. There’s less room for misinterpretation if there’s only one link in the chain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m as vulnerable as them. Weakness isn’t always negative. I’ve got to directly make money to have food and shelter, so have my clients. It’s much more personal when you’re not throwing somebody else’s money around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t have to check that what I’m saying is the right thing on behalf of my company and/or employer. Ditch all the legalese, I’m talking to you man-to-man (or girl-to-man or girl-to-girl, you see what I mean!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-feel-like-i-m-good-enough&#34;&gt;I feel like I’m good enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s upsides and downsides to hiring a freelancer or an agency but the important thing is that I’m happy with what I am. If you’ve got no confidence in yourself as an individual freelancer, then go find yourself some like-minds and form an agency!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not arrogance to say I feel like I’m good enough to speak as myself. I’ve got as many insecurities as the next person but I enjoy being a human, friendly face in a sea of (often) faceless companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next time you’re thinking of saying ‘we’ when you just mean ‘me’, think about how much that little word means. I think it’d be better if everybody was a little bit more honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;36-comments&#34;&gt;36 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-54&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;ibernat&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-54&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T09:49:51+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:49am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag This is funny when people write “Our work” on personal pages
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-52&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55208acc66708f2fbbd95f1fca239771?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55208acc66708f2fbbd95f1fca239771?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.jemjabella.co.uk/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-52&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T10:51:33+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:51am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Well said. It’s almost like some sole traders are ashamed to work by themselves, for themselves &amp;amp; I don’t understand why.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-53&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Craig Hawker&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-53&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T10:53:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:53am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        One reason small companies do this is when they are –; sometimes –; a ‘we’.  As an example, I know a small company that is legally a ‘me’, but they subcontract where needed to become a ‘we’.

Therefore, going to a company and stating that ‘we’ can accomplish something, even though that company only has one employee, is accurate; they become a ‘we’ as and when needed.

I know you’re not necessarily pointing the finger at these type of companies, but they are often the ones who you’ll find out later are a ‘me’ but call themselves a ‘we’.  From an investigatory perspective they’re a ‘me’, but work with them and you’ll find they become a ‘we’ as needed.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-55&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-55&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T11:59:32+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:59am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I was really talking about individuals who are genuinely individuals but I get your point.

Seems like a fairly confusing situation becoming a &amp;#039;we&amp;#039; as and when. I frequently work with other people but don&amp;#039;t hire them myself or speak for them, so that&amp;#039;s why I&amp;#039;m always a &amp;#039;me&amp;#039;.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-59&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/19f4ecd23326a2f55288b690a66e3d47?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/19f4ecd23326a2f55288b690a66e3d47?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;christopher&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-59&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T11:07:26+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:07am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Good point –; i’m a designer, but i get customers wanting dev work.

I have 3 or 4 other freelancers i use for code, i have a couple of printing companies i use who are almost part of my team.

The student argument is also valid in this case. I AM a student, and i am running a business, but i’ve been doing both for the past 5 years, all my customers are aware of that and none of them have a problem with it&amp;#8230;

So yes, maybe I should put ‘I’, but a lot of the things I offer, i personally do not do..

A toughie.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-60&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Craig Hawker&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-60&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:09:07+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:09pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I guess and you&amp;#039;re right –; from your statement, you&amp;#039;re a &amp;#039;me&amp;#039;.

I&amp;#039;m talking more about single-owner companies with no full-time employees, but they have other companies or self-employed people that they consistently subcontract work to.

As an example, a web designer may be asked to implement a website that requires some technical skill, some development/integration work, some copywriting, etc.  Under these circumstances, provided there&amp;#039;s money for it, that designer may decide to subcontract elements out (get an engineer in for a couple of hours for the technical work, subcontract development and copyrighting work to third parties&amp;#8230;).  Would it be wrong to refer to the web designer&amp;#039;s company as a &amp;#039;me&amp;#039; in a tender?  It certainly would not be a &amp;#039;me&amp;#039; who completed the work.  However, if all the work is whitelabelled (done under the web designer&amp;#039;s brand, all paid to the web designer then paid on as appropriate), why shouldn&amp;#039;t they call themselves &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;?

I&amp;#039;m playing devil&amp;#039;s advocate to a degree.  It doesn&amp;#039;t affect where I work (we&amp;#039;re definitely a &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;) but we provide technical resources to companies who are &amp;#039;me&amp;#039;s, but promote themselves as &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;s.  Do I think it ever really makes a difference when we go up against them?  Not really.  And, from the customer&amp;#039;s perspective, as long as they&amp;#039;re getting what they asked for and are happy with the service, why should they mind?
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-4&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-63&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-63&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:17:01+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:17pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        If it&amp;#039;s &amp;#039;we&amp;#039; doing the work then &amp;#039;we&amp;#039; should get the credit, it would be wrong to claim that &amp;#039;me&amp;#039; is doing the work when it&amp;#039;s really more than one person. I&amp;#039;d be pretty annoyed if I hired someone to do work for me and found out that they&amp;#039;d outsourced it.

I just think that everybody should make it perfectly clear who is doing what in those cases. You don&amp;#039;t have to confuse a client with the technicalities, but there&amp;#039;s no harm in saying &amp;#039;I don&amp;#039;t do this, but so-and-so does so I pay them to do it for me. Is that cool with you?&amp;#039;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-5&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-68&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Craig Hawker&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-68&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:32:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:32pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Well, yes and no.

Yes, I believe that honesty is the best policy in most things (work matters in particular), but I understand why people aren&amp;#039;t up-front about it.  As I said, if the customer is getting what they want, for the price they want, and they&amp;#039;re happy with the service, why does it matter?  All you&amp;#039;re doing is actively highlighting that you&amp;#039;re a one-man-band to the customer and that can be a negative.

That&amp;#039;s before you get into larger organisations with approved supplier lists etc.  For those, actively pushing the fact that you don&amp;#039;t do the work yourself can cause problems.

That said, would this be an issue with web design?  I have had issues where major additional design work/modification was needed quickly (I worked with an organisation deeply affected by foot and mouth a few years ago).  If the design agency was unavailable, or not able to react because of resource issues, that would have been a problem.  So much that it&amp;#039;s now part of risk assessments for suppliers.

Coming across as a &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;, even though that &amp;#039;we&amp;#039; may be a collective of &amp;#039;me&amp;#039;s, would put a tick in a box.

Now, I feel like I&amp;#039;m arguing myself into a corner and –; as I said –; I&amp;#039;m playing devil&amp;#039;s advocate to a degree.   I do believe that you&amp;#039;re better off being honest.  We have won a large number of tenders, I believe, because we have had the confidence to stand up in front of people and say &amp;quot;look, that&amp;#039;s not exactly possible, how about this alternative&amp;#8230;&amp;quot;.  People accept that honesty over a quick-fire sales-response of &amp;quot;yes, sure, no problem&amp;quot;.

That said, I just don&amp;#039;t have a problem with &amp;#039;me&amp;#039;s masquerading as &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;s.  And, from the customer&amp;#039;s perspective, I&amp;#039;m not sure they do either.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;p class=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-5&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-84&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/083f7d6bca0497c9a4359c383e75fcb4?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/083f7d6bca0497c9a4359c383e75fcb4?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://armorik.com.ba&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;roni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-84&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T17:45:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;17:45pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Why would you be annoyed if you find out it has been outsourced ?

This is kind of silly, if I may !

Why silly ?

&lt;p&gt;–; You can outsource some part of a job in order to get higher quality. (for same money)

–; You can outsource to have lower cost. (with same quality)

–; You can outsource to speed up production in order to meet deadline. (bcs you are late since you are dead busy but don&amp;#039;t want to pay penalties)&lt;/p&gt;
So?  What&amp;#039;d be your call ?

I don&amp;#039;t get the idea of been against outsourcing because.. .well&amp;#8230; &amp;quot;because I am against !!&amp;quot;

&lt;p&gt;You can build up a team of expert and manage that team, produce high quality work. Who&amp;#039;s going to suffer ?

Now indeed, you hit another field of job, more project management than &amp;quot;design&amp;quot; or however you want to call it; but when you got your own business, and hopefully got to get a few clients at the same time, search for the future at the same time etc&amp;#8230; well, doesn&amp;#039;t it comes to a few hours of PM a day ?&lt;/p&gt;
And when you business is so packed with orders for 1 month or so&amp;#8230; what are you going to do ? Turn down clients ? sleep 2 hours a night ? hire someone for 1 month ? Or outsource a couple of tasks ?

Many companies do, I agree, outsource with only in mind the idea of profit, pay less charge more,  but that&amp;#039;s not everything behind outsourcing and this eventually fails as quality is missing.

You can outsource as well, with great outcome, for 1 million good reasons !

&lt;p&gt;Note : I am an outsourcer. The money is ok in the country I live in, would not allow to survive in yours, for sure.

The only pride I have &amp;amp; take is in the quality of the apps I deliver to my clients. I have no credits, not recognition or all that, only the satisfaction of  quality work.&lt;/p&gt;     &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;p class=&#34;reply&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;





&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-57&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/239967b793837ace06b552199baa433b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/239967b793837ace06b552199baa433b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.ewan.org.uk/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Ewan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-57&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T11:04:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:04am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Laura

while I agree with the sentiments, I can also see why some people may choose to use “we” instead of “I”. For example, I’m sure many of us often rely on the services of others, whether that be outsourcing, or employing someone to do our books once a month. It’s not a team of staff as such, but should the worst happen to the sole trader, there is a confidence instilled that they are not totally locked down to that person.

There is perhaps a small sense of arrogance as well as to saying “I can do this, this, this, that, and this too”. I think by using “we” you can kind of overcome this.

I don’t think it would be particularly difficult to use “we” and not portray yourself as a big company. It should be quite possible through the rest of your copy not to give this impression while still using “we”.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-61&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-61&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:11:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:11pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Couldn&amp;#039;t all this be said on a site? I&amp;#039;m not sure that employing somebody to do your books (which aren&amp;#039;t necessarily relevant to the services that you&amp;#039;re providing) would make you a &amp;#039;we&amp;#039;.

As I said to Craig, I&amp;#039;m not so much getting about who you work with or who employs who, it&amp;#039;s about being honest about who you are and what you do.

There&amp;#039;s nothing arrogant about saying you do it all when you really *do* do it all! That&amp;#039;s just honesty!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-62&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-62&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:12:40+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:12pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        (Although it could come across as arrogant depending on how you say it.)
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-58&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7f4ac75544228f6ed52aea4fa09570d5?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/7f4ac75544228f6ed52aea4fa09570d5?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://gilest.org&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;giles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-58&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:07:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:07pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        *Applause*

I&amp;#039;ve held the same view for years; thank you for expressing it so clearly.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-72&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;mealybar&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-72&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T11:14:06+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:14am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag great post, we/me been on my mind a lot lately. It’s deceitful perhaps without meaning to be.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-64&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576951f66442b28f0dded221a59af51c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576951f66442b28f0dded221a59af51c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.100yen.co.uk/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Jonic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-64&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:19:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:19pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post, Laura..

I&amp;#039;ve always found this a little annoying too.. Like there&amp;#039;s some shame in being small and adaptable..

Anyway, is this the blog you said you might not set up because no one would read it? Looks like you were wrong there!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-65&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/605f29bd5ea7732c8947e6166b451114?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/605f29bd5ea7732c8947e6166b451114?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://skl.me/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Stephen Lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-65&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:20:44+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:20pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        An honest and encouraging article. Thanks for the read.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-66&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d8f35cebbc045646a733938b9a06bdc6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d8f35cebbc045646a733938b9a06bdc6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Dan Palmer&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-66&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:22:38+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:22pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I know someone who runs a business out of his study in his house. It used to be run out of the spare bedroom. However, if the large banks, government departments, or other large businesses he does consulting work for found out this, I doubt they would use him.

If you are asked by your boss to spend money and hire a consultant, do you go for a consulting company or the guy in his bedroom. It is a fairly obvious choice, if only to appear better to your boss.

The person I know uses rented office rooms when needed, he has a phone answering service who will answer the phone at a call centre, record the caller and email him so he can call them back. All of this creates an illusion, but one that is certainly necessary.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-67&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-67&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:32:02+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:32pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It&amp;#039;s a shame that it&amp;#039;s seen as necessary. I know I&amp;#039;m in a very different position, in that I haven&amp;#039;t done work for huge corporations, but I&amp;#039;d like to think that the fact I work from home doesn&amp;#039;t make any difference to the quality of the work I do and so shouldn&amp;#039;t affect somebody&amp;#039;s judgment of me.

But I&amp;#039;m an incredibly wishful thinker.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-74&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-74&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:24:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:24pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Dan,

I can&amp;#039;t speak for your friend&amp;#039;s clients –; but all my clients know the truth about our operation.

You&amp;#039;d be surprised.

We (and it is a we in my case) do work for clients like Waitrose, John Lewis and WWE.

All of them know:

&lt;p&gt;a) We don&amp;#039;t have office

b) I work from a room in my house

c) So do all my staff&lt;/p&gt;
There are advantages to this:

&lt;p&gt;1) Lower overheads, which we pass on to them

2) We work late when needed .. and it makes that easier

3) They know where I live

4) If they call me at 5.35 I haven&amp;#039;t left the office&lt;/p&gt;
Also, people that work for large companies are people –; first and foremost.

They get why you&amp;#039;d want to work from home.  Some of them are even jealous!

&amp;quot;God, I&amp;#039;d love not to have to commute for an hour each morning.  How wonderful. Lucky you!&amp;quot;

I had one client who used to work in the City and gave that up once she saw I was doing fine working from (what was then) a house with a sea view in Cornwall.

She took a job working for a chain of hotels as marketing manager, which had head offices closer to her home.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-78&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-78&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:58:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:58pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Note: My staff work from their own houses .. they don&amp;#039;t all come to mine every day!
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-69&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/645857fa57d63c092fca4a61eff6c6f0?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/645857fa57d63c092fca4a61eff6c6f0?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.maketea.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Matt Hinchliffe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-69&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:39:00+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:39pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I really liked reading this article, points you raise match my experiences and opinions. As a teenager I did this to make myself appear difference from other web kids and it certainly worked.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-70&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6fb3e1dfbb710824c436eb940c0bc1d6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6fb3e1dfbb710824c436eb940c0bc1d6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.simianstudios.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Kris Noble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-70&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:39:10+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:39pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hmm&amp;#8230; this post has made me re-evaluate my own copy.

I use &amp;quot;Simian Studios&amp;quot; as my business name, so it seems natural for a company named in such a way to be a &amp;quot;we&amp;quot;, saying &amp;quot;me&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; doesn&amp;#039;t feel right to me somehow. Maybe that&amp;#039;s just me though.

Like Ewan and Craig, I chose my current stance based on the intention to grow as needed –; perhaps temporarily in the form of hiring in others, or perhaps permanently in the form of becoming a fully-fledged agency further down the line.

Perhaps I should go back and change that though –; I *can* do everything I advertise, but I guess in the case that I get too busy it won&amp;#039;t hurt me either way to just own up to that fact. If/when Simian Studios does become an agency, then the collective terminology can come out to play again :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-71&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-71&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:17:58+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:17pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Totally agree with you on that. It&amp;#039;s also counter productive. Your biggest advantage is that you&amp;#039;re an individual. I hired Laura Kalbag .. not Laura Kalbag Inc.

If I wanted a company with large overheads and lots of staff then I wouldn&amp;#039;t go to you anyway!!!

A lot of small businesses like dealing with a single person, because they feel they&amp;#039;ll get better service and not just be just another customer in a queue.

Or because they really like something that individual has to offer –; be it their talent, their understanding of business, or their winning personality.

The only exception, I&amp;#039;d say, is if you don&amp;#039;t consider yourself a freelancer and are aiming to build up a company with lots of staff. In that case I&amp;#039;d say it&amp;#039;s forgivable .. just about.

But to be honest, what&amp;#039;s the difference between you pretending you have staff and you pretending you&amp;#039;re an 33 year old bloke with stubble and a bit of a spare tyre?

They&amp;#039;re both dishonest, essentially.  And stupid!

Also, it might surprise a lot of freelancers to know that the biggest problem I have as a company owner is that people buy into me .. and then they are actually concerned that it&amp;#039;s not me doing the work on their site.

I imagine Headscape or Clear Left might have the same issue. You choose them because of Jeremy Keith or Paul Boag .. but that&amp;#039;s not actually who you get.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-82&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/5d4ac85b8b2642debb2d2bccac11167c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Craig Hawker&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-82&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:49:32+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:49pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
            &lt;blockquote cite=&#34;Rich Quick&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But to be honest, what’s the difference between you pretending you have staff and you pretending you’re an 33 year old bloke with stubble and a bit of a spare tyre?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
Hey, I resemble that remark!

Not quite the age, but it’s close enough to hit hard&amp;#8230; ;-)
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-73&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/364e547f7cb705fd81ddc45cf8da09f0?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/364e547f7cb705fd81ddc45cf8da09f0?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.friskdesign.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Matt Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-73&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:20:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:20pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I&amp;#039;m struggling with this very issue right now. I&amp;#039;m a self-employed web designer and currently market myself as &amp;quot;I&amp;quot;. However, I&amp;#039;m rebranding and considering going down the &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; route, for several reasons:

&lt;p&gt;1) I want to get bigger clients, and like it or not, they won&amp;#039;t use individuals for big complex projects

2) I intend to outsource the development side going forward as it&amp;#039;s the part I&amp;#039;m less good at and don&amp;#039;t enjoy

3) I&amp;#039;m considering offering hosting to future clients (I currently don&amp;#039;t) &amp;#8212; and the hosting company offer free white label support to my clients, so they would appear to be my employees

4) &amp;quot;We&amp;quot; gives you the scope to expand in the future. &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; doesn&amp;#039;t. I don&amp;#039;t want to be seen as some cheap freelancer when I&amp;#039;m 50 (assuming I&amp;#039;m still doing this!) &amp;#8212; I want to be seen as a respectable provider and however you cut it, &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; just doesn&amp;#039;t have the same weight in that regard.&lt;/p&gt;
So I&amp;#039;m erring towards &amp;quot;we&amp;quot;, but I do have some reservations over it. Mainly because I agree with your points that being honest and upfront with people about being &amp;quot;I&amp;quot; is admirable, professional and well, just plain good old fashioned personal service.

I&amp;#039;m torn!
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-76&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-76&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:43:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:43pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        1) I want to get bigger clients, and like it or not, they won&amp;rsquo;t use individuals for big complex projects

Nonsense.

They&amp;#039;ll use an individual.  It&amp;#039;s all in your head.

You don&amp;#039;t believe they&amp;#039;d want you .. and so you probably never asked.

It&amp;#039;s like saying &amp;quot;that stunning girl would never go our with an bloke like me.&amp;quot;

Actually, she probably would.  I&amp;#039;ve seen stunning girls with ugly blokes (that aren&amp;#039;t rich) .. it&amp;#039;s probably at least partly down to the fact the ugly bloke she&amp;#039;s with actually asked her out .. and partly down to the confidence he had.

It&amp;#039;s the same with a big company.  If you don&amp;#039;t ask them .. or you don&amp;#039;t put across the plus points of being an individual, sure they won&amp;#039;t hire you.  But that&amp;#039;s your fault for not selling yourself well enough.

Plus points of being an individual:

–; you&amp;#039;re a big client to me.  Not like some big ad agency where you&amp;#039;re just another number to invoice.  I&amp;#039;ll pull out all the stops for you.

–; I&amp;#039;m cheaper, because I have lower overheads

–; You spend less money and get a better developer to boot!  An ad agency charges you &amp;pound;100/hr and in return you get a &amp;pound;10/hr developer. The rest goes on overheads and profit.  I charge you &amp;pound;35/hr and you get a &amp;pound;35/hr developer.  My overheads are lower, and I&amp;#039;m not passing the work on to some junior who&amp;#039;s not that good.

–; I don&amp;#039;t mean to be rude, but I&amp;#039;m better than the agency.  They can&amp;#039;t afford me –; that&amp;#039;s why I&amp;#039;m freelance.  They have to hire somebody cheaper.

Etc etc etc

As for the &amp;quot;for complex projects&amp;quot; bit.  You shouldn&amp;#039;t take on projects that are too complex for you anyway, so if that&amp;#039;s an issue you&amp;#039;re pitching for the wrong work.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-79&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/364e547f7cb705fd81ddc45cf8da09f0?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/364e547f7cb705fd81ddc45cf8da09f0?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.friskdesign.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Matt Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-79&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T12:59:43+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;12:59pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Hi Rich, wise words. You’re right, I need to be more confident. Regarding my point #1, you’ve definitely convinced me to go with “I” :-)

I’d be interested to hear your opinion on using “We” vs. “I” for the other three points I listed.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-4&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-80&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-80&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:14:35+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:14pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        2) I intend to outsource the development side going forward as it’s the part I’m less good at and don’t enjoy.

I do the design.  And when I feel like it, I do the coding too.  But sometimes, I get someone else to do that stuff.  It means I can concentrate on the bits I’m good and it means I can make sure I don’t miss the deadlines I’ve agree with you.

That means you’re happy and I am happy.

3) I’m considering offering hosting to future clients (I currently don’t) — and the hosting company offer free white label support to my clients, so they would appear to be my employees.

I offer hosting to you.

I use a company which can offer you extra support on your hosting, so if you ever have a problem they can help you fix it.

That’s better for you, because it means you can phone them out of hours and –; to be honest –; they deal with hosting all day long so know much more about it than me.

4) “We” gives you the scope to expand in the future. “I” doesn’t. I don’t want to be seen as some cheap freelancer when I’m 50 (assuming I’m still doing this!) — I want to be seen as a respectable provider and however you cut it, “I” just doesn’t have the same weight in that regard.

OK, I think I’ve already said where I stand on “I” vs “we” in terms of credibility.

When you decide to expand, start off by saying “I’ve just take on a guy called Paul (it should always be a Paul BTW!) to help me out with some of the coding work.”

Then, at some stage, once that’s been going on for a while and you decide to take on another person then you can move to being “we”.  Then it’ll be genuine, and will make you and your clients much happier.

1 point –; make sure once you start trading as “we” that you don’t use your own name.  Don’t be Matt Hill Design.  Be Hillybilly Design, or something.  It’ll make it clear to your clients that it’s now a company, not just one person.
        &lt;/div&gt;

        




&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-75&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b1e63769b74cd20b83b121c69ee3da6c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b1e63769b74cd20b83b121c69ee3da6c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.remotesynthesis.com/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Brian Rinaldi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-75&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:38:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:38pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Great post. I actually had a similar revelation a while back related to my work running a conference in Boston ([RIA Unleashed](http://riaunleashed.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)). For the longest time I always said &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; until one day I decided it was just silly since it was only me. Since then, I often have to catch myself reverting to &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; but always go back and correct it. For me, a large part of it is is selfish in that I deserve credit for the work if I do it. We seems to disperse credit to unnamed persons.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-77&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/58d75b3b91b9c58bf2ba4010c50cd57c?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.successfulsites.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Rich Quick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-77&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T13:54:49+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;13:54pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        [http://elliotjaystocks.com/](http://elliotjaystocks.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)

Microsoft, Virgin

  [http://hicksdesign.co.uk/](http://hicksdesign.co.uk/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow)

Opera, Linotype, Firefox

Honestly, it&amp;#039;s a myth and an excuse that big companies won&amp;#039;t work with individuals.

And before you say &amp;quot;but I&amp;#039;m not Elliot Jay Stocks&amp;quot; then that doesn&amp;#039;t change anything!

Who&amp;#039;s fault is that?  If the reason you&amp;#039;re not getting work is because you&amp;#039;re not as good as someone who is then deal with it.  Either get better or accept you&amp;#039;re gonna deal with smaller clients.

But don&amp;#039;t think for a second that not being able to say &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; is the issue.

Big companies don&amp;#039;t want 2 sh*t people over 1 talented one!

Just another point .. do you honestly think big companies don&amp;#039;t check up on you first?
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-83&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cb82ccb3c72846f4e111348b8d5a01e5?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/cb82ccb3c72846f4e111348b8d5a01e5?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://erisds.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;ErisDS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-83&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T14:03:38+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:03pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Seems like you’ve caused a bit of controversy! I totally agree with you though, “me”s who outright just pretend they’re “we”s are twisting at least one fact, so how do you know they’re not twisting others?

It makes me feel really really uncomfortable.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-85&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-85&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T18:09:52+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;18:09pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @roni I&amp;#039;m not at all against outsourcing as a rule, I just think that freelancers should be honest and make their clients aware of the fact they outsource their work.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-86&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/083f7d6bca0497c9a4359c383e75fcb4?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/083f7d6bca0497c9a4359c383e75fcb4?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://armorik.com.ba&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;roni&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-86&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-02T20:50:57+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;20:50pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#039;s take as a parallel construction: You call an architect then building company.

What guarantee do you have that this building company does all the work in-house ? Any ?

They will sub-contract some parts (99% of time): roofing, electricity, water, whatever&amp;#8230;, to some specialist in that field&amp;#8230; It&amp;#039;s not &amp;quot;pure outsourcing&amp;quot; since it local real life&amp;#8230; but same process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#039;s take another example : GM, the car maker&amp;#8230; Do you think they build in house all the parts of your car ? Do you even think what&amp;#039;s sub-contracted is 100%  produced in the US ?

Are you aware of where your car&amp;#039;s brakes are made? lights? seats?gear-box ? and by whom ?

No, because you buy a GM made car. And anyway, you don&amp;#039;t care, bcs you buy a GM car. And GM is responsible for the quality !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#039;t think freelancers should say &amp;quot;btw, I outsource this part&amp;quot; when this does not apply for any other company !

If a client has done basic research he should have a ruff idea of what he is buying and how much it costs. Then to him to ask &amp;quot;Why so cheaper ?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;How come you are expert everywhere?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;       &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-87&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/41548ecfe0816ed4a7c8817472993478?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/41548ecfe0816ed4a7c8817472993478?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;pronebird&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-87&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-10-26T21:18:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;21:18pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I think when individuals are saying &amp;#039;we&amp;#039; it means the one thing only &amp;#8212; they want to seem more than they are.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a whole year since I officially started working as a freelance designer last August. I graduated from uni, had a brief fling with some full-time remote working, had an awkward interview with a recruiter and then decided that I’d rather give it a go by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt pretty ready for freelancing full-time, I’d had a lot of experience on projects whilst I was at university. I knew I could run a project and I knew I could do the work. I’d done a one-day course at uni in freelance accounting and got myself a business account and subscription to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeagentcentral.com/?referrer=32rbfqy3&#34; title=&#34;FreeAgent freelance accounting software&#34;&gt;FreeAgent&lt;/a&gt; so I felt like I could stay on top of the finance side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month started pretty slowly, but that was only the first month. With the help of two lovely people in particular, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/bookmeister&#34; title=&#34;Chris Book on Twitter&#34;&gt;Chris Book&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/simonwheatley&#34; title=&#34;Simon Wheatley on Twitter&#34;&gt;Simon Wheatley&lt;/a&gt;, I got to know a few people and started getting a few projects under my belt. I really couldn’t thank these two guys enough for recommending me to their friends and giving me great opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found that meeting people (I don’t like &lt;em&gt;networking&lt;/em&gt;, it’s too false) is incredibly important when you’re starting out. After that, my network seemed to grow itself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-stats&#34;&gt;The Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe how much I’ve done. I’ve just worked these out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects completed –; 27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current projects –; 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress themes created –; 13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logos designed –; 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone app designs –; 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static website designs –; 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illustration projects –; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website maintenance projects –; 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML e-mail designs –; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-work&#34;&gt;Getting Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the stats above, you can see that I’ve been busy! Thanks to Chris and Simon and a lot of really great clients, I’ve managed to be constantly booked up and busy since last October. I’m now booking up around two/three months in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been difficult. Learning to not stress and cope with a big workload is one of the many things I’ve tried to get my head around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trying-to-learn&#34;&gt;Trying to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily things I’ve already learnt, but things I’m in the process of learning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Scheduling projects is all well and good but &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; stays on schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback isn’t instant, work takes much longer or nowhere near as long as estimated. It’s not a nightmare if I don’t stress about it, but I’m getting good at frequently reorganising and juggling projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Desk space is important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work got miles easier when I had my own working area set up. Matt built me a great custom desk, shelf unit and wall-mounted my second screen. When I’m at my desk, I’m working. The division between working at home and just being at home makes a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2010/08/desk.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter size-full wp-image-201&#34;&gt;
	
		&lt;img src=&#34;https://laurakalbag.com/images/2010/08/desk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;desk area&#34;/&gt;
	
	
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;My desk area (if anybody knows a good way to keep those cables tidy, I’d love to hear it!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Honesty, friendliness and manners go a long way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m horrified by e-mails I receive. I take time to write e-mails, try to be polite and I’m always honest, even if it means admitting I don’t know what I’m doing. I really appreciate it when people are open with me, and it seems to work the other way for me too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Don’t take on too much work. Don’t work when you’re ill. Just don’t overwork at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing kills the desire to work than overworking. At first I was happy to work 10+ hour days. Then I was constantly tired and resentful. Now I take plenty of time to relax and always take time off when I’m ill. I’m so much more productive and enthusiastic for being happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### Clients take you much more seriously when you charge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re working on ‘portfolio projects’ or ‘getting experience’ when you’re starting out it’s very easy to find people who want a lot of your time for nothing. It’s not their fault but these clients will expect you to always do a lot for nothing, and they’ll never understand the value of your work because you’ve placed no value on it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that as soon as I started charging reasonable rates, I got reasonable clients. Not really an issue I had over the last year, but one I had to get over to start working professionally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;### The busier you are, the more they want you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very strange, the busier I get the more clients are willing to wait to work with me. I’m sure it’s that by telling a potential client that you already have clients reassures them that somebody else wants to work with you, so you must be decent enough.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-one-downside&#34;&gt;The One Downside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have work mates. Well, I have one and that’s my lovely man, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MatthewFuller&#34; title=&#34;Matt Fuller on Twitter&#34;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt;. Matt mostly works from home too so it’s lucky we don’t get sick of each other. However, living in Reigate (not exactly the hippest tech town around) and working from home, I miss hanging out with people who have the same work interests as me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to &lt;a href=&#34;http://futureofwebapps.com/&#34; title=&#34;Future of Web Apps conference&#34;&gt;Future of Web Apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://futureofwebdesign.com&#34; title=&#34;Future of Web Design conference&#34;&gt;Future of Web Design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://open-mic.org.uk/&#34; title=&#34;openMIC Open Mobile Innovation Camp&#34;&gt;openMIC&lt;/a&gt; are like going on a social binge, I’m totally exhausted afterwards and probably babble incoherently at everybody when I’m there. Twitter and Skype are both useful in their own ways but it’s not the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hopefully-there-s-more-years-to-come&#34;&gt;Hopefully there’s more years to come&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping this is the beginning of something good. It’d be hard to give up on the luxury of working flexibly from home. I’m making enough to live on and I’m having fun at the same time. I really hope this post might give confidence to some people who are thinking about leaping into freelance. It’s hard work but it’s the best work I’ve ever done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-comments&#34;&gt;13 comments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol class=&#34;commentlist&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-44&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitoaster.com/country-gb/hayles/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;hayles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-44&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T09:15:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:15am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag Congratulations on the first year! The social side is what scares me about homeworking I think!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-40&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;timperrett&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-40&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T09:09:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:09am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag Congratulations on your first year –; many more to come hopefully :-)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-41&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://twitoaster.com/laurakalbag/&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;laurakalbag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-41&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T09:11:05+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:11am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @timperrett thanks, definitely hoping there’s many more to come!
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-42&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576f5c4bb54b8c197174b1a61cd15ed2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576f5c4bb54b8c197174b1a61cd15ed2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Jack Franklin&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-42&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T10:19:59+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:19am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Wow Laura, fantastic post, and congrats on what sounds like a fab year for you! One of the things I’ll be considering after Uni is freelancing so I may well start bombarding you with questions! ;) (4 years until I graduate though)!

As for the social side of things, I’m pretty sure I’ll see you at Bath Camp! That’s my main issue with living in Cornwall&amp;#8230;.the closest any conferences get usually is Bristol, and even that is a 3 hour train ride away.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment even depth-2&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-47&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/55bb2acf65203dbb95c35a83e62e9ae6?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Laura&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-47&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T11:20:46+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;11:20am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Thanks Jack :)

I’m really lucky living where I do, as I’m commutable distance from both London and Brighton but not near enough to either to have a social life there!

Definitely see you at Bath Camp, it’ll be worth the long journey :)
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;children&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt depth-3&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-50&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576f5c4bb54b8c197174b1a61cd15ed2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/576f5c4bb54b8c197174b1a61cd15ed2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Jack Franklin&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-50&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-04T23:18:19+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;23:18pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        I&amp;#039;m off to Bath uni come September 25th so from now on I&amp;#039;m going to make an effort whenever possible to get to as many events as I can, suddenly everywhere is a relatively simple train journey! :)
        &lt;/div&gt;

        



&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-45&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;duncanmacgregor&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-45&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T09:20:50+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:20am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag Congrats! totally agree with you on charge reasonable rates you get reasonable clients. Very true (99.8% of the time! ;)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-46&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;juliancheal&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-46&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T09:31:39+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;09:31am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag ooh nice one Miss Kalbag.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-48&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/d281a23b55db2b3d1d6b0be43791bf6b?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;mastermute&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-48&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-08-31T19:47:08+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;19:47pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        @laurakalbag Great post! Thanks!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-49&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b8b8ba9a1d6e1afcbf07d6e21b6f4615?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/b8b8ba9a1d6e1afcbf07d6e21b6f4615?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://bardowl.com&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Chris Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-49&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-01T10:17:56+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;10:17am&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Congrats Laura

Its very easy to recommend someone when they produce not only quality work but do it in a very professional manner. I think you are unique in being able to be so professional straight out of university.

But thanks for saying thanks :-)

I think your point 3 is the most important of all, we all have different roles to play, commercial, creative, technical and Honesty, friendliness and manners make it so much easier to do business. There is too much politics and backstabbing in big business you are so lucky to have gone straight into working for yourself you never have to see too much of that.

Here’s to many more years to come.

Cheers Chris
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment even thread-odd thread-alt depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-51&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4a4dcd983642d2d826337b4437c685ce?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/4a4dcd983642d2d826337b4437c685ce?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;http://www.damianherrington.co.uk&#39; rel=&#39;external nofollow&#39; class=&#39;url&#39;&gt;Damian Herrington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-51&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2010-09-13T14:50:44+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;14:50pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        Congratulations on your first year! I myself have roughly been freelancing for around a year now too and I can totally relate to your &amp;quot;Trying to learn&amp;quot; section but I suppose thats the fun and beauty of doing what you love to do whilst learning to run your own business.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li class=&#34;comment odd alt thread-even depth-1&#34; id=&#34;li-comment-3212&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;comment-author vcard&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&#39;&#39; src=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6b0724551e23d538184d22018af98cd2?s=72&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&#39; srcset=&#39;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/6b0724551e23d538184d22018af98cd2?s=144&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g 2x&#39; class=&#39;avatar avatar-72 photo&#39; height=&#39;72&#39; width=&#39;72&#39; /&gt;&lt;cite class=&#34;fn&#34;&gt;Denis&lt;/cite&gt;
                &lt;aside class=&#34;comment-meta commentmetadata&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#comment-3212&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2013-11-04T15:02:09+00:00&#34; pubdate class=&#34;published&#34;&gt;
         at &lt;span class=&#34;hours&#34;&gt;15:02pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/aside&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;comment-entry&#34;&gt;
        It’s so hard to get your first clients. I stuck on this.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
