<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clients on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/clients/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/clients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In my latest column on A List Apart, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Heart Internet</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Heart Internet posted an interview with me on their site. They start off saying some very kind things about me, and then it covers accessibility, design, speaking at conferences and a bit of client work. As a bonus, it’s interspersed with photos of me pulling weird faces at conferences (and being business on the phone!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including “ask me anything” in my contract</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</guid>
      <description>At Dare conference in September, I saw a great talk by Kevin Hoffman on “How To Rebuild Amidst Crisis.” I loved this talk, there was so much in it, but one thing struck me as something I could carry over into my work: Kevin said he included “ask any question and I’ll answer it” in his contract.
This might seem like stating the obvious at first, but really there’s nothing obvious to a client who is new to you, and your process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Apart column and first post on Good Designers, Good Clients</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-list-apart-column/</guid>
      <description>This week the first post was published on my A List Apart column. It’s a very exciting thing for me. I’ve been reading A List Apart since I started learning about the web and loads of people I admire have written there.
It’s good fun and a proper challenge having an editor working with me. I’ve already learned a lot, and I hope to be slightly less hopeless at writing clearly as the months go by…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.
“Devices” It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest co-host on Unfinished Business again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.
I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!
 
Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage One of the sponsors this week was Slide + Stage, a full-day intensive masterclass with Aral Balkan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project  It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)
Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was guest co-host on one of my most favourite podcasts, Unfinished Business. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.
We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people  In the previous posts, I mentioned that I was going to explain the details of the project later on. This was because I didn’t want to get bogged down by the details of the brief while I was focusing on finding the right team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Feast Designer’s Quest(ionnaire)</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 08:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-feast-designers-questionnaire/</guid>
      <description>Design Feast have my answers to their Designer’s Quest(ionnaire) on their site.
Scroll past the scarily large photo of me quickly… their questions prompted me to think about some interesting points, especially challenges for designers:
 What are some of the challenges you encounter as a designer and how do you deal with them?
I think the greatest challenge a designer comes across is their own ego. It’s in our nature, as those that deal in creativity, we have egos that allow us to consider our work good enough to share, and good enough for clients to pay us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: finding the right people</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 10:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>We’ve got a project! I’ll elaborate on the details of the project in a future post, but the importance of having a project was that it’s allowed me to choose the designers/developers who could get something out of being mentees. I didn’t want to do this before securing the right project as I needed to know what I was looking for in a mentee.
Finding the right mentee for the job This has been one of the hardest decisions I’ve ever had to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the right project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</guid>
      <description>This post is an update on my mentoring project idea.
Finding the right project If you follow me on Twitter, you might have seen that I’m now looking for a different project to work on. Whilst the previous project I had in mind would have been great fun, the client had a very tight deadline. I didn’t want to push that pressure on to students and freelancers who are likely to have other work they need to do in order to pass their studies or pay the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grid Frameworks and why I’m not keen on them…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 19:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/grid-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a post for 12 Devs of Xmas on Grid Frameworks.
After spending months whining about grid frameworks, 960.gs and Bootstrap, I’ve finally backed up my tweet-sized complaints with some context and examples.
I knew it would be contentious and that some people would feel antagonised by my saying that developers who don’t consider accessibility shouldn’t be on the web. And possibly also that I suggest some developers lazily fail to customise frameworks to appropriately suit their needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insites Tour Brighton</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/insites-tour-brighton/</guid>
      <description>Insites is a mini tour of four cities in the UK where Keir Whitaker and Elliot Jay Stocks present discussions with well-known people from the web/tech industry. I was lucky enough to go to the first evening in Brighton on Monday where Aral Balkan, Sarah Parmenter and Jeremy Keith were the guests.
The Format The format of the evening was something unfamiliar to most of us. Each guest was interviewed by either Keir or Elliot and then there were questions from the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design work is 50% visual, 50% justification</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-is-50percent-visual-50percent-justification-2/</guid>
      <description>After I finished my last post about Design Tips for Developers, it really struck me how much I wrote to justify my design. I wasn’t just writing tips saying “*do this, it’s good*“, “*don’t do this, it’s bad.*” I put time and effort into explaining why I made these decisions and why I didn’t do it another way.
When I send a design to a client via e-mail, I usually spend around 45 minutes –; 1 hour writing an accompanying ‘justification’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on a design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</guid>
      <description>After discussing Dribbble and Forrst, and my latest post that looked at criticism in design, I’ve been thinking a lot more about how feedback features in my design process.
Getting stuck When I used to get stuck on a design, from ‘creative block’ or a complete lack of inspiration, I would frantically brainstorm, then browse inspiration sites, then ask the opinions of other designers. Usually the feedback from other designers would form the basis of my amendments, I’d gain inspiration from those changes and continue work from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me vs We</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 10:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</guid>
      <description>There’s something that’s been niggling at me for ages. The way people act as if they’re a multi-person company when they’re really just one individual. This whole ‘we’ syndrome.
 We have a great new client now working with us at Just Little Old Me Ltd.
 Sometimes it makes me giggle when I know somebody is an individual ‘me’ and they’re saying ‘we’ as if they’re some kind of medieval queen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/year-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a whole year since I officially started working as a freelance designer last August. I graduated from uni, had a brief fling with some full-time remote working, had an awkward interview with a recruiter and then decided that I’d rather give it a go by myself.
Getting Started I felt pretty ready for freelancing full-time, I’d had a lot of experience on projects whilst I was at university.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
