<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 12:58:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Assistants, Facebook Quizzes, And Fake News! You Won’t Believe What Happens Next</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/you-wont-believe-what-happens-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 12:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/you-wont-believe-what-happens-next/</guid>
      <description>This is the talk I gave at DIBI Conference in Edinburgh in March 2017. Many people asked me for my slides, but I wanted to include them in context, with accessible links. This is roughly how it went:
 
Performance! Nowadays performance seems to be the hot topic of the web industry. So let’s have a look at how we might improve the speed of a web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 21st March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-21st-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a busy few weeks.
Ethical Design Manifesto refresh Last week we launched a refresh of the Ethical Design Manifesto, along with a video. As it was a short-ish video, I felt like I had no excuse but to do the captioning for it too. I couldn’t get Subtitle Horse (my usual favourite web software) working with the video, so I ended up using Jubler instead.
It took a while to get my head around how to use the interface, but I found using the audio track from the video very useful, as I could sync the subtitles to the wave forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 418:conf web meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-418-conf-web-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the very first 418:conf web meetup on 16th June 2015 in Nutfield (near Redhill) in Surrey. It’s exciting for me because it’s near where I used to live, and it’s a cool new meetup with a lot of potential.
If you’re local, you should get your ticket now. They’re free!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at the Sherpa Summit</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-sherpa-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 10:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-sherpa-summit/</guid>
      <description>Last October, Web Standards Sherpa published my mini series on Getting Started With Sass. It was a whole new experience as I’d never written a technical tutorial as in-depth as this, let alone doing so with a proper editor and technical editor. Web Standards Sherpa is like that; all about the quality. So it was sad to hear about Sherpa closing its doors this year. However, in order to keep the site and all its wonderful resources online forever, Web Standards Sherpa is hosting an online conference on the 23rd April, and I’m speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Web Day at Bath Digital Festival</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-web-day-at-bath-digital-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 14:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-web-day-at-bath-digital-festival/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at Web Day at Bath Digital Festival on the 28th of October. Bath is great, I went to university there, and it’s full of lovely people. I’m looking forward to going back and giving a talk about accessibility. Tickets are a very reasonable £15, and it looks like it’ll be a very interesting day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a diverse speaker lineup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/building-a-diverse-speaker-lineup/</guid>
      <description>This post is so good, and so incredibly valuable, that it’s deserving of more than just a passing tweet. Julie Pagano has written about ‘Building a Diverse Speaker Lineup.’ This should be the go-to post for conference organisers, and it should be read as soon as you’re even thinking about organising an event.
Julie’s post doesn’t just explain why you want a diverse lineup (also worth reading on this topic: Aral’s post, On design and diversity), but also how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business 81 and 82</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 18:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-81-and-82/</guid>
      <description>I was so busy last week that I forgot to post about Unfinished Business episode 81: Do you have a dinosaur onesie? This week, Ashley and I recorded episode 82: Love a good pep talk.
It’s been a fun few weeks. It’s been interesting how a lot of people have said that Ashley and I focused more on business-related topics than Andy’s recent episodes. That may well be the case, but it wasn’t really intentional, or because we think the podcast should be more business-focused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discount code for WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/discount-code-for-wxg-2014/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen that I’m speaking at WXG in Guildford in September. If you didn’t already get a ticket, you might want to use my discount code of kalbagWXG to get £10 off the (already very affordable £99) ticket price.
There’s some great speakers in the lineup, and it’s sure to be a fun day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with public speaking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/how-to-get-started-with-public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/how-to-get-started-with-public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the wonderful Ashley Baxter asked me about how I got into public speaking. Ashley asked a few cool people, and published their public speaking stories on the Insurance By Jack blog.
By the way, if you want business insurance, you really should get a quote from Insurance By Jack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at KiwiParty in Strasbourg</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-kiwiparty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 07:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-kiwiparty/</guid>
      <description>On the 13th of June, I’m speaking at KiwiParty in Strasbourg. I’ll be speaking about web accessibility.
It’ll be my first conference in France and I’ll be trying to remember my French from AS Level ten years ago! I won’t be giving my talk in my terrible French, but if you’re coming along, please find me and test my conversational French. Especially if you want a good laugh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #61</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. I had a lovely time chatting to Andy about speaking at conferences, working for free and I even managed to squeeze in a rant about accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 10:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-wxg-2014-in-guildford/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at WXG 2014 in Guildford in September. This is exciting for me because I attended the first ever WXG a couple of years ago, and it’s about as local as a conference is going to get to my hometown, Reigate.
The tickets are a bargain at just £69 for early birds, and there’s already a great lineup with still more to be announced…
I’m going to talk about how we design the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Design &#43; Banter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 12:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-design-and-banter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at Design + Banter on Monday in London. It’s already sold out, but there’s a waiting list available for the free tickets.
Nicklas Persson and Cole Peters are also speaking so I’m really chuffed to be part of a great lineup!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Interlink conference in Toronto</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 11:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-interlink-conference-in-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 This is very very exciting. In June, I’m going to speak at Interlink conference in Toronto, Canada. The line-up is incredible, and I can’t believe I’m a part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Heart Internet</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-with-heart-internet/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Heart Internet posted an interview with me on their site. They start off saying some very kind things about me, and then it covers accessibility, design, speaking at conferences and a bit of client work. As a bonus, it’s interspersed with photos of me pulling weird faces at conferences (and being business on the phone!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at 12 Devs of Winter</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-12-devs-of-winter/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at 12 Devs of Winter on the 22nd January in Shoreditch. Because I’ve clearly lost my mind, I’m going to be doing another new talk. This time on ‘Freelancing for the reluctant businessperson.’ I’m that reluctant businessperson, and I’m hoping to share some silly stories about all the daft things I’ve done and some of the things that have worked out just fine.
For once, I’m ahead of the schedule, and tickets will be released this Wednesday 8th January at 10am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MKGN this Thursday</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 10:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mkgn/</guid>
      <description>This Thursday I’m speaking at Milton Keynes Geek Night. Tickets sold out terrifyingly quickly, but I put that down to MKGN always being a great event.
I’m going to talk about self-discipline, it’s a new talk and so that makes me even more nervous than usual &#34; /</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-mobx-conference-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Next Friday I’m speaking at MobX Conference in Berlin about designing for accessibility, covering problems that affect many different types of screens and devices. It will be my first time in Germany, so I’m very excited!
 
One comment Anna at 10:34am
  Hello there, I very much enjoyed your talk about accessibility at the mobXconference last friday. Is there any chance you can put your slides online?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Untangle the Web</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 11:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-untangle-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Nothing quite like a last-minute post… Tonight I’m speaking at Untangle the Web at Google Campus in London. I’m doing a talk on Design Theory for the Web where I do a whistle-stop tour through designing with typography, grids and colour on the web.
I also have a stinking cold so I’m going to be taking industrial quantities of Red Bull and a quarantine zone with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at LXJS in Portugal</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 09:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-lxjs-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>I’m really looking forward to October, where I get to return to Portugal to speak at LXJS in Lisbon.
One of the reasons I jumped at the chance to speak at LXJS was their fantastic Code of Conduct. After hearing some horror stories from other women speakers, I wish more conferences had this sort of approach. It’s friendly, not strict, and lets everybody know where they stand.
The tickets are incredibly reasonable for a two-day event, and it looks like Lisbon is well-worth a holiday so a conference there is a bonus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#define 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/define-2013/</guid>
      <description>Next Saturday I’m speaking at #define 2013, a “diversity in computing festival” for 11-13 year old students who wouldn’t usually consider careers in computing.
It’s an event aimed at improving diversity in computing and I’m really proud to be speaking. I’m going to talk about a day in the life of a web designer/developer in the hope that I can share the variety involved in this kind of work and how rewarding and fun this job can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sass For Designers at CSS Summit 2013</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/css-summit-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 09:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/css-summit-2013/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at CSS Summit 2013 about Sass For Designers. CSS Summit is a great online conference, meaning you can attend from anywhere in the world (hooray!)
There’s a huge amount of expert speakers across three days, with a day each dedicated to CSS3 Training, Advanced CSS and Preprocessors. I’m on the third day, covering the basics of Sass with ‘Sass for Designers’. The other talks on that day will cover Sass in more depth, with case studies and more advanced techniques, so I’m hoping to provide a useful introduction for those of us who are less familiar with programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to speak</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year ago, I was in a country I’d never visited, about to give two talks I’d never given before to two large, paying audiences in the space of three days at Future Insights Live. I had only given a couple of talks to small audiences before. It was one of the scariest things I’d ever done.
A helping hand I’d seen Aral Balkan speak a few times before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Breaking Borders</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-breaking-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-breaking-borders/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking at Breaking Borders. Breaking Borders is a brand new, totally free, bi-monthly event in Reading organised by my good friend, Ben MacGowan.
The inaugural Breaking Borders event will have the lovely Steve Workman speaking about Front-end web architectures that won’t bite you (in the ass) and me speaking about design systems.
If you’re in the area, I really recommend you join us. If Ben’s events are anything like his front-end development skills, it’s going to be great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladies In Tech</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/ladies-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, Jeremy Keith introduced me to ladiesintech.com, suggesting that it might be something that’d interest me. After having a chat with the lovely Jenn Lukas over email, I had a story that I wanted to share about my adventures in speaking, and Jenn has now helped me share it on the site.
This was the first time I’ve ever had anybody edit my writing. I’ve had other people proof-read and check my writing for mistakes, but never changing that much (despite often needing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Wing podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 09:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was a guest on Tim Smith‘s The East Wing podcast. It was a pre-recorded conversation and it was great fun. You can listen to it on the East Wing website, and it’ll be up on iTunes soon.
We discussed how I got started in the industry (really sorry traditional Graphic Design people, I may have generalised a bit…), speaking at conferences, women in the industry and mentoring.
As I said last night on Twitter, Tim Smith is such a great guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and conferences</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 21:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/women-and-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I used to not understand the fuss around women at conferences, I thought that we should all just carry on with what we were doing well already and not get caught up in needless controversy. I even wrote a blog post saying exactly that a couple of years ago. I’d never experienced (to my knowledge) any difficulties because I was a woman.
A bit uncomfortable But then I started hearing more about/was exposed to women who did have bad experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
