<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/feedback/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feedback on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/feedback/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’m doing now and why</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</guid>
      <description>I’d been a freelance web designer/developer full-time, working for myself, for six years. I love working with clients, and working with small businesses is a very sustainable business model. You can make a big difference to a small business. You can get paid fairly well. And you can forge long-term relationships with people whose businesses you really care about. I always said I’d never give it up, unless it was for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest co-host on Unfinished Business again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.
I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!
 
Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage One of the sponsors this week was Slide + Stage, a full-day intensive masterclass with Aral Balkan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 10:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was guest co-host on one of my most favourite podcasts, Unfinished Business. It was great to ramble and rant with Andy for 90 minutes as it’s not often I get to chat for so long to another designer whose main focus is client work.
We talked about smoking chimps, mentoring and how we can try to help newcomers in the community, tools and techniques for dealing with client feedback, egos and constructive criticism among many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We read with our own contexts</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 14:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/we-read-with-our-own-contexts/</guid>
      <description>Oh Twitter. Yesterday was another day where I accidentally incited another riot with a poorly-worded tweet. Nobody is perfect, but it’s starting to happen with alarming frequency, and I wanted to understand why I keep doing this.
The ever-present ego We read everything through our own ego filter. It’s how we apply new knowledge to our own situations. Whenever we read a tweet, blog post, article, book, watch a TV show, a film, a play, we take in what we’re reading and hearing and apply it to ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critiques, giving and receiving useful feedback</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Funnily enough, a couple of days before Mark Boulton said to critique design effectively.&amp;quot; says Mark Boulton on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) and wrote his piece on design critiques, I’d been thinking about that same topic. I’ve been struggling through an iPhone app icon design, and had asked Twitter for help. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an app icon design that needs some criticism as I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of it. Anyone free to give me some time via email today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck on a design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/stuck-on-a-design/</guid>
      <description>After discussing Dribbble and Forrst, and my latest post that looked at criticism in design, I’ve been thinking a lot more about how feedback features in my design process.
Getting stuck When I used to get stuck on a design, from ‘creative block’ or a complete lack of inspiration, I would frantically brainstorm, then browse inspiration sites, then ask the opinions of other designers. Usually the feedback from other designers would form the basis of my amendments, I’d gain inspiration from those changes and continue work from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dribbble and Forrst for feedback on a client project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 20:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I created a quickie logo for Andy Warburton’s mobile stock photography service Stockyoo. Andy was really keen on the idea of using Forrst and Dribbble for posting the progress of the project to get the opinions of potential users of a stock photography service and do some early promo for Stockyoo itself.
Dribbble and Forrst Dribbble and Forrst are part of a new wave of sites aimed at (mostly web) designers and developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>