<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freelancing on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/categories/freelancing/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/categories/freelancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’m doing now and why</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/what-im-doing-now-and-why/</guid>
      <description>I’d been a freelance web designer/developer full-time, working for myself, for six years. I love working with clients, and working with small businesses is a very sustainable business model. You can make a big difference to a small business. You can get paid fairly well. And you can forge long-term relationships with people whose businesses you really care about. I always said I’d never give it up, unless it was for something I really believed in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Stuff on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 13:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/breaking-stuff-on-a-list-apart-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week my latest column, Breaking Stuff, was published on A List Apart. I’m in a strange transitional period, moving from client work to fulltime at ind.ie, so I think I’ll be writing more about situations like these as time goes on.
I’ve also finally updated that terrible avatar to something much better. I look uncharacteristically pale, but at least I’m normal colours! (Unlike the last terrible photo I’d used.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And I accidentally became a control freak…</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/junes-pastry-box-thought-on-being-a-control-freak/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my post yesterday about working with Indie Phone for 50% of my time, my thought on the Pastry Box today is about how I accidentally became a control freak. It’s hard to admit the flaws you find in yourself, but I’m so determined to do a good job that I think it’s better to find those flaws and try to fix them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming part of Indie Phone</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/indie-phone/</guid>
      <description>There’s some big changes around here. As of Monday, I am now working with Indie Phone for 50% of my working time.
What is Indie Phone? Indie Phone is a huge, and very ambitious, project. We’re building a smart phone that allows you to own your own data. The majority of companies on the web have a simple, and potentially dangerous, business model. These companies give you services for free, and sell your data on to third parties to make their money (think Google, Facebook, Twitter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and My Big Fat Ego on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-and-my-big-fat-ego-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Today my column on Me and My Big Fat Ego was published on A List Apart. It’s not that I’d say I have a huge ego, but it’s definitely something that’s easily bruised when I feel like things aren’t going my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #61</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 10:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-61/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I was a guest on the Unfinished Business podcast again. I had a lovely time chatting to Andy about speaking at conferences, working for free and I even managed to squeeze in a rant about accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delivery Logistics on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/delivery-logistics-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing wrong with sending a client a rough sketch if that’s all that’s needed to communicate your idea. In my latest column on A List Apart, I’ve written about deliverables and why what the client expects isn’t always the right thing to do…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfinished Business #54</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 18:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/unfinished-business-54/</guid>
      <description>The latest Unfinished Business podcast has just been published, and I’m on it again! I had a lovely time talking to Andy about scheduling projects, invoicing, rates and people who don’t understand copyright.
A very big thank you to my friend Jo who let me take over her internet and bedroom for the recording, as our internet is still terrible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Including “ask me anything” in my contract</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 10:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/including-ask-me-anything-in-my-contract/</guid>
      <description>At Dare conference in September, I saw a great talk by Kevin Hoffman on “How To Rebuild Amidst Crisis.” I loved this talk, there was so much in it, but one thing struck me as something I could carry over into my work: Kevin said he included “ask any question and I’ll answer it” in his contract.
This might seem like stating the obvious at first, but really there’s nothing obvious to a client who is new to you, and your process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Learning People</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-by-the-learning-people/</guid>
      <description>The Learning People have posted an interview they did with me about women in the technology sector, working for myself, and what inspires me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open for Business on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 14:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/open-for-business/</guid>
      <description>My second column for A List Apart, “Open for Business,” is now up. I wrote Open for Business as a follow-up to my Dare conference talk about honesty. It’s not the same as the full talk (and has been edited into a far better shape by Rose Weisburd) but is the essence of why I feel that being open works for my business.
 
One comment Daniel Dogeanu at 18:16pm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest on Happy Monday Podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-on-happy-monday-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest for today’s Happy Monday podcast. It was great fun chatting with Josh and Sarah about design, client work and inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast interview with Jonathan Kahn</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 08:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/podcast-interview-with-jonathan-kahn/</guid>
      <description>Ahead of speaking at Dare conference this September, I was interviewed by Jonathan Kahn, one of Dare’s organisers, about being honest, client relationships and mentoring in the web industry.
It was lovely chatting to Jonathan, and his podcast also has a proper transcript if you’re more of a reading person than a listening person :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview in Allan McAvoy’s Freelancers series</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-in-freelancers-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 09:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interview-in-freelancers-series/</guid>
      <description>Last week Allan McAvoy posted up the interview he did with me as part of his Freelancers series. Some of the questions are fairly standard, but there’s also some unusual ones like “favourite colour for design” and “typical day in the life…”
 
## One comment  David Griffiths at 23:44pm
  “transparentize” –; I love you –; thought I was stuck with rgba too! And if only I lived on the South Coast my 2 labs would love a walk in your park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest co-host on Unfinished Business II</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 09:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/guest-co-host-on-unfinished-business-ii/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday I was a guest co-host on Unfinished Business again. It was great fun, Andy and I spoke about clients, how location affects our businesses, how to find good subcontractors and Star Trek.
I’m a massive fan of Unfinished Business and listen to every episode so it was a real treat to go back again. Thank you for inviting me, Andy!
 
Oh, and one more thing: Slide + Stage One of the sponsors this week was Slide + Stage, a full-day intensive masterclass with Aral Balkan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-contract-and-kicking-off/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project  It’s been far too long since I wrote about the mentoring project. I’ve been incredibly busy and really needed to dedicate more time to make it a success (more about that in another post!)
Last time I wrote about the project, we had just started to get the contract sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed on The Industry</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-on-the-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 07:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/interviewed-on-the-industry/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a chat with the lovely Conor O’Driscoll and last night he published the interview on The Industry. We talking about design work, education and what I define as success, among other things.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnout</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 20:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/burnout/</guid>
      <description>Burnout. Spending hours just staring into space when you’re supposed to be doing work, when you want to be doing work. Feeling foggy-headed and grey the whole time when you usually feel eager and excitable. Menial tasks are just about manageable, but anything requiring careful consideration or creative thinking feels impossible. I sleep but I still feel tired.
I’m burned out. The last couple of months have really taken their toll.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-project/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people  In the previous posts, I mentioned that I was going to explain the details of the project later on. This was because I didn’t want to get bogged down by the details of the brief while I was focusing on finding the right team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing to display podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 17:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/nothing-to-display-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had a lovely chat with El for her Nothing To Display podcast. We talked about technology and how people get started with technology, accessibility, mentoring and dystopian futures! It was a real treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love Unfinished Business</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/why-i-love-unfinished-business/</guid>
      <description>I know, this is a funny topic on which to base a blog post but I love the Unfinished Business podcast, and I’d like to elaborate why in something more than a few fawning tweets.
Business, but not suits Business doesn’t feel like the right word to describe what I do. It’s a hobby that makes me enough money to support myself. The word ‘business’ conjures up images of suits, handshakes and networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: finding the right people</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 10:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-finding-the-right-people/</guid>
      <description>We’ve got a project! I’ll elaborate on the details of the project in a future post, but the importance of having a project was that it’s allowed me to choose the designers/developers who could get something out of being mentees. I didn’t want to do this before securing the right project as I needed to know what I was looking for in a mentee.
Finding the right mentee for the job This has been one of the hardest decisions I’ve ever had to make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Wing podcast</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 09:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-east-wing-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was a guest on Tim Smith‘s The East Wing podcast. It was a pre-recorded conversation and it was great fun. You can listen to it on the East Wing website, and it’ll be up on iTunes soon.
We discussed how I got started in the industry (really sorry traditional Graphic Design people, I may have generalised a bit…), speaking at conferences, women in the industry and mentoring.
As I said last night on Twitter, Tim Smith is such a great guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the right project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 15:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-right-project/</guid>
      <description>This post is an update on my mentoring project idea.
Finding the right project If you follow me on Twitter, you might have seen that I’m now looking for a different project to work on. Whilst the previous project I had in mind would have been great fun, the client had a very tight deadline. I didn’t want to push that pressure on to students and freelancers who are likely to have other work they need to do in order to pass their studies or pay the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring a project: the idea</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-a-project-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, a potential project turned up in my inbox. An old school friend wants a website, needs it soon and doesn’t have a huge budget.
Me and freelancing I’m lucky, I get offered a lot of projects, and usually I don’t have any availability for a few months. Little projects like this generally can’t pay the bills for me. It’s a lot of time (particularly admin) for a fairly small return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sharers on The Branch</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/the-sharers-on-the-branch/</guid>
      <description>I’ve written a post over on The Branch.
 James Dinsdale emailed me about a new project he was starting out, called The Branch, a site collecting posts about what inspires people. I love these kinds of posts, so I was really keen to be involved.
As a designer, inspiration is a much-discussed topic. Unfortunately, this ‘inspiration’ is often described as particular styles of design and the work of individual designers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six months of the Fitbit (and the new Fitbit Aria)</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/six-months-of-the-fitbit-and-the-new-fitbit-aria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 16:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/six-months-of-the-fitbit-and-the-new-fitbit-aria/</guid>
      <description>Skip to the main review!
The backstory I’m a fit and healthy person. Probably not your typical work-from-home desk-based screen-faced designer. I go to the gym 4 to 6 times a week, walk my dog every day, I eat fairly healthily and I’m a good weight.
I wasn’t always though. I’m not pretending I was massively fat, but after leaving university three years ago, I’d got some really bad habits (two cans of Relentless a day, anyone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me vs We</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 10:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/me-vs-we/</guid>
      <description>There’s something that’s been niggling at me for ages. The way people act as if they’re a multi-person company when they’re really just one individual. This whole ‘we’ syndrome.
 We have a great new client now working with us at Just Little Old Me Ltd.
 Sometimes it makes me giggle when I know somebody is an individual ‘me’ and they’re saying ‘we’ as if they’re some kind of medieval queen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
