<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Critiques on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/critiques/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Critiques on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/critiques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critiques, giving and receiving useful feedback</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 09:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/critiques-giving-and-receiving-useful-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Funnily enough, a couple of days before Mark Boulton said to critique design effectively.&amp;quot; says Mark Boulton on Twitter&amp;rdquo;) and wrote his piece on design critiques, I’d been thinking about that same topic. I’ve been struggling through an iPhone app icon design, and had asked Twitter for help. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an app icon design that needs some criticism as I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of it. Anyone free to give me some time via email today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good old designer snobbery is alive and kicking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</guid>
      <description>There’s one thing that I hate about being a designer and that’s the snobbery. Most, if not all, designers are a little bit guilty of looking down on other people’s work. Comments such as “Pah! They used Comic Sans” or “Ergh! Don’t they know reflections are so out of date now?”
These are comments I’m 100% guilty of saying, but I think the problem is the outlet. If it’s a quick chatter between friends then there’s not much lost except making yourself look like a bit of an arse, but start broadcasting these harsh judgements to the world and you’ll rapidly give the impression of a big ego, huge mouth and tiny brain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>