<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talk on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 18:06:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at DotYork</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dotyork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dotyork/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at DotYork conference in York on the 1st of May. My friend Jonic is one of the organisers, and with the thought and love that they’re putting into the event, it’s got to be fantastic.
It’ll be my first time in York, so I’m looking forward to seeing the sights and feeling incredibly Southern. You should join me! Early bird tickets are coming out soon, so why not go over to the DotYork website and sign up to be the first to hear when tickets are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Secret is Honesty talk video</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 18:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/my-secret-is-honesty-talk-video/</guid>
      <description>The lovely people at Dare conference have released the video of my talk, My Secret is Honesty. It’s pretty much a longer, talk-version of my latest column on A List Apart, “Open for Business.”
I’m not going to embed it here, because I want you to go to the website to watch it. The reason is that there’s loads of great talks on there, and in order to help support Dare conference for next year, they’re taking donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at Dare conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 16:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-dare-conference/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking as a ‘Breakout’ speaker at Dare conference in September. As soon as I saw the rumblings of this conference, I knew it was an event I wanted to attend. It’s focusing on risk, vulnerability, communication and trying to make the world a better place.
Then I realised that I actually had an idea for a talk that could work for this event. I’d wanted to talk about my openness and honesty online, and how it affects my business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to speak</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/learning-to-speak/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year ago, I was in a country I’d never visited, about to give two talks I’d never given before to two large, paying audiences in the space of three days at Future Insights Live. I had only given a couple of talks to small audiences before. It was one of the scariest things I’d ever done.
A helping hand I’d seen Aral Balkan speak a few times before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live-designing WordPress Admin Icons</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I wrotea post about how I was going to do a talk at WordPress London where I would try to design a WordPress admin icon live. Well, I did it, and it didn’t go too badly. In fact, I was very lucky as the first suggestion for what I should design was a calendar icon. That’s mostly squares, so not too tricky!
  The final calendar icons (as designed quickly in 30 minutes or so)   The WordPress London guys kindly filmed my talk and I’ve included it below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips For Developers</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-tips-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>This little post is based around the talk I gave at Bathcamp. Rich Quick came up with the great idea that, whilst Bathcamp attendees are mostly developers, a talk on design for developers was probably appropriate.
And you might have seen on my post from last week, I was looking for a case study to use in my talk. As happens with everything, I just didn’t have time to include the case study in the talk, so I thought I would blog it here as a follow-up from Bathcamp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
