<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at border:none</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-border-none/</guid>
      <description>Next month I’m speaking and running a “creator unit” at border:none in Nuremberg. This is incredibly exciting as it’s an event focused around the decentralisation of the web, a topic that I care about a great deal. I’ll be talking about using considerate design and great user experiences to create genuine alternatives to the products that make money from exploiting their users’ data.
It’s also an all-new topic for me to share with other people, so I can’t wait!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web workshop at Interlink conference</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop-at-interlink-conference/</guid>
      <description>Sadly, Interlink conference has been cancelled. I’m gutted that I won’t be visiting Canada this year, but I totally understand how difficult it is to run a conference, especially if you’re trying to put on the best possible event for your attendees and speakers.
 I’m running my ‘Design theory for the web’ workshop at Interlink conference in Canada on the 18th of June.
 
It’s a one day workshop and I’ve written a mega description below for anyone wanting to know more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design theory for the web, a workshop</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/design-theory-for-the-web-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a slightly scary thing: I’m doing my first solo workshop on the 11th October 2013 in Barnsley.
I often get asked about the best way to “learn design”, and I usually say that you learn by doing and you learn by watching how others do it. In this workshop, I want to give new designers, developers, and anybody else wanting to learn how to design for the web, a good foundation with five primers, a bit of doing and a bit of watching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CreativeJS for non-coders workshop with Seb Lee-Delisle</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/creativejs-for-non-coders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 13:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/creativejs-for-non-coders/</guid>
      <description>Programming block I’m a bit scared of JavaScript. Since I started learning front-end development about seven years ago, I’ve pretty much stayed away from it. That aside from some pretty dodgy jQuery where I can usually bodge something together but would never rely on it. I’ve always said it’s because I wanted to be really really good at HTML first, and then CSS and then JavaScript, but I somehow always stopped short of actually learning JavaScript properly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>