<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Arts Magazine on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/digital-arts-magazine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Arts Magazine on Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 16:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/digital-arts-magazine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 16:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-web-fonts-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>Another fab and in-depth article from Craig Grannell on Digital Arts, this time on Web fonts: what designers need to know in 2015. Craig asked a load of smart designers (and me) about web fonts, web font services, and how to choose web fonts.
 
My full answers to Craig’s original questions are below:
What do you consider the current best options for working with web fonts? I’m forever changing my mind, but I tend to prefer to host fonts on the site itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: Designing for the unknown</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-designing-for-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Craig Grannell asked me some questions about designing for the unknown. The result was a really fantastic article called Designing for the unknown: how to design templates and frameworks, and has contributions from some really smart people.
The title image is from my writeup of the Default Perch Theme project I did with Perch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Arts: The future of web design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 13:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/digital-arts-the-future-of-web-design/</guid>
      <description>Over the next few days I’m catching up on things I failed to share in recent months. It’s been a very busy few months, but I still like to have a record of what I did and where I’ve been!
In April, I spoke to Neil Bennett about the future of web design, and the challenges we face. There were some good questions, and it’s interesting to see the answers of difference people from different areas side-by-side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>