<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like It on A List Apart</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/i-dont-like-it-on-a-list-apart/</guid>
      <description>Heh. That’s a misleading title! I’ve been on holiday, so I’m late to posting this update. Just over a week ago, my most recent column, I Don’t Like It, was posted on A List Apart. I’d heard some designers discussing their clients in less-than-favourable terms. This kind of behaviour makes me cross. It’s the Clients From Hell attitude that poor communication is a client’s fault, when it’s more often a designer’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser windows and responsive language</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 18:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/browser-windows/</guid>
      <description>In the same way that we continually evolve the processes we use when working with clients, I’ve now found myself evolving and refining the language I use with clients when discussing responsive web design.
“Devices” It started out with talking about devices. “This design will use X on a mobile phone, Y on a tablet and Z on a desktop computer.” Then it seemed that, as a web community, we realised that the lines between these devices were fairly blurry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentoring: the evaluation</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/mentoring-the-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Previous posts on the mentoring project:
 Mentoring a project: the idea Mentoring a project: the right project Mentoring a project: finding the right people Mentoring a project: the project Mentoring a project: contract and kicking off  It’s been four months since we started the mentoring project and now it’s drawing to a close.
It’s been very different from what I expected, I didn’t realise I’d learn so much just through explaining to Sibylle, Yago and Phil what I do and why I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive Day Out</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 22:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/responsive-day-out/</guid>
      <description>A month ago I spoke at Responsive Day Out, an “affordable, enjoyable gathering of UK designers and developers sharing their workflow strategies, techniques, and experiences with responsive web design.” As I said to Jeremy Keith when he first asked me if I wanted to do it, this would be a day I couldn’t possibly miss, regardless of speaking. It very much lived up to my expectations.
After a whole month of mulling over the talks in my head, and chatting to other people who were there or who have listened to the talks since (you can listen to them here, or watch them on BeSquare), I’ve joined a lot of dots in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day Two</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-two/</guid>
      <description>Day Two Ethan Marcotte –; Responsive Web Design Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Femi T Adesina –; Enhancing your Creativity I mis-hastagged the first tweet!
Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
My thoughts at this point: Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Josh Clark –; Buttons Are a Hack: The New Rules of Designing for Touch continued&amp;#8230; Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Adventures 2011</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/new-adventures-2011/</guid>
      <description>Conferences are my social life As I go to more conferences, I meet more lovely people and get to see friends I’d only ever talk to on Twitter otherwise. In the last two years, I’ve been to about three a year and it feels about the right amount that you rarely see the same talk twice and it’s not just the same topics going round.
Again, I met loads of great people at New Adventures, but unfortunately missed more people than I meant to catch up with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
