<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logo Design on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/logo-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 14:55:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/logo-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary, 29th March 2016</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-29th-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/diary-29th-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Back in the office today and we’re working hard and getting a lot done. We can’t wait to share what we’re working on with you all. (Soon, I promise!)
Friday and today, I’ve been getting our Labs and source.ind.ie in tip-top shape. Now with our own logo in the corner, it feels more like home, and Aral has added single sign-on so you can sign up with your GitHub account, as well as adding some new copy on the source homepage to explain a little more about what is housed on source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look inside a designer’s sketchbook</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/a-look-inside-a-designers-sketchbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 10:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/a-look-inside-a-designers-sketchbook/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago, Ian from logogeek.co.uk, asked if I’d share some of my sketchbook pages on his site. Ian wanted to emphasise the rough, imperfect nature of the way we plan logo designs, and show real work done by real people.
Last week, Ian added some pages from my sketchbook to his post, “A look inside a designers sketchbook”. He included some of my sketches from the Indie Phone and Turbine projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good old designer snobbery is alive and kicking</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 10:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/good-old-designer-snobbery-is-live-and-kicking/</guid>
      <description>There’s one thing that I hate about being a designer and that’s the snobbery. Most, if not all, designers are a little bit guilty of looking down on other people’s work. Comments such as “Pah! They used Comic Sans” or “Ergh! Don’t they know reflections are so out of date now?”
These are comments I’m 100% guilty of saying, but I think the problem is the outlet. If it’s a quick chatter between friends then there’s not much lost except making yourself look like a bit of an arse, but start broadcasting these harsh judgements to the world and you’ll rapidly give the impression of a big ego, huge mouth and tiny brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Dribbble and Forrst for feedback on a client project</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 20:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/dribbble-and-forrst-for-client-project-feedback/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I created a quickie logo for Andy Warburton’s mobile stock photography service Stockyoo. Andy was really keen on the idea of using Forrst and Dribbble for posting the progress of the project to get the opinions of potential users of a stock photography service and do some early promo for Stockyoo itself.
Dribbble and Forrst Dribbble and Forrst are part of a new wave of sites aimed at (mostly web) designers and developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
