<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Laura Kalbag</title>
    <link>https://laurakalbag.com/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Laura Kalbag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 13:09:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://laurakalbag.com/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live-designing WordPress Admin Icons</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/live-designing-wordpress-admin-icons/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I wrotea post about how I was going to do a talk at WordPress London where I would try to design a WordPress admin icon live. Well, I did it, and it didn’t go too badly. In fact, I was very lucky as the first suggestion for what I should design was a calendar icon. That’s mostly squares, so not too tricky!
  The final calendar icons (as designed quickly in 30 minutes or so)   The WordPress London guys kindly filmed my talk and I’ve included it below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at the WordPress London January meetup</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/speaking-at-the-wordpress-london-january-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I’m speaking at the WordPress London January meetup on the 17th of January 2013.
I’ve been using WordPress for years, for my own site and for client sites, and I really love it. I had absolutely no idea what to talk about though. I tend to create custom themes for clients, but these are very different from themes designed for use by many different sites, and so I wasn’t sure whether my experience would be relevant to many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Of Web Design 2011 –; The Summary –; Day One</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/fowd-2011-summary-day-one/</guid>
      <description>A few people have recommended that I post all the tweets summarising the great talks at Future Of Web Design in a blog post. So here it is!
Day One Aarron Walter –; Transforming Ideas into Interfaces I arrived late for Aarron’s talk so it took me a while to engage properly.
Tweet
Tweet Mike Kus –; Designing for Humans Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet
Tweet Ian Stewart –; Power Your Design With WordPress Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet Tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the iPad is saving my sanity</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 18:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/how-the-ipad-is-saving-my-sanity/</guid>
      <description>Fan girl I’ve had an iPad since the day it was released in the UK. I bought it because I’m a fan girl. I admit it. I could pretend that I wanted it to take to conferences or use for testing or when I didn’t need a laptop when I went to visit clients. In truth, I only go to one or two conferences per year, I’ve not yet made a site that needed an iPad-specific site and when I go to visit clients I always need my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 3.0 Part 3—Theme Development and the Design</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-theme-development-and-the-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 21:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-theme-development-and-the-design/</guid>
      <description>This post has three parts. This is part three. Visit the other parts below:
 Part 1: WordPress 3.0—Pre 3.0 and Beyond Part 2: WordPress 3.0—Really WordPress 3.0  Easier for theme developers to make it easy for users The following WordPress 3.0 features really make it easier for the big-time theme developers who create highly customisable themes.
Menus This is brilliant. Before the menus feature, we had to bodge any extra links we wanted on to the end of the wp_list_pages (that just lists pages!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 3.0 Part 2—Really WordPress 3.0</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-really-wordpress-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 21:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-really-wordpress-3/</guid>
      <description>This post has three parts. This is part two. Visit the other parts below:
 Part 1: WordPress 3.0—Pre 3.0 and Beyond Part 3: WordPress 3.0—Theme Development and the Design  Really WordPress 3.0 Custom Post Types Custom Post Types are my new best friends. I have used new post types on every client project since the beta of WordPress 3.0. That’s how valuable I think they are.
For any content that you need to act like a post, but not actually be a post, custom post types are there for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 3.0 Part 1—Pre 3.0 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-pre-3-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 21:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laurakalbag.com/wordpress-3-0-pre-3-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>This post has three parts. This is part one. Visit the other parts below:
 Part 2: WordPress 3.0—Really WordPress 3.0 Part 3: WordPress 3.0—Theme Development and the Design  I’m a big fat WordPress fan. I love the people behind it, I love the ethicsand I love how it makes it easy for me to make cool sites that my clients can update themselves.
Not really being much of a PHP developer, I can still get by and can make fairly capable themes from-scratch for my clients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
